Welcome to office hours with prime. This is prime time your chance to ask questions about
Pretty much anything you want about Nia, so please feel free to drop in those questions two channels up from one
You currently clicked on which is the office hours text chat. I don't see any questions there so until there are questions there
We're just going to sit in awkward silence
If you want a question answered drop it in there otherwise awkward silence will get more and more awkward the longer you let it fester
If I asks, what did I miss the answer is nothing we've had absolutely nothing so far so again awkward silence
but with
Slightly more awkwardness ah we have a question from shadow coffee shadow coffee says where do you see Nia's being in three to five years?
Um it's a little bit difficult right now to you to the announcers channel, so I don't really know I'd like to see that turned around
And once that's turned around I'm sure we'll have plans and ideas until it's turned around
I don't really know okay, so the next question is from NFT hater
NFT hater says is it possible to browse the web within near so I'd like to access documentation in game
My best advice there would to be use the desktop
The desktop tab of your dash that gives you for access to your regular computer
You can access your browser and all sorts of stuff from there
That's the best option right now in the future would likely have inbuilt documentation tools of in the game
That means that you don't really need a browser to do so
and then beyond that we'll have
a better more accurate screen sharing that's a feature on our roadmap to allow you to look at like you know individual applications or
Services etc so you don't have to do the whole desktop tab, but the desktop tab is great
I don't understand why more people don't use it for like basically everything. It's like having a computer inside
Yes, your host is prime. Can you make a vid on you trying cheeses and rating them someday?
Um I need to do some research and maybe speak to some other youtubers about it because like I never really understood
Why youtube has made second channels, but like I now have a second channel where I put like junk
But like I'd love if my channel could be like other stuff
But if I start putting non-neo's video tutorials there
Then I start splitting the universe and splitting the the audience and so I don't really know how that works
I would love if like playlists were more sort of
Fine-grained at YouTube maybe you could subscribe to just a playlist or a topic that a user or creator puts out and that way
You wouldn't get any surprises almost like each channel had like a sub channel
That'd be great because right now my choices appear to be like rename my main channel to be probably prime
Neos make probably prime just general leave the second channel is as probably I'm gaming and then
I mean it has tags
It's just it's like categorization such that you know
I don't have to make like five different channels like you get to the point where it's crazy like you look some really big creators
They've got like six or seven channels just because they want to make different topics and maintain the ability to review them all a little
bit easier
It's it's yeah
Yeah, I just do it like it's gonna start alienating people and it's it's weird. You know, but whatever next question
Shadow coffee says it's Neos based in unity on real or another engine its own. So there's a little bit like
Confusion there that needs to be resolved every time it comes up, which is we currently do use unity
But we only use unity is basically like rendering. That's it
all of the sort of logic and
Operational stuff networking etc is ran via an engine called fruits engine
Which is sort of attached to unity like some sort of weird parasite really
We just feed it like there is a cube over here and unity goes
Okay, and then your computer renders a cube over there. Like that's all that unity is doing
It doesn't do any of the gameplay logic. It's really like it's bare-bones
We want to pull that out and make our own engine to run stuff because that gets us a lot more sort of affordances there
But until that's done, yes, you see another question here from chroma
She says with your absolute expect certain expert certainty that will hold you specifically accountable for where you see Neos
100 years big update marketplace question mark
Um, I don't particularly see any Neos existing in a hundred years and people get like surprised about this
But you have to think about like how long a hundred years is
Is we'll probably be playing something like Neos
I doubt it will be Neos itself as you see it now or as you see it in five years or whatever
There may be you know an equivalent but it certainly
You know won't be the same software package the same engine the same programming language the same input environment
You know
There are people right now that still use the temp five ones and it's just like you expect to be using a vive one
You know hundred years. Nope. What will be our interaction look like then? Like, how will it run?
You talk about paradigms all the time and it's sort of just looking at it like, you know, Nokia 3310
All right, they weren't that long ago. So you just got to think about it. You also have to think about like in a hundred years
like
Stereotypically everyone here will be like not dead but like a little bit dead, right?
Most of us will probably be either dead or not that interested in computer games
Actually, this generation is probably one of the first generations that will be like I still understand our computer works
And I'm 80 because like all of like, you know grandparents stuff like that. They're just like, oh, it's too complicated understand it
I am never going to be that person like as I grow older
I'm gonna be like, okay, even if it takes me like a like a year
I'm gonna like understand, you know the next generations of computers so that I don't turn into that like, you know
Oh, I don't know how to push a button on a computer. Like I'm not I'm not, you know
No one's gonna have to tell like grandpa prime how to turn on the television. It's it's not gonna happen
The point there being is like hey, what what are we gonna like? What are we gonna do?
I don't think it's gonna be strapping screens to our face and you know holding weirdly shaped controllers. It's gonna be something else
I don't know what though. I mean, maybe the FTE controller will have been released by then
They keep pushing back their schedule, but whatever so just following up
I think we answered shadows question about will be live in a hundred years. I don't think so something like us maybe
Similar parts of the community but like it's really a long time. Like I almost certainly be dead. So I don't really care
Will we be up up there we'll be able to upload our consciousness into nears. No, not nears
I wouldn't trust us with our consciousness. Um, it'd probably crash
Oh, yeah, you gotta be like reasonable and you got to be like realistic, right?
the the whole consciousness thing is is terrifying go play soma soma is a very good game that
Endeavors to teach you about the sort of horror that is consciousness transference
but I've seen a lot of people who play soma and they're just like yeah your spooky horror game like amnesia and I'm like
You're missing like the actual horror. Yes, of course
there are monsters etc, but look into like who the monsters are why they exist and then look into like who you are and you'll
You'll figure it out and you'll see the real horror is just like existing in that game. Like you can stand
Directly in the first tutorial room of soma and it's terrifying if you know exactly what's going on
You don't even need to take a step just stand there
Although screw the patterns in spartan summer and I'm not like spoiling any part of summer at all here
But at one point you are very very far down
underwater and
You have to go out in a very high-pressure suit and there are like
tunnels like caves and tunnels and stuff and there are like these
Spider crab water creatures that are like attached to the cave walls and they're like thousands of them and it's it's horrible
Like atmospheric storytelling in that like super super underwater area with those like spider crab things on the wall terrible
No spider crabs, please
Speck says considering how much the term metaverse has been somewhat poisoned
Are there any other terms you might personally favor for a virtual world instead? I'm fond of cyberspace myself
I'm fond of no terminology. What I what I don't like is
The words that are used in the media are sort of shortcuts for our headspace, you know, we say social media
You think Twitter Facebook YouTube tik-tok now, but those platforms are all different in their own respects, right?
They're just shortcuts. And so I really rather we used more words to figure out what the thing is because like people call
Everything a metaverse now. I've seen Microsoft Teams been referred to as a metaverse and as someone who works sort of
Horizontally near Microsoft Teams. It's not a metaverse. I hate teams. I just can't stand it. Um
So it's not a metaverse
I mean then some people say like oh metaverse is about interoperability and I think that's cool
So I was looking at a VR game company the other day and they make some good games
The problem is those games are linear in their purpose
So they make a darts game a bowling game and it's like, okay
Well, if I want to play darts, I have to switch to this app
If I don't play bowling I have to switch to this app
But they do have internet operability is in that use it uses the same account system
But like a metaverse would have none of those walls
But it's very difficult to do that with the many cut money companies that are doing it
So I don't like the term. I think it's stupid and I don't think it should be used and I think you should use better
Terminology for it moving on to the next question, which I believe is from my cat. Oh, this is
What kind of options do we have for importing animations into news?
And if not, well that they'll consume with VR chat formatted animations be supported right out of the box
No, so VR animations are stored in unity animation files. We don't support those. We're not unity
I know I said earlier we run on unity, but remember we're this weird sort of like
Parasitical thing that like attaches to unity. We have no idea how unity works at all
We cannot use unity animations
if you want to make an
Like a regular FBX GLTF animation in blender or whatever those will work
There is limited functionality of those you can get away with a lot
Like you'll see a lot of people use them as a few examples in my public folder
But we certainly do need to do more work there
the important thing I would like to stress though is I really want you to think about why you're asking them because some people are
Like I need animations to turn on and off my hat and I'm like we have an inventory system
Just spawn your hat and put it on you don't need an animation for that and then people say I need an animation such
That like when I do the finger gun gesture
I I put a cute face and I'm just like who invented that system and why is that the case?
You don't need an animation for that. You need logics for that
You know, I've seen people say like ah, I need an animation to make my rainbow shader work
I'm like a pano 1d over a
Material like you don't need an animation for that
So really like ask more questions about what you're trying to do and then maybe you don't even need animations
Like hey, I want to do this cool. You don't need animations for that. Hey, I want to do cool
You don't need animations for that. I've heard some people say like hey, I want animations so I can change the walk cycle
Did you know the walk cycle in years is entirely procedural you can control everything about it
If you know specifically which five boxes to check around and take a look at
You're looking for gates. They're inside
I don't know either the rik avatar or ike avatar those components always confuse me like which one's which
and you can do all sorts of things there like I
Played with it a little bit and I managed to get a walk cycle, which is basically just sort of giant leaps
You know like jumping from spot to spot
I also did one where my legs stretched awkwardly forwards like a sort of ballerina doing a prancy sort of leap
But for every step I did another one where my both legs were completely synchronized and just moved up and down like a pogo stick
You can do whatever you want there. No one's just taking the time to sort of
Write documentation my bad or play around with it in another level to sort of tell people about it
But go ahead take a look at gates. They are exceptionally cool, but people just go no one animations, and I'm like okay
Go play the gate system, and then they say no and then we go into the loop
So just ask more questions shadow coffee asks. What's future support can we look forward to in this?
They're asking particularly about hardware, so the interesting thing about hardware is
Fruits and the team would always want to implement hardware, but we have issues sort of communicating the
Priority and the sort of chance of us doing that
So we have a lot of products that are basically like you can implement us
Here's an SDK, and I don't want that like I want the actual device. I want to check it works and
Then they're like oh, that's cost us money to send it to you
So you can loan it to us like we got loaned the the fight the very facial tracker
It was on loan to us. We didn't own it fruits
Just got like it loaned to him he implemented the entire thing and then sent it back
And then he bought one when they actually came out like that
That's like how it worked and it was cool
But then that leads to the next problem, which is I have sent you this hardware, and you haven't implemented it
Why and it's like well just imagine like?
Fruits is mailroom just imagine. It's like a physical place rather than just I know somewhere in his house like fruits
It's mailroom, and it's full of like a hundred devices all stacked up in their boxes
And he wakes up one day, and he's like what do I want to do today?
Do I like grab a device off like the mailroom or do I want to work on something else?
And that's the way it works, so you need to basically be patient
Open a a gab issue for any device you'd like to be
Invented implemented and then get people to vote on it another thing we have there is a problem of adoption
So adoption of some devices is going to be quite low, so
We see adoption of the the haptic vests
They're cool
But I don't know about the adoption of them like I don't even have a percentage of them when it comes to smell and taste support
I see adoption of those being very low right now because of some of the limitations about them
The current really cool smell thing which Peter thinker works on with the company that they work for is great
But it requires a foresight what I mean by that is if you need I don't know a grassy meadow smell
You need to put that scent cartridge into the device which means you can't have spontaneity
so say the next MMC I do smell support and I have a
Cheese factory that you go through unless I pre-worn by I don't know sending a piece of paper to them and say hey
All of the cartridge slots need to be full of cheese one through five
Please make sure you do this before you go in like I've lost the spontaneity. I've lost the surprise
People talk a lot about molecular printing which is like a step beyond 3d printing which is where you print molecules like you're you know
You're printing the individual atoms
Maybe that's a way to go if you'd like to see what that might look like in the future go watch big hero 6 again
the girl with the
Handbag, I guess you could call it. That's a molecular printer, and she can create like all sorts of stuff
She uses throughout that film. It's super cool
That's where you would need to go for like spontaneity to exist in those
The same with taste because it's just like a chemical signal if full-dive VR occurs
You know hooking your brain up, please don't do that by the way look at soma
Then they won't need that of course because they're not recreating the taste using an actual fluid or the smell using natural fluid
They're just like sending false signals to the brain
Hey, you're eating strawberries even though no strawberries actually exist moving on to another question
You know how long will Neos last until it falls out of interesting?
I don't know like I said a hundred years. I can guarantee we'll be playing something different
It might still be made by freaks. Yes, although freaks. Yes will probably be dead in a hundred years
Let's just be honest like you know
No one's living that long right now, and maybe we are again see some of those for how terrifying that might be um
So it's probably gonna be something different who knows I don't know moving on was NFT
Hey, there's a question which says how easy is it to import source engine content?
I'm not sure I haven't seen anyone that does that um usually what happened those you would take
The if it's a map you take it out of hammer editor and export it as like a common model format
I know you can do that from source engine so export it to obj
FBX or whatever and then you can import it easily if you mean an animation or an avatar or anything like that probably a lot
More more difficulty what happens with main like many triple-a 3d engines is they do everything their way because they're an engine
For example the use of blend shapes in most triple-a systems isn't that common they use bones more
It's all about bones bones everywhere so many bones
So that's why when you see facial animations increase there, there's loads of bones associated with it
So that's not compatible with us right now
I mean you could technically hook them all up, but like there's a lot of bones there
I have some people that have taken bony faces and
And baked the bone positions into blend shapes, which is a really cool way of doing it
They add a bunch of bones to the face which allows
Easy dragging around of those vertices and then they bake those to blend shapes and that way they work with our systems easier
Um, but don't have those big bony faces
It's kind of interesting like the way the assets are prepared like people like oh
You're kind of good at 3d modeling prime and it's like I know how to make an anime avatar that is too lit
Look good inside Neos. I don't know how to make a triple-a apps asset that could go to a natural game
I have no idea moving forwards to a few more questions. So
Juby asks, I'd assume that Neos would one day be launched into the public spotlight when that time comes
What do you think will the integral element of keeping people interested in Neos?
I'd like to say freedom of expression and freedom of creativity a lot of people are like, yeah
It's just another social VR platform, but like yeah sure it is but like there's the freedom of expression and freedom of creativity there
But I think we do a lot better than some other social platforms
For example, they're not hiding on these platforms. They're great
They just have different sort of targets if you look at something like rec room, for example, everything's very blocky
It's it's great because you know, you can put stuff together there, but you can't do like crazy visual effects there
Yeah, you can't do crazy avatars there. Yeah, you can do that here
Um, you know stuff like that. We're a different platform for that. So like freedom of expression people will say like
The community are only there because like the game's cool, right?
If they form because the game is there and they'll hang on because the game with that but like they need that freedom
they need that sort of platform to exist on and
I think Neos is a good platform for that to exist on
I think all the other social VR platforms are good for that to exist on hopping forwards
A shadow coffee says what is summer summer is a game. It's a very good game
Just search it so ma exactly how you spelt it. Very very good game. Leave were caught up on questions
So I'm just gonna sit here in awkward silence
Okay, we have another question from shadow coffee that says I saw a feature that meta is working on
It basically puts down objects in places to ask the system to to do
Example like you ask put the tree in this spot or a bench in this spot voice activated world building
Is that something that we possible so you're talking there about sort of procedural generation?
Um, there is a lot of tools exist there. I saw business lawyers typing earlier. He is a
Load of tools which are great for creation like that. Then you added sort of voice activation
That is something probably we'll look at in the future, but like not not to that level
Like it's just like that's a very sort of complex compound question like to break it apart is like okay finding assets
So you want to find a bench cool that search, right?
So you'll be able to search through find a bench you want to put down cool placing it here
That's about sort of grabbing it and moving it there
All right
Those are the operations you're talking about and then you could you could add voice activation at any point during those
For example, you could say search for a bench cool and then search results appear for a bench, but like place it here
I think you want to do that with the actual tools. I don't know. Oh, yeah, it's very possible
Yeah, you can you can build that as well. I just I don't think it's useful like for search here
Sure, maybe voice activated searches but like put a bench here where they told me to like say the coordinates place a bench exactly
327 point two five five X by five hundred Y by
200 Z and you're like cool. I'd rather just like put that visually or I need to put it
I mean, maybe you can point like, you know put down a pin say here
But at that point you've already done like half the job
So just grab the bench and put it there gun Griffin asks
Can you inject a sound that we use as audio stream? I'd like to add an audio marker to synchronize a piece of media
Yes, but that wouldn't be inside. Yes. I have a very complicated audio setup
Lots of it is muted and disabled but there is actually a square button on my go XLR mini here
Which I've muted because it would send a loud beep noise of accidentally pushed it and that was hurting some people's ears
But you know like that's inbuilt into the hardware
I'm using to power my microphone and power my audio systems. It's nothing to do it
Yes, I don't think it should be in some cases in some cases
Maybe it could but like just virtual audio cable voice me a banana whatever you want to do it
Just like figure it out a quick note on this one, which will probably head over to the be considerate page
Do not under any circumstances ever play your Spotify playlist over your microphone channel. I
will
Eviscerate your existence from my world
I have had Spotify since 2013. I don't need to hear
Any of your music ever I want to hear my own music if you use an audio stream
Which is a feature that we have that allows you to do that without it being on your microphone
Then I have the choice to mute that audio stream and still hear your lovely voice, which is the actual thing
I want to hear I want to converse with you. I don't want to hear your trashy music
Thank you way too many people do that over in VR chat, and I just don't understand it
I went to a world in VR chat recently where there were three people next to each other Oh
Blasting over their microphone channel different genres of music and dancing to it
I presume they'd all muted each other
But I hadn't muted any of them because I'm trying to converse with them
And so it was just a cacophony of just shit, and I don't want to hear that
So don't do it over your microphone channel. Thank you moving on to the next question
Is it normal that a collider does it shrink or grow?
exactly the same size of an item I mess with when I shrink an object with colliders the collider kind of becomes
Bigger compared to how much I shrunk the object and when I make it bigger the collider uses volume
That would depend on how you've got it set up
Most colliders are procedural and if they're not they're mesh colliders at which point
They're directly tied to the vertices of the mesh, so they shouldn't really shrink or grow there
You'll also see a weird thing that happens with
Non uniform scaling never use none of uniform scaling if you do there are things that you need to do to make it work
Or you can just choose to not use it, and you'll never have to remember those things to do
I'd have to actually like see your object there to understand more
That doesn't sound normal, but I don't know what it's set up
It's causing that moving onwards nft hater says is snap to grid a thing in years there are very
Varieties of snap to grid so there are snapping systems for example
There is the builder tool bag happy which is a great tool for building stuff you can snap all sorts of things to a grid
There there is the green laser 3000 which is a little bit of an older tool made by coffee is to work on this team
That completely destroyed a world. I was working on when they were working on it
And they apologized profusely and put my world back to you. Thank you so much for that that does snapping to grid there is logic
Logics ray uvs ray uvs logics tip got that the right way around which does snapping to a grid for logics nodes
There is red print which does again snapping to a grid for logics nodes
There is native snapping which is sort of a weird feature that I would love to improve
But it exists people are like what are like if you inspect something and you get that pink
Cube that goes around it and it's got those yellow balls in the corner and everyone's like what are those yellow balls for I?
Have a video on exactly what those yellow balls are for because they actually do something
It's just a bit weird so that's snapping as well
Then there's snappers, which are things like putting on hats or bracelets, or you know gadgets on yourself asks, whatever
That's also snapping technically snapping to a grid because it snaps to an exact position
Depends what you mean and what you want next shadow coffee is asking will Neos have AI NPC bots to hang out and talk to
Yeah, uh you can build those we might have features in the future particularly animation features would be helpful there
But you can build them they already exist there is a bot just this comes to mind
There is basically like an NPC bot experience inside
the
Debug warrior that's a MSC entry that has a sort of tutorialized bot system. It's like here's how you play the game, right?
That's an NPC or bot
There are a couple a couple of social worlds which have bartenders in them
They're not really that smart when it comes to NPCs or bots, but you know they hang out. They talk to you
There is eco which is a map by
another MSC entry for who's by
That has a village of little foxes which mine
My ore and cut down trees and bring it back to the village. That's really cool
There's another MSC entry for the next year's MSC
So the eco one was
2020 or 21 remember for the most recent
and
This sorry the MSCs will blur together especially because the the distance between 21 and 22 is so short
There's another one which is the traffic system. I think that was 21
Which again had pathfinding AI and bots so that was cool
I get a lot of questions like this, so I'll kind of elaborate a little bit some people like can you do this?
The answer is they yeah, go build it
Yeah, go build it. Yeah, go build it like if you if you don't know if you can do something
Just go try and build it or ask can I build this not like will this happen can I build it sure brightness asks?
Why is there a launch desktop mode option in the steam Neos launch options if it breaks the game?
I straight-up use launch Neos and it works better launch desktop version doesn't break my game break sure game
That sounds like a bug you should submit a bug report on our github the reason why those desktop options exist there are because
Once you have a headset you need the options to not use it so yes
Well by default when you don't use any of those launch options when you launch it. It'll be like cool
I have detected that you have a headset plugged in I know you're not currently wearing it. I don't care
I'm gonna launch into VR mode, and it's like sometimes you don't want that sometimes you want to hop on desktop mode
So that launch desktop mode there is is mostly for VR users that have VR headsets and want to launch in desktop mode because they don't
Want to play VR at that particular time? That's why all those launch options are there
The one that forces you into steam VR mode that's there for people who run
oculus
Headsets, but with full body tracking using steam right they need steam to run
But Neos will by default say yo you've got an oculus headset
I'll run an oculus VR mode not steam VR mode you like buying to run in steam VR mode because I do full body tracking with
Steam stuff so I need you to technically run both and so that's what that's for
Torazo says once the ability to bookmark worlds you can actually do that. It's just a little bit weird right now
It's really weird right now in the way that you do it, so if you want to bookmark a world
Get the world up for it and save it to a folder tada bookmarks. It's a really weird way to do it
It's not like any sort of bookmark that I would see but if you just save the world up to a folder
If you've been marked it now you haven't saved a copy of that world when you save the world off
So don't worry about your file space
You've just saved a literal orb
Which has the link to the world in it if you do save copy save as or something like that
Then you've you've you know that will affect your your file storage
But if you just save a copy of the world orb and the world orb itself you've got a favorite list
It is more involved fuzzy. Yes. I did say it's not ideal, but you can do it
Technically so brightness adds to the question about the launch desktop mode saying it would basically cut the connection between me and some users
They'll get frozen on my end it also completely prevent me from seeing things that people would spawn that is a bug
That's nothing to do with that desktop mode option. That is a bug
That's another thing that continues to happen with users and trust me. I don't blame you for it
It's just something that happens you see something weird, and then you use like your detective powers
You're Sherlock Holmes ness, and you're like it must have been caused by this
So the fact that I have an empty bag of Haribo gummy bears on my desk is the reason why Neos didn't start
Usually not the case so when you come across something that doesn't make sense
Please make a bug report and we'll be able to take a look at it
Additionally when people are making bug reports, please make sure you provide the entire log file. Do not provide screenshots of the log file
I can't read screenshots
I can't copy and paste screenshots into our code base or into Google or into wherever I need to don't provide
Segments of the log file as well some people like this error is surely the problem
And I look and like that's the error that happens every five seconds inside Neos because of some bug we haven't fixed
And then like two lines below that is the stuff that we need you haven't copied and pasted that one in your message
You've just copy and pasted one bug. I can't see it
So just the whole tire log file in your bug report, and if you don't make a bug report. We can't fix it
We don't know about it
Even if you come up to us in game
And you tell us about a problem that you're having you might think that's reported you don't need to make a bug report
That's incorrect unfortunately because we're human we're gonna forget about that bug report because we're in game
We're busy what you need to do is go to the github make an official report
Then come and speak to us about it because then we'll be able to like tie the two conversations together otherwise
I'm literally just gonna forget. I will try my best to remember. I'm not being rude or anything. I'm just gonna forget
It's just human nature shadow coffee says will Neos crypto coin be worth more than Bitcoin at some point
Oh, no, probably not see announcements
Double stick says do you think Neos is growth and development will progress?
It's the main will rate with a closed source development model yes if we can fix hashtag announcements
Open source development is an option, but it's not a mandate
And I can't stand people that like oh it must be open source because XYZ reason doesn't need to be like is
League of Legends open source node and how much money they made just sort of painting the same champions you play every day different colors
Like oh, we're gonna do today prime module you do today. What if we painted them pink? Oh, yeah paint them pink
Pink paint the pink charge another five bucks for a pink version of this character cool, and they make thousands and hundreds of you know
They make millions of dollars that close source
So just it is the time here GB if you have a question brightness of your question
Please continue to type otherwise no more questions
So double six is there a plan to a born board additional developers to the nearest team in the foreseeable future
No, when we need them will get them however we can that's also weird because like that gets in the sort of ray of like
Are they paid employees or are they not or are they volunteers if they're volunteers? What are they doing?
Are they just know coming on board just to be like yo?
I want to come on board and work on this one
This one feature and then do nothing or are they coming on board to do exactly what we need to do or are we paying?
them for paying them are they good and
It's especially right now. Okay, so GBs question
We've seen the application applications for education purposes and if you see bill plans on the future to expand to other fields
Health care we have training on like it's already happening
again, you have to sort of say go do it and really like, you know, drum that into people there is nothing stopping you do be or
Double sticks or shadow coffee or chroma up there or brightness from tomorrow?
Going to a research institution and saying you should use Neos for
Cancer research you should use Neos for
Or psychological research. I was reading a paper the other day about
Exploring and researching how people with autism were processing various sort of scenes and
Like environments they weren't using Neos, but they could easily use Neos. And so what they did was they had a kind of train station
model or mock or room and
They would change subtle things about the room. For example, they had a tiled floor that was black white tiled
almost like a chessboard and then they would do eye tracking using the eye tracking features of the headset and
See how you know people with autism without autism would process that environment
because you get people that are hyper observant and people that are not hyper observant and you may notice that hey the
Some users would basically scan the chessboard like it was a chessboard
even though it's just a tiled floor and so then they removed the floor and
They were like, okay, what does the eye tracking do now that you know, the floor has been removed or has been changed
You know
They could put groups of people within the environment and then sort of ask or ask the user to kind of navigate through that environment
It's a great paper. I don't remember what the conclusion was or anything
I just remember existed but the point is you could do that easily with a couple of like
Toggle boxes and check boxes in Neos easily like incredibly easily
Some of that stuff's already happening from the community. We already have research in there
There's already a couple of scientific papers. Unfortunately don't mention Neos by name, but they used Neos and I'm aware of them
Neos has also been in the newspaper again not mentioned by name. I was mentioned by name though. So it's already happening
I think though to expand your question back into sort of realms of what the team can do
The team could have someone that does that stuff with that community of researchers
Oh, wait, they already do it's me
Hello, if we were a more traditional company with the growth and the need to do it and the budget to do it
I would predict that maybe in the future we would hire someone full-time to be like a community liaison for that particular market
At which point they would be helping
The community and users and companies of in the Neos community do more research using Neos that actual job role exists at unity
For example, I was looking the other day. They have a job role open it for right now
It would be a product manager who just does that they help our educational and nonprofit products projects using unity
So if we were big enough to need that we would get it until we are just go do it go do it
There's nothing stopping you
I was calculating the angular velocity of an eyeball a couple of months ago fuzzy says is there an end in sight for halted updates?
See the announcer's channel with that. I believe we're out of questions
We go ahead and end things off here and speak to you later. If any further questions, please drop from the discord
DM me block my DMS check the github check the wiki or just speak in the discord and I will speak to you later. Bye. Bye