All right. Recordings active. We'll go ahead and just type in office hours. We're live.
And then we'll get going. Okay. So, as we had no, like, form up there,
we'll go straight into questions with Specs's question. Specs asks, the VRIK component is
very useful to know for avatar setup, but it doesn't seem well covered for how important
it is. It helped me debug a friend's bone assignments this weekend. Sorry to discover
the shorter role settings have been useful in adjusting shorter bone behavior for us.
I'm sure it will be a lot of work, but a detailed overview of this component may be extremely
useful to experienced users. Is there any chance we get a prime video on the topic?
Maybe. The problem with the VRIK and the VRIK avatar components is that they have so many
properties that I just don't know what they do. I know what, like, five of them do, but the rest
of them I'm just not sure. There's a lot of numbers there, a lot of, like, sliders, a lot
of random fields that don't seem to make sense. But they have lots of power in them. I did drop
some content into the tutorials channel. I'm calling them pointers, because they're just,
like, stuff I make in one minute. Not produced at all. But I was showing someone how to do
custom walk animations with that. And a few other things there. And it was just, like,
I don't know how half this component works, but if you mess with these numbers, you're going to
get a different result. So, in the future, sure. Not quite sure when. I actually just need to go
ahead and figure out a description for each of those properties, even if it means I, like,
I don't know, I take fruits out for some fruit and I'm just like, all right, fruits. We've got
400 fields to go, fruits. Let's do it. What does blah, blah, blah, blah do? However, there is one
field which is really useful, which is arm length multiplier. I think it's in IK avatar, I'm not
quite sure. It's in one of the two. Arm length multiplier will let you make your arms longer or
shorter. I kept doing that for new users last week. Someone said, oh, how am I going to remember
this, you know, if I need to change my arms later? And I said, well, you could remember it by the
name I remember it internally, which is arm length my little pony and then you'll never forget it.
So, remember, if your arms need to be shorter or longer, adjust your arm length, my little pony.
But that's just me. Moving forwards. Yeah, actually, we didn't do any of that. Good call,
Mr. Easton. So, for anyone who's new here or isn't familiar with office hours or hasn't seen them
before, I sit here and answer questions and I inevitably start ranting about various objects
or stories or experiences in life. But I'm meant to be answering nice questions. If you have any
questions, please drop them in the office hours text chat that is it used to be two above the one
that you're currently looking at for community meetings, but now it's one, two, three, four,
five. So, it's five above the one that you're currently in because we added some extra voice
chat channels just to spread out the load from the oncoming people. So, if you have questions
about Neos, drop them into the office hours text chat. I'll get to them as soon as I can.
Keep them coming and we'll keep answering them. Let's go ahead and move on to the next question
here. So, Alex says made of interesting Neos lately. Yeah, you can actually find it I think
it's in like the full dive Neos discussions and questions and help kind of just blur into my brain
sometimes and I need to like remember which one I actually like posted it in. I'll drop it down to,
here we go, let me see if I can just copy these holistically down. Where are we? Office hours,
office hours, office hours, paste. Oh yes, a blank thing pasting. I'll just upload them again from
my actual computer. We were looking at doing more, I'm doing like a lot of like science and
sciency stuff with a user name shfr and we were doing science involving eye exams and so we had
to come up with an anchor that forcibly put your head in a head restraint which is not something
like anyone would probably do but it's something that we were doing for a particular goal. You can
see that sphere there is me positioning a avatar pose filter so I can get the head in the right
spot so it looks convincing. It is fun, you never quite know what you're gonna do. Everyone else is
like oh let's make a game, let's make a world and those are fantastic, please keep making them.
When it comes to science we're just like what? You need what? You sure? Okay.
Ozzy asks what's your funniest unique encounter with users so far? So I always get like weirded
out by the people who don't realize that like yes I am the YouTube person. It happens a lot. They're
like you're the guy I watched YouTube videos on. I'm like yep that's me and they're like thanks for
the videos. I'm like yep thank you for watching them. It's very simple. If you watch them,
fantastic. If they help you, fantastic. If they don't help you, also fantastic. I don't mind.
So it's always good to see those people. The funny or unique encounters usually occur when
I'll suddenly go into like parent or teacher mode and I'll be like hey we don't do that here. So
I was in a world this is actually just before the VRChat like big boom over here due to all
that stuff and a kid came in. They sounded quite young and they walked up to an uninhabited avatar
and started bullying it. You know they're insulting it, swearing at it, etc. And I walked
over there I'm like hey we don't do that here. We're nice here. And you know the kid persisted
for a little bit and eventually they stopped because I just wouldn't let them do it. I was
like hey we don't do that here. I wouldn't argue with them. I was just like hey we just don't do
that here. Eventually they got the picture and they apologized to the uninhabited avatar
that no one was wearing. They're like sorry I was mean or whatever and that was that was that was
fun. Alrighty scrolling down. Alright Shy River says can public avatars be fully exported from
Neos? No you cannot export any type of avatar from Neos currently and that's because the moment you
bring a skinned mesh which is what an avatar is into Neos it uh it gets uh garbled is the
wrong word it gets translated into Neos format which is not currently exportable. That might
change in the future but right now go ahead turn off this ac we'll have less brr noises.
Let's move on to the next question here from unnamed cyborg cat. How exactly does the nitty
gritty of avatar creation work? Like yeah there's a thing you put on the head and hands and stuff
but what about where your eyes are or how to calibrate how big you are in comparison to
the avatar itself? How does it all work? That depends exactly on what you want. You like you
have like a couple of questions there which are sort of hidden behind that larger question like
how does the avatar system work? It's very very very very complicated but for where the eyes are
that is usually turned by we try and figure out if we can find the eyes if we see a bone called
right eye left eye hey that's an eye bone. How big you are in comparison to the avatar itself
is controlled by a height compensation field on the avatar that'll be under vrik or vrik avatar.
Please for the love of god and everything that has ever been ever said to anyone in the planet
both in vr chat and on neos in the settings there is a height setting you set it to your real world
height or i will personally come and send you angry cat gifs the reason is because uh we get
a lot of people changing the height setting so that they can change how big they are in comparison
the avatar completely wrong way of doing it there's height compensation which will map how
tall the avatar is compared to your real world height and then there's also um the default user
scale component which allows you to be small should you want to be small so not actually to
be big although i don't know anyone that does that but uh default user scale is how you become sort
of smaller than than you want to be uh do not set your height to anything other than your real world
height otherwise i will send you angry cat gifs you quite clearly like it says put in your height
and everyone's like if i put in a smaller height my avatar looks better and i'm like well just to
use the appropriate tools for the job please please erin doesn't know their real height you
you get a ruler and you figure it out moving forwards now he asks uh will there be unity
package support eventually that is a difficult answer because what i want you to remember is
that we aren't unity we are right now but we're going aiming to not be unity now a unity package
is essentially just like a zip archive with a bunch of like crap on top of it and so me
personally even before i knew what neos was i got really annoyed at unity packages it seems like a
really inefficient way to submit avatars across like i don't understand like it just just the
problem that the largest problem with unity packages being hey hey it's a format that we
don't really own and then be the materials we can't map one to one the material so it doesn't
really work the best thing that we can do currently i know there's some mods out there that
do it but like you know the best thing that we as neos could do is scan through that unity package
find the assets and dump them into a world for you which is really what the the mod does it's
just not that simple right we're not unity and so that needs to be respected by our users we of
course can make the avatar setup process more easier more better more intuitive and stuff like
that but i don't think we're going to get to the point where it is like a vrchat import it actually
probably diverge further and further away from what our vrchat import is uh whilst also still
being easier and that might lead to oddities that haven't been foreseen but uh the best way to look
at that is hey if you had started making avatars uh with neos and not vrchat you'd probably be
saying the other way around you'd be like whoa you know vrchat doesn't just take my fbx
file and make it into an avatar so i guess in summary an easier process yes specifically unity
packages possibly but also possibly not you really i guess need to ask um like more questions there
like why don't you have your files knocked in here that's another interesting and unique experience
with with new users is uh when i'm helping them import their avatar and they manage to find the
fbx for their you know their avatars like being the flesh and the skin the the armature etc they
bring it in and i'm like great now import your textures and they're like i don't know where those
are and i just give them instructions and uh it always goes fun i've had someone manage to
import the fbx and then two hours later they're still trying to find their textures it's it's
i don't know i don't understand sometimes why um like finding files on your computer is difficult
i see people within like my downloads folder is full of like thousands of items just clean it up
if you're watching a film clean it up if you're watching some tv clean up you'll have a lot better
time let's go ahead and move down into more and more questions all right here we are uh slide
swap region what does the slide slot what does this slide swap region component do under uix
utility is there any there there isn't any documentation on the wiki i don't know um i do
have the code base open so i can just have a quick look based on what i'm reading here it isn't usable
by uh yes find all references let's see if there's a way that does it okay yeah um so the uh login
dialog uses it and the uh file browser uses it uh for similar functionality you probably want what's
it called as a component um that i'm thinking of access multi-viewport panel would be exactly the
same as slide swap region it's in uix uh utility access multi-viewport panel will do identical
things to slide swap region based on my current reading of it fenre who um asks what's your
current thoughts on the rise of the player base uh in the game compared before i don't really have
any thoughts about it it's great to see you all um i love that all of you are trying neos but um
you know it's for us a lot it's just sort of like hey welcome try us out we're a lot busier i guess
but like i don't know it's it's a strange question if you can elaborate on that question or ask in
the area that you're asking for that'd be great kind of struggle with generic questions sometimes
toasty my roasty amazing username here uh they ask are there any new worlds places recommend new
players uh should see visit to experience new unique features i want everyone to see uh like
all of the sort of the spectrum right so i want you to see a game world to try um abandonware
ncr the heist uh cabin of the seasons even fropey's i can't remember fropey's entry name
something dark something i don't know it's really really good though i've just forgot its name
uh those are games try some social worlds yep we do have uh rim of the rain we also do have midnight
rooftop but we do have ones that vrchat doesn't have um 72 groove lake um hole in the wall one
of my favorites um uh various other ones there that i'm i'm not gonna be able to remember by
name if i didn't mention your um your world don't be sad it's just like there are thousands of
worlds i need to get to them so make sure take a look at those social worlds make sure you also
take a look at sort of experiential worlds as well um go touch grass is kind of like a game
but more like an experience right uh if it was on steam it would probably be tagged walking simulator
uh just just like see what there is to offer i see so many people treat this game as like
gary's mod you know they'll just load into like in some cases literally a gary's mod map
um and then they'll just spawn guns all day like that isn't like that isn't in my view what neos
is for like all the gadgets are great but like um i don't know it's like a year or two ago i
just stopped saving cool stuff right i i don't need the latest guns someone shows me in their
world i don't need the latest like weird thing that i've i've seen i know where like loads of
them are in public folders but like i don't feel the need to without a gun start shooting people
like it is gary's mod um so do make sure that you're seeing all of the stuff that we've got
to offer neos universe is another good suggestion as is um gas station that may mentions neos
festival is amazing it's just started i know that content is being raised for neos festival as it
continues to come out so do keep an eye on that one the the weird thing with neos festival is like
it is identical in in some aspects to the previous neos festers but it feels great because they've
managed to make like an art browsing like or a booth browsing sort of system that that feels fun
you ride on this skyship and uh you know it takes you between the booths it's really like a another
way of also hiding that loading bar so uh that's cool moving forwards to pyro shade who says uh
i had noticed while bringing an fbx drag from unity project window that neos importing mentioned
something about converting a scene i haven't tried this here but what happens if i dragged in scene
or objects from a scene hierarchy you can't do that uh we don't support any unity files like
doesn't work um when it's just converting the scene um it means it's looking at the fbx because
like although for avatars you don't usually see it uh for like a level that's an fbx you would
like it is a scene right that's what fbx is it's a whole scene what converting scene means is it's
like well what's in the scene so neos knows enough about avatar imports to understand that it should
ignore cameras and lights that you import especially if it's an avatar i don't need those
and then it converts that into something that makes sense to it that's that's all it means
it's not like we don't support scenes from unity um alex is one of the editorial delegates would
have to be more specific there delegates aren't something you should usually be playing with if
you have any particular questions about where you might be wanting to use them or how you might want
to be using them let me know um you don't really need them uh lou says news from vr share is the
way to dynamically change avatar parts absolutely there is um you said rgb cycling um i have a video
i'm going to link in the video description about a rainbow shader i call it shader just for search
terms it's a material that is um uh targeted using logics and you can basically do triple quadruple
like quintuple 10 times the stuff i show in this video just by iterating over the properties of a
material um and that's something which i really wish more newer players would understand as well
as like yes our material options are limited but all of our materials are dynamic and live
updating on as many of uh the as many of the places as as we can right you want to change
the color you can do it live you want to change the color 50 times a second to your favorite
color of sandwich done um if you're talking more about like changing parts as in like hats scarves
bracelets jackets than yet again like that that's totally fine um you can use snappers for that
context menus for that check boxes for that cloud very there's so much stuff there like again here's
a video where i uh i put on a hat and bracelet and i'll show you how i do that because like what
what what unity does and sort of by extension vr chat right is it is it when you hit play or
when you compile it like freezes everything that exists in place and doesn't let you change it like
sure if you've got code in your unity game that says like hey the hat changes that's great but
that's code that has to be sort of pre-thought out ahead of time whereas what we've done is we've
said like hey we don't know if you're going to wear a hat but what allow you to wear a hat like
you don't need to pre-think of it like anything you can think of you can probably do moving
forwards for questions aaron says my working progress photo is getting too big and suggestions
on how to start finishing my projects stop giving up stop giving up that would be my suggestion for
mr aaron i see them like they're like i'm tired and then they delete it and it's like go back to
it benry has elaborated on the question thank you they've said uh like did you ever think you would
suddenly get a blow up of people do you feel prepared uh to get so many people or not are
you just going to the flow of that really really plan uh there is a plan um and the plan is
spearheaded by both of our fantastic volunteer teams so we over provisioned and i knew why we
were doing that but we over provisioned our mentor team and in some regards our moderator team such
that we could handle the load so we got a bunch of mentors on in fact mentor applications have
like been open and closed a little bit but they've just been like wide open recently
and uh a lot of times the mentors were not not doing anything right but like we only needed like
two or three to help out at like certain busy periods during our regular play but we've had
this big rush and the mentors have just gone like yep we'll help out and then there's been 10 20 40
50 mentors flooding in to try and help you guys out and that's great to see and the reason why
that worked is because we had over provisioned that that volunteer team if you're interested
in becoming a mentor do you check out the wiki um wiki.neos.com forward slash mentors will get you
information on how to be a mentor there one quick note to know that if you're here um you do not
need to be a mentor to help people and if a mentor appears and you are helping someone you should
continue helping them don't yield to a mentor because you feel that they are more qualified
or that it's more correct that they help people uh mentor is just someone who wants to go through
that process and have the green badge to be recognized as someone who can help you can help
without being a mentor and as for mentors if you go into a world and someone is helping read the
room and uh maybe don't take over i've heard a lot of feedback about that recently and it bothers me
that we keep hearing that feedback so do keep that in mind um our servers were less prepared
than we realized which is a shame but uh that's the way it is sometimes um most of our stuff can
scale uh quite dynamically but sometimes there's like an upper or lower limit on that so you can
think of it like uh you know a dial on like a stereo or something right we can turn it up by
like two points but suddenly it was like hey we need to go to like we need to go to 11 we need to
go to 11 on these dials anyone that gets this reference you're amazing we need to go 11 on these
dials and it's like cool we have to remove like a couple of blocks there to allow it to go to 11
moving on ones two additional questions we have from olaf who says it's a way to have an avatar
return to t pose to more easily add things on like hats or clothing and over the character avatar
changes pose yes uh go inside inspect the root of the avatar it's vrik or vrik avatar i just can't
remember the difference between those two the reason is they're just really big components that
are on top of each other they're always on the same slot and i just i can't one of them will have
ik position wait drag that down to zero and your avatar will t pose just making sure i'm missing
any questions before i scroll down scrolling down mattie says that the mentor team was not prepared
for the exponential growth i think you were more prepared than if you'd like said yo we we only
have like we're only allowing five mentors this year like you were basically like anyone can apply
uh sir says hey don't forget the community members they did as well i did not mean to say that they
didn't in fact i made a particular call out to hell if you're not a mentor you don't need to be
one if you want to help like anyone can help uh i've seen crazy amounts of help going on uh i have
a really weird way of doing anyone that saw me drop into your mtc if there was a user there that
had more than five badges i'm like are you helping these guys out and they're like yep i'm like i'll
leave you to it if you got any questions let me know and i'll just instantly disconnect like i
don't want to crowd them like if they're helping someone out just disconnect uh moving onwards
foxbox says i had a session um hoping to help new users and they filled my session it was just me
and nine other new users asking for my help it wasn't too bad because they uh goofed off in the
background waited their turn yeah i also had that i was in a world of like six people and by the
time i got to the last person who wanted an avatar set up it was 5 a.m i did all their materials and
texturing um and they sort of timidly asked about dynamic bones and i just went tomorrow please
tomorrow that's another thing for the mentors out there and for the community members that are
helping out you guys can go to bed it's not a job there are no minimum hours there's no maximum
hours either work will uh fill the available space and the available time that exists in the day
so stop don't play nios for the entire 24 hours that you're awake um or exist on the planet if
you're not awake for the entire 24 hours you know i mean it's like go play i don't know have a kitty
online adventure instead of nios for a bit and chill out get some water in you and then chill
out moving forwards we have jelly gecko hello who says i'm in the process of creating avatars capable
of shape-shifting in this case shape-shifting implies going from a character to a monstrous form
i'm also interested in oh kitting i thought it said knitting and then i thought it said kiting
knit kitting out to the human character of different outfits in addition to uh his default
getup obviously there's a lot of data to be dealing with though can the idea of an avatar be
broken up into different files that components we can load as needed uh not dynamically but in some
regards yes um so just as you might have a hat that can be snapped on if you do it correctly
and amati if you're still in chat they have a um good example um you can do like snappable clothing
snappable ab um uh outfits uh snappable systems and all sorts of stuff like that which means you
should just load it from the inventory um i do have actually a note on that one but i'll leave
that until we run out of questions because i didn't do it at the start because i was running
late so uh yes moving uh forwards oh left says is this office hours audio getting recorded yes
everything gets recorded sometimes i do get um like uh forgetful in uploading it but like there
is a recording and it will be on sounder.fm as soon as i can get it there uh yes um there is
before i started using sounder i did text based notes those just got like really unwieldy um if
you'd like to see more text based notes you're more than welcome to transcribe the recordings
um there is an automatic transcription feature which i'm working with sounder on improving
because right now it lags at my computer um let's move on to pyroshade why is that green
tick not as green today like do i have a colorblind filter or something i'm very confused
anyway um pyroshade says something has went on my mind is level building in respect to custom
geometry while blender is a fantastic tool i can't help imagine there's liable to in-game
tools someone has likely created for creating geometry on the fly do you have any tools for
this and what you recommend um there's two types of of like buildings or geometry that uh you'd
likely need to create for a world one of them would be terrain so we're talking like grass
hills etc stuff like that and then the other one would be buildings you know a house a warehouse a
hut a shed a bridge or whatever for uh terrain um there are some terrain editors the problem with
those is that they are usually not as flexible as a mainstream terrain editors that you might find
are but you can still go ahead and get away with them uh the terrain editor that i'm thinking of
was when mmc entries so you should be able to find it just by searching for terrain editor
it lets you edit terrain in in game uva editing is another problem you might have with editing
creating game um as for buildings uh the builder tip by gahape which is one of the members of our
fantastic news community is what i would recommend i don't have a link to it or a tutorial for it
um so it might be a little bit difficult to find but if you go to essential tools jp tools it
should be somewhere in there uh look for gappy's builder tip it allows you to snap stuff together
on a grid how all sorts of parts have custom parts it's it's really good really quick um
if i can remember where it is i've been trying to find it for a couple of days i haven't managed
to find it there is a video i think by kahape which is like here's me building a house in 45
minutes and they just use the the builder tip and make a whole house it's crazy uh matty says i've
threatened a public banner and mentor leads before overworking yeah rest rest mentors community
members moderators rest it can wait it can wait it can wait alex says that they are using uh
they're using green tick rather than white check mark which is why i'm i'm not crazy excellent
thank you uh i i don't know where like i don't know how to get a happy tool other than like just
browsing through my folders which of course i can do whilst we wait for a few more questions
so i'm just gonna go ahead and do that let me just make sure i'm not missing any yeah i'm not
missing any questions uh is it even in this folder these days uh grab body node pack cd player gimbal
gimbal no it's not okay so their folder isn't in there i'll have to find that in the public folder
listing then uh gee items okay yeah i got it let me just get a link that for you there you go if
you paste that in the game uh you'll get a gap is a public folder get these items inside that
folder you will find a folder called tool tip go inside there and you will uh see a bunch of tips
uh look for the builder tip um build it at 1.1 and then it's there unfortunately i have no guide on
how to use it if someone else would like to make one of those fantastic uh great but uh i haven't
actually managed to like make a guide for how to use it yet mostly because i'm like not quite sure
but i know it's really cool and a lot of people have a lot of a great time with it mellow has
a question which says i really apologize if this discussed already if it was discussed already it's
totally fine i would answer anyway you just keep asking questions and don't worry about what you
worry about what the question is um i will answer it all day if i if i need to um they say is there
a plan to implement client-side filters for other people's advertisement how optimized they are
not currently our um approach there would probably be what can we remove um from your cognitive load
i mean by that is i'm always looking for stuff i can remove from your mental load not because i
don't think anyone can do it but just because like hey it's a game it's a platform we should make
things easy where if we can for our users so if there is a performance problem with a particular
avatar we'd like to see what we can do to edit that to make that better um so an example there
being hey let's actually start with user to user blocking um which we don't have currently and we
need before we go on to any sort of performance based stuff bean bean m chocolate that's kind of
difficult to phrase there um they said they've got something weird attached to them if you're
worried about what you've got um attached to you parented to you or like what's going on best
result is to leave the world and rejoin or respawn or change avatar it should go away if it doesn't
um that may be something malicious in which case please open a report at moderation.neos.com for
us to take a look um from the pictures it appears to be a multi-tool that you've somehow equipped
um you can just de-equip that tool and it should go away respawning is the the best way to like
get get that sorted um jelly yeah i'm not sure if we have like a cross communication there like
i'm not saying you could split them into separate avatars and ultimately that's what i would probably
advise but if you wanted a jacket a hat i don't know whatever that you could attach to the avatar
there are ways to do that as linked in matty's post above i have a hat which i don't ever wear
but sometimes can if i want to wear for example moving forwards to more questions so robo man
410 hello what are some of the top games activities the community has made um i don't like
doing that because like i would have to then choose my favorites and that's wrong um do you remember
that the world browser has um a game selection and you can go ahead and click that and then you'll
see a bunch of stuff there uh at the top of my head thinking about things if you want to go see
like crazy crazy crazy stuff this isn't good this isn't bad this is just crazy stuff from memory
go take a look at h&l uh ironworks that lets you smith smith weapons um the newest fishing lets
you fish aerial garden guardian mmc feels like a whole game really like it's it's uh it needs
some more polish before i would you know be okay of like launching on steam or anything but like
it's a it's a good game there is uh there is lots lots there please build more as well if you have
an idea for a game just go ahead and build it if you need help ask us all right let's move on to
question olef says how would you make an emitter of some sorts that spawns a random model plus
texture from a list of models that move and move rotate said spawned model on a path from a to b
and how to make the model gets despawned watch it reads its destination there's a component called
random object spawner it's a target for one of my next tutorials because i saw some people
discussing it earlier today and they didn't know how to use it so they didn't use it it's quite
cool uh you should probably use that um and if you want to go from point a to point b you could use
a uh skinned not skin mesh render what we're talking about a line transform
axis panner or the tween node to move that uh as for despawning it there is logic node called
delete destroy slot which will destroy the slot and anything underneath it uh so your approximate
plan would be spawn the thingy uh move it using tween axis panner line transform even alert would
do it actually and then destroy or destroy slot moving uh forwards if you've got any specific
questions about uh that particular setup do let me know um because uh i can just give you like
a bunch of videos like basically there's a video i made on reciprocal motion which means back and
forth like that should apply to sort of one direction as well if you just take off half of it
uh hack 13 asks what is the what is the too much respawn disconnect gestures i get them mixed up and
i want to make sure i remember which combos the buttons on next my head do it uh go look at the
basic controls page on the wiki because i always forget them too and therefore don't use them
but basic control should have a list and remind you what which ones which etc okay let's continue
erin says this is a moderation question but i'm never here for these office hours things
are you informed about the outcome of the moderation tickets you filed example you're
asked by something and something then decided to stay away from public worlds worth being taken
care of you are notified when we receive a ticket some people say that that is like a robot thing
like that's not actually a person yes it is automated in some aspects but it's like we've
received it we're processing it you'll also um get various messages sometimes we ask for more
information uh if we ask you for more information please provide it and you'll also get the sort of
ticket closed i don't remember the exact phrasing of that um but to sort of back that up we're
never going to tell you what we did and the reason behind that is because it just leads to it just
leads to drama right so it's you're never going to get like you say you put in a ticket which is like
yo i'm being harassed by erin you're never getting a response which is hi yeah we banned erin for the
rest of their life from neo so you're not going to get that like you'll get like hey moderation
has taken appropriate action or moderation has reviewed this and taken appropriate action or
something like that isn't because like we're hiding it from you it just it prevents all
sorts of like weird cases where people yell at each other people are strange when it comes to
moderation uh moving forwards let's take a look so dat uh asks is there any documentation for
networking because i'm struggling a lot with my current game that needs a lot of sync um
do you mean like the sync progress thing like syncing five items at the top etc
because like i've noticed that being a problem in users but i i don't know why i have been playing
the game for many many years and i've never had a sync issue um the usual ways to like avoid having
sync issues are to make sure that your hard drive space is not going to fill up and also that your
cloud space is not going to fill up and also that you are only saving the stuff that you need i see
people that are pack riding stuff away and it's like ah please stop saving that like do you need
the 5000 weapons that you're saving please no um okay sold that has as a clarified network sync
between players that is largely dependent on where you are located and where those players are
located and how fast your internet is um so we we do have a way of going between players it's
called our relay um but if that relay isn't used then you're either using steam sockets
or using a direct connection to that person's computer and so if you are in australia and
they're in america then you'll have less of an ability to sync between players if you connect
to the same country you'll have better uh stuff there yeah big red wolfie is one of our australian
players we have quite a few and uh they're just like they've just learned to cope with it
sometimes it depends what's going on as well depends how many people are in the world um
depends how many people are in the world um if like a world gets busy you'll have more and more
sync issues jumping down to it eastern says private doesn't have to get issues that isn't
what i was saying what i was saying is like i gave people advice about how to avoid it um
on the topic of sync issues there is something i need to say which is stop again for the love
of everything stop deleting your local nearest database you can delete your cash that's fine
just stop deleting the local nearest database unless support or something you read tells you to
what i see a lot is people going like x or y didn't work so i you know reinstalled my entire
computer and i i rebuilt the building i live in and i deleted everything and i sold all my worldly
possessions and i moved into the mountains and it still doesn't work and it's like well like the
fix for that wasn't any of that so make sure it's clear that you have gone through prior
debug steps to do it uh there are some sections on the frequently asked questions that do cover
that those do need to be better we just need to write some better ones there uh so jumping back
up now we're away from uh actually electron it says deleting your database can make issues worse
correct it can um in computing there's like a few ways to solve a problem there's fix the problem
which means hey it doesn't reoccur and you learn something there is delete the problem that's
usually where you reinstall the game you reinstall your computer or even when you reboot your computer
when you reboot your computer you're just flushing all the bits back down to to zero not of course on
the you know the hard drive storage but like all of the bits in your cpu all of the bits in your
memory is just like flushed back to zero and so the problem just gets deleted it doesn't get fixed
or you can ignore the problem so your choices are fixed delete or ignore and uh i never want to do
the delete i frequently do the ignore though let's move back to other questions that we got here so
uh actually we'll have to end at the top of the hour so i'm going to try and get through this
quick as i can um so bean says uh thanks that got off there's a train brain treat fair is there a
terrain build a system i can use like a voxel system where i can just dig into the terrain or
add on to it i saw some terrain but i don't know if that was built outside of neos um not to that
level it's not like how some of those like voxel based games um hydrogen air comes to mind we can
just like dig a massive hole or like some of the minecraft inspired games where you can just like
dig more sort of smoother terrain in not like that no but the terrain editor that we do have in game
is uh cool for making just sort of like larger more general structures we're able to say like
here's a hill here's a mountain here's a valley etc but you wouldn't be able to be like i want
the mountain to be in the shape of my favorite dog potato munchkin that that's that you'll need
the outside terrain systems for that and that's because the outside outside terrain systems have
like brushes and you can go in and you can brush onto that terrain with various sets of brushes and
pull things around such that it looks how you want it to look you can sometimes get away with just
like drawing like a height map and to make terrain as well um again then there's like a loss of detail
jelly says that uh they're in a session and someone spawned stuff and it wasn't visible
interactable into almost an hour that's a uh that's a synchronization thing um check your
queued packets there are various ways to do that various uis very spawnable thing even bobs there's
even a logics node for it um queue packets are basically how many messages are waiting on the
server to be delivered to you and if all of your queued packets are zero then that means you are
up to date with the server there's nothing being waited wait waited wait waited being there's
nothing waiting to come down to you there you go take a sentence the right way around uh night
nitrous 96 says i was wondering on the status of the quest to port of neos is um it is in the
android testers channel if you don't have patreon at 12 or more you cannot see it it is a testing
build it is not suitable for mainstream use it crashes about every 45 minutes for various reasons
and if you go into average session on neo she'll probably crash due to the amount of blend shapes
that exist on people's avatars right now um more work needs to happen on it before it become
mainstream and before it can become optimized um that work is not happening right now see the
answers channel um so that's really the state isn't it okay solder has a further expanded the
question totally fine that this that happens just keep on asking the question in different ways
till i actually answer something that makes sense and and we'll get there i apologize for that so
they said that they're making a game and are struggling to sync the game state because there's
almost no documentation about sync what type of stuff would you like to sync so as an example here
if you'd like to sync like ammo on a gun um you might want to sync that locally or something like
that um you need to learn a couple of preset thingies so you would need to learn take a look
at dynamic impulses dynamic variables cloud variables and just logics in general and then
you should know how to sync it isn't something that like you usually need to think about and
that's why there isn't much documentation on it right because you don't usually need to do like
when it comes to game design you don't usually need to do synchronization with neos you just need
to know the tools that are available and build the game around that there is a video i did recently
about mindable ore in a game that will sync across everyone without any additional work
in that mindable or tutorial you have to hit a pickaxe three times into an ore node and it will
drop a piece of ore which is an item none of that has to be synced manually by you uh the moment you
hit it once of a pickaxe every single user provided they're not queued of course will get a message
that you've hit it and that you need to hit it two more times before it comes out like you don't
need to do anything extra there alex has found a skipped question which is fantastic thank you for
doing that um alex uh has pointed to it is there a good guide for explaining layering for worlds
like separation or instancing uh no um be careful when you're doing that like uh if you're doing it
for coloring culling coloring if you don't have color reasons fantastic um uh for culling you
need to keep in mind that people will insist that they need to be in noclip even when they don't
need to be in noclip so you'll have to do some sort of culling system that works in noclip that's
one of the reasons why i haven't documented it because i just disagree with that i'm like if you
need culling you should not be in noclip noclip is called noclip because you don't clip we actually
had a github issue a long time ago just like can you make noclip clip i'm like no no we can't make
no clip clip so by my knowledge there isn't any guide on it uh what you're looking for is culling
system if you ask in other channels in discord for a culling system some people will show you
what they've got nitrous asks uh uh if there's any plans to optimize the game yes optimization
is like always something i'm thinking about but always something everyone else is thinking about
as well that's also why sometimes features don't come out as quickly as you would like
we could quite easily throw out collections tomorrow for example but it would not be
optimized there'd be more key packets um it will be largely and holistically more frustrated than
the lack of collections that's why it doesn't exist um we're always planning on optimizing it
fruits has a list of stuff they just need to do to be more optimized and with that we've reached
the bottom of the questions so i want to do i should have given this at the start but i do
want to give one more message joniel that's still listening here slots do not cause lag
stop proliferating that rumor i will chase you with cat gifs until you stop i was in a several
worlds over the week and people like yeah slots cause they don't slots count the slot count of
an avatar the slot count of an item is a symptom not a cause the symptom is there are a lot of
slots and the reason why there are a lot of slots is because there's too much on that particular
system so if you want to optimize an avatar start by removing systems don't remove slots remove
systems do you need to tell us your favorite cabbage variety above your head in your name
badge do you need to tell me your fps do you need to tell me your battery control level
do you need to tell me that your uh local time do you need to tell me the weather in your location
do you need to do any of that no you don't so remove that remove that before you start removing
slots remove systems do you need a gun at your hip for every single session that you're in no
remove that do you need um do you need a custom inspector parented to your avatar no spawn it in
with the tool when you need to do build let's move uh so yeah just just think about like it's it's
like a it's like a stacked order of things because like electronics points out like shifty has said
the uh slot transforms due to ik cause some lag yes they do cause some lag but not compared to
the like a million systems that are on your avatar that you don't need like it's all relative right
so think about what you're loading into the world before you think about how many slots it has
because like the slots are just a symptom right if it's a complicated system it's going to have
a lot of slots and if it's complicated it's probably causing lag by itself and doesn't need
to care about the slot count like i could probably rig up a 1 million slot thing that has the same
that has the same performance as like one rex avatar it's not slots moving uh forwards for the
last few questions uh cloud cloud support says uh your vision aware virtual worlds building and
hanging out and special communities are i don't quite understand the question i don't personally
have a vision there i just want to enable people to like build cool shit and that's the the vision
i know that's a poor answer but like it's difficult to answer that one unless there's
more specificity about what's going on just notice that you've clarified some specificity
specificity there by saying curious about where things are headed uh you can see our roadmap that's
on the github which has all the sort of features that we're looking for and stuff like that uh
aside from those features the general goal is to just enable you guys to create more and more stuff
with more and more tools more and more abilities and to be more optimized and easier to use so
that's our like forward progression okay moving forwards to nitrous's next question um how do i
go about completely wiping my home worlds because i messed up and now have a giant miku that i can't
delete uh you can delete that open up the um inspector and just go through each item in the
inspector and you'll find the miku and you can delete it you can reset those home worlds but
it'll be a lot easier to just go through the inspector and find that miku and you also learn
about how to do that process for next time that happens um i don't know if anyone in here was
aware it was around we were in uh raivi's nest world and uh i noticed in the middle of spawn
was a single flame badge and siro then spent like 30 minutes trying to figure out where that flame
badge was and we eventually got there like we eventually found it it was a null parented slot
which sometimes does happen it's a bug and it's problematic uh and then uh actually so nitro has
a second question which is i've seen people with custom menus of different sounds what mod is that
that's not a mod um that's another thing like i like like the policy like i wrote the policy on
modding the modern community are fantastic if there's one thing i could say and you know you're
entitled to go do your own research etc it's stop looking for mods when you initially join the game
learn about our existing features before you go look for mods like we had someone in the modding
discord the other day asking for a mod to enable flying and it's like that's just part of neos you
can just fly you don't need a mod for that and so again for um custom menus of different sounds you
don't need a mod for that you just build it um when building those things do keep in mind that
some users myself included are sound sensitive and that we don't care when you open up your context
menu and so if you should for example use kingdom hearts sound effects from the menu noises of
kingdom hearts on the global audio channel at 150 volume every time you open your context menu
i'm likely to kick you from my world it is like no offense like i don't i'm not angry of you
i just don't want to hear kingdom hearts music menu every time you open your context menu so
don't do that maybe play it locally and maybe make it situational if it's locally actually i
don't care but like if it's not local make it situational and make it sound reasonable
well now you open up a context menu i don't want to hear the entire halo soundtrack you know the
choral like r's and o's from the main soundtrack don't need that don't know why anyone does please
don't do it okay i'm going to go through these really really quick i do have to go at the behalf
as i said um electronicis ought to know about more slot transforms what exactly is that and what be
the way to minimize that that's about calculating where our slot is relative to another slot so i
don't know and i'm not going to give out false information so i don't know but i would think
theoretically theoretically say the um parenting logic systems to the top of your avatar would
probably be best as there are low less transforms there but again it's not about slots just just
reiterating that it's just like uh an idea shark says when you talk about slots but you meet the
do you mean by slots every clothing option reduces performance even if it's not in use
uh slot you if you're familiar with unity vr chat stuff like that slot is basically an empty game
object it's anything with a transform anything in the hierarchy that appears on the left side of
ninos of unity uh over in unity it's called game object over here it's called slots it's basically
just like a position a rotation and a scale of which things can be attached to including other
slots um so you want to keep that count low but you want to look at other stuff before you worry
about slot count so if you're like yes my avatar is 800 slots but it also has like 50 000 logics
nodes on it talking to a web socket server so i can see the uh temperature of your hamster's
rear end that's probably what's causing lag and not the slots uh so that says what's the best and
most optimized way to do quaternion look rotations uh check the components we have uh transform
drivers look at look at user and auto look at user i don't know the difference between all those
three i just pick one and mess with it till it works and if it doesn't work i'll load the other
ones and take a look at those those are the best ways to do it because those are the simplest ways
you don't have to do any of the maths yourself you just put in some details and it'll do the
look rotation for you we also have in logics we have math rotation and then there is look
rotation as a node which would work in a similar way to how the unity function would work if you're
familiar with that one i used that one the other day both of those are as optimized as we can get
them uh so use those don't wherever possible see if there's a node that does the mathematical
calculation for you because in those aspects we're able to optimize it for you basement says
what's wrong with the entire helo centric the helo centric is fantastic someone opening their
context menu and then a halo spawning around it the halo from halo and then the the coral
main track going off whilst they fumble around with equipping a tool and then close it again
not cool uh aaron says that that's not an actual question great skipping it uh no more questions
after aaron i gotta run it's it's getting late but i'll get uh olaf's and i'll get nate's uh
olaf says which trial subjects are planned to cover in the near future i don't know i had the
covid booster yesterday and i'm alternating between shivering and boiling everyone's like
you should skip office hours and i'm like no i've been doing office hours like every week for a solid
like year i'm not losing my streak uh so i don't know today maybe some tara who knows i want to do
um like i said i want to do random object spawner and i want to do a few on stuff which i just i
just see questioned and aren't covered that may involve some of the um the walking animation stuff
etc but like it basically is like when i start recording is what i feel like it used to be i
could do like i knew i was planning out because i hadn't done tutorials and everything but now
it's harder and harder to find something that i like go yep i can do that um nate wrench says
can we filter uh worlds that have potato modes uh yes if you would like to contact a user that
has a potato mode in their world and ask them to add the potato tag to their world tags then you'll
be able to search for worlds by the potato tag and then you'll be able to find worlds that have the
potato modes uh worlds can have tags tags are very powerful make sure that your worlds have
appropriate tags if your world is a game make sure it has the game tag give us a piece of art make
sure it's the art tag uh i split shots when is the office house hosted each week um i will post
a wiki link in just a moment and uh my last final message before i go because i really don't have to
run is make tickets if someone is bad to you in a session if they harass you if there's a problem
if you want to get someone banned because you don't like them moderation.neos.com we won't
penalize you for invalid tickets we would rather hear about it moderation.neos.com best way to get
in touch with moderation fastest way to get in touch with moderation thank you and goodbye