Welcome to office hours if you have a question, please go ahead and drop it in the office hours text chat
There's a couple channels above this one that we're currently in
And we'll get them answered in the order that they appear. We have a question flooding in so fantastic. We'll get to it right away
So Tiki asks, I know an empty world takes around 20 megabytes. I have a custom world that uses 1.6
6 6 giga giga biggie, but good boo 1 6 gigabytes 1 point try again 1.66 gigabytes the usage report only shows the world as one big blob
How can I understand what is taking space in the world? Um
Take a look in the world and maybe try saving parts of it separately to see how big those are
Do you remember that the file space?
Reporting isn't entirely accurate in some cases. So
an empty world probably won't take 20 megabytes because
It's most the assets that are everywhere. So they don't really
meet your
Your quota as for the world that is taking 1.6 6
Yeah, save different parts of the world. See if there's anything large in there
Make sure you've got the clean up unused assets thing of a Bob turned on you can also do that from the asset clean up
Was it to try and clean that up?
Look through all the slots make sure that there's this stuff there if need be and I only say this like
I only do this like when I really really need to actually also look in the assets folder
You shouldn't really go in there too much, but you can mess stuff up by just you know doing incorrect stuff in there
But take a look inside the assets folder make sure there's nothing in there that for some reason isn't being cleaned up
Keep an eye your textures and materials there
It's surprising how many sort of of the CC zero materials as well are to offer K and then they really don't need to be
So maybe it's that
moving forward to
Lex question asks
What's a good way of presenting educational content?
In this case complex geometry to the nearest community in a way that makes sense to most people or at least intrigued
You mean like mathematically complex geometry. I like the walls and experiences which like let people play with it
so a good example would be the
The
Neural network world that was produced for M.C. I believe it's 22
By a team that involved orange
I don't remember who is on the like entire team there
But they gave you sort of a history of AI and then they let you play with a very simple artificial intelligence that can play pong
And they let you play with it in a way where you can like you can interact with it
There's also a few worlds by me where I sort of lay out stuff in a way that can be played with
If anyone that's hung out with me enough you probably seen some of my mathematical things where I've sort of started trying to build a sort
of Museum of Maths with having different
educational ways of showing content
As a help to that I want to
Link this again. I think I linked it in a previous office hours
I just pushed a weird button and Chrome did a weird thing. I've never seen it do before. Okay, strange
I
understood I said Pythagoras as a kid with a humongous amount of explanation and understanding right traditional stuff
But the video that I just linked gives people
Something that you can play with like I've seen a similar setup in a variety of museums etc that allows people to just like play
With what's going on and see what happens the context actually does help so
Lex is talking about the monotile
That was discovered by someone completely unexpected wasn't it?
I can't remember and I don't really have a chance to sort of read through this but it's a
Tile that when you use the pattern will never repeat
Something on that it's like really complicated
Yeah, make a world or a symbol or a sorry not a world or a tool
That's what I mean not simple make a world or a tool where people can play with the mathematics of that to see what's happening
all right moving forwards to
a
Cloud pandas question in expansion to Tiki's question. I have a 2.6 ish gigabyte
I know I have 2.6 ish gigabytes used out of 3 gigabytes for my cloud storage
I don't quite know is eating up all that storage
I have some worlds and some avatars and shouldn't take up my much storage as it is
What do you recommend doing to remedy that make sure you do the usage report that will show you what's going on there?
Keep an eye on things like videos textures etc those do mount up quickly particularly if there are four or eight K textures moving forward to
How do I do this report thing is I'll jump ahead to look out who says how do I do the report thing?
You can find that command on
The wiki I'll get you a link in just a second
Hey, there's a link to that so it's near spot storage commands on the NES wiki will show you how to do that
moving forwards to exos
Question X that we could ask with the tail root virus being dealt with how long should we have there is protections in our worlds
I know how to answer that because we still have the protections in the world for the previous instance of something similar to that
In the actual code base, so I don't really know how to answer the question to that
the problem that occurs is let's say it's a year or two down the line and
Someone spawns into your world and for whatever reason they need to refer to where take a look at spawn
Whatever the hell you want
An item that has that element on it it will reinfect the population
In particular if any saving is going on
I don't really know how to answer that one
In that regard then it'd be interesting if someone made like a detector and cleaner
that
kept data tracking somehow make sure you're following the guidelines of course on this but like let's say you had a detector that
Like just tapped some sort of web endpoint on the shoulder every time it found one to clean up
You could then graph those over time should do that anonymously as well
There's no need to know who it was or whatever just like I found one web server
I found one the web server goes got it and
Then you could graph that over time and and and when that tails off down to like zero
You'd be like, okay, it's probably safe to do it now. It's interesting though because if you look at the
cases of things like smallpox or
What's the one no smallpox has been eradicated many? I don't know how because it's very difficult but
Polio that's the one if you look at polio
It looks like it's been eradicated but hasn't occasionally there's a spike in polio cases
So that's why you're still vaccinated against it as a kid or issue are in the UK. Um, I think it says people might get annoyed
By HTTP dialogue just for it
If you're the world host no do it as the world host if it's a popular headless as well
You can do it as the headless host and then you could do double check the guidelines there because it's anonymized
It's basically like I found this not where it was found. It would be okay
I think it's just you know, the detection logic found a case of it
Tap a web address. I think that's all the questions we have. So I'm gonna scroll up and down
I haven't missed any I have not
Do assist or other loop? What does the tail root virus do?
It self propagates itself into various systems behinds in avatars tail roots. It's tail root virus and
It will when it gets attached to a user it will emulate stick drift. It is quite
Malignant in the way that it hides
so even if you weren't working on avatars, you might find it inside the world there are various detection systems and
Removers that you can find and use I would recommend running them on anything you have saved recently
I would also recommend for the mean time
Unfortunately for the mean time that if you're saving an avatar you do it in a private world. I know that's problematic
You know or you have a detection system where an alarm goes off when when one is found
Because when one instance of it is found, they'll be surely more common and truly really annoying and not that I want to like, you know
Rant on ahead about this more
But if you're in a public world and you're editing your avatar like maybe don't like build something cool build an experience
Build something that reaches out touches me and says I exist
I am a cool experience because then at least it's you know, it's right into that experience. There are no
Sorry, excuse me. There are no additional questions. Just make sure you get those questions in and on some the order appear
Otherwise we'll sit here in silence
Hope everyone's day is going
fantastic
Tabbing around back to the chat
Jackal asked have I missed an update to how your move is going whether you settled in yet the move is at the end of the
Week I go on about a lot because I find moving really stressful. But yeah, I see that at the week
An update there is I'm amazed how much you can pack whilst maintaining functionality of an apartment
I mean by that is I have a ton of boxes packed
But I can still you know, drink water make tea use the bathroom like everything in there. Not just the toilet, you know like showering
washing hands everything in the bathroom
Perfectly fine in there. My computer still works VR still works
I am down to base stations though because they're in the way
So I took those down bookshelves completely empty, but I'm still sat here talking to you guys office hours
I know it'll be like a real move when I start losing functionality
So, you know when I can't sleep in the bed or I can't make food or whatever
Link asked how a runescape is going
We'll go there until if a Neos question appears we will abruptly stop because this is a Neos
See, okay. We're gonna stop immediately. We've got a Neos question. Never mind. No runescape
I'm actually happy about that
Tiki asked when optimizing a world for performance. What's the best to start with between lighting materials and colliders?
Start with materials because
That will affect the world
The most but I'm trying to basically do is when you optimize stuff you want to preserve the original intention of the world
So if you have sort of like I don't know I always go to this art example
I don't know why someone make this like a moody
Backwater sort of you know
dive bar in like a you know, very quiet dark street like, you know
You still want that atmosphere to be there?
And so if you're optimizing and somehow you lose that because of optimization that's like the wrong way to optimize. So
Start with materials and lighting do colliders last because colliders shouldn't affect the visual and functional parts of the world
they just affect performance, but if you don't start with materials and lighting and you're
You might end up with a point where it's like oh, I've optimized everything else about this world, but this material is like wrong
So I got to swap it out now
I don't know the bar counters a different type of wood or whatever and I have ruined the whole aesthetic that I was going
I was going for if you do materials then lighting
It means you don't get into the point where like oh this materials now too light because like I you know
There's now light on it. I know it's too light. I'm gonna make it dark
It's just like, you know, I also consider what people use in the world
I've seen a common thing in VR chat for example is like every single goddamn world has the pool set up
You know, you can play pool the game not a pool is in swimming pool that with the snooker but baby snooker
That's what some people call pool
Every single world in VR chat has udod pool and it's not used. It's just not used
So just don't put it in the world
Or consider not putting it in the world
And again, that'll be a lot more optimization because remember that each of those those balls
Has a texture and if there are too many balls, there's too many textures and then there's too many materials. I mean
Hopefully those balls are atlased into one
Material but it is VR chat
Think it says VR chat has texture streaming though on like us. We have file streaming right when you load into a world
And stuff but you know, do you need balls in your world?
No, particularly with Neos where like if someone wanted to play the lirds pool, whatever
They could spawn out a table and just plop it down in the middle
I think I said sometimes Neos client doesn't even load from cash
It's really downloads them from the cows point having cash it downloads from the cash from the cloud when it senses that it needs to
for whatever logic that it might have if that logic is broken or
problematic
Then it's probably a bug that we need to fix
So I'm noticing a lack of questions. So let's go back up to runescape. Oh, no, here we go. We got a question
This is great thread to talk about runescape and people post Neos questions. This is amazing
Tiki asks in continuation the question. How about of a hit on performance do very complex mesh colliders all around the world do
Mesh colliders are bad on high poly things
Where you are colliding with them a lot or in differing ways
Example here might be let's say you have a mesh collider. That's just a square right? It's floor. It's floor. So it's a square
that's okay, right because the poly count should be low, but now let's say that the
It's not like regular for its terrain. Okay, that's a little bit worse because the train is a bunch of sort of
meandering triangles that make the sort of bumps and the valleys and the hills in
In the terrain now, let's go up to that if it's the $8 chicken nugget touching that or walking on that is very painful
would not suggest
Beyond that if the mesh collider is active you're gonna die
a good way to remember this is that if it's not a mesh collider and if it's not a
I'm just putting convex cull colliders in a different category
Those are more efficient than mesh colliders
But just putting them in a different category just for now if it's a primitive collider that is not a convex hull collider
The mathematics for determining whether you are colliding for it with a very simple because they're volume based
It's are you inside the volume of this collider, which is very easy mathematically with convex hull
There's different maps. I don't quite understand but with mesh colliders
It's are you inside every single triangle of this mesh and it does it on a triangle level?
Because right it doesn't know what the structure of the mesh is. It has to sort of test every triangle
So if your mesh has a hundred K triangles, that's a hundred K tests if your mesh has one triangle
That's one test hence why floor is okay. Because if a floor is just a square then it should just be two triangles
Unless yeah fusion 360 makes it a lot
I've noticed the architectural tools and 3d printing tools
Make more complex geometry because they need that level of detail because they're going to a CNC machine
They're going to a CAD machine. They're going to a 3d printer. They need that detail
so it doesn't really apply to architectural or
printy things
Think you asked what's the weird collider have a ha ha ha ha go to 2.0 thing
That is a HVAC or HCAV. I can't remember which way around it is
Mesh decomposition. I have a video on that on my channel
More people should use it
Additionally, there is someone who in the comments sort of mentioned how they use it which completely
Completely destroys the point of using it. So try not to do that, but I'll link the video in just a second
I talked about the simplicity of that
Here as well
In the video I talked about how a cat actually the cat pitched in the thumbnail there convex hold decomposes very well
But how the convex hold decomposition for the chicken nugget isn't that good?
But then I also talked about how for the this conference table in the middle of the world during that tutorial
there's no real need to update the
The collision meshes for that conference room table. It's very low poly
there's also a version of that cat in my meme folder where I've selectively removed a few of the convex holes and
Texture the convex holes is bread. So it looks like the cat is sort of embedded in bread. It is very good
I couldn't tell you how it works though. There's like if you like click the help icon, it's like yeah if you change the theta
Number it does like magical blah blah blah. It's like, okay great. I have no idea what that means
There's also the lucca lucca cat and then the meme folder that one doesn't work as well
I want to rewrite it
But my meme folder is just a journey through insanity like where else like memes in popular culture are things which are very widely known
My meme folder is stuff that it's very wildly known to me
But no one else everyone's going through it and they're just like what the hell is going on. It's like, I don't know
Okay, we're gonna try and go back to RuneScape. Okay, this means more Nios questions. This is amazing. I love this. I love this
So RuneScape had a bunch of promotions stacked on top of each other which are really frustrating me right now
Because it means I can't do what I'm trying to do which is get to 95 divination
But so first of all, they had this event called the golden cape event and that you had to do like a bunch of just crazy
Stuff to get golden cape shards eight golden cape shards made you a golden cape
The golden cape is going for like 13 million gold right now
So like I was doing it for the money
But it turns out that the golden cape gets you a buff for 30 days
Which means any gathering that you do immediately teleports to your bank
So if you're mining rather than it going into your inventory it teleports to your bank
So when that started I then had to spend basically 30 days making use of that
So I decided to train mining because mining is very simple
There are other gathering skills like wood cutting but sometimes a tree doesn't respawn
So you have to like walk around and click a different tree or find another tree
But for mining you stand in one spot and you just periodically have to click the rocks and it will continue mining
And so I got mining from like level 59 all the way to 91 in those 30 days
And there's still six days left and I've progressed through the ores
So much so that every time I now hear the mining sound I'm making 4k because I'm mining top-level ore
Like I hear like quack
It's 4k, quack 4k, quack 4k and it immediately goes to my bank. So it's really profitable
But during that they also had a beach event where you had to go to a beach and do a bunch of beach events
Beach events were great exp apparently, but I didn't really do them
There was also sandy clue scrolls now sandy clue scrolls are different from regular clue scrolls in that they are
Themed for the beach and given to you by a lady called sandy
Now the best way to do sandy clue scrolls is a like little tip for next time the beach happens maybe
Do it
RuneScape themed office hours at another time is if you collect the sandy clue scrolls on a non-members world
The pool of clues that they they pull from is much smaller
So swap to a non-members world do the clue scrolls there if the clue scroll tells you to go to somewhere that is not on
The beach destroy the clue scroll get a new clue scroll and it will be on the beach and you just keep doing that
so sometimes the clue is like travel across the lands to the top of the mountain and pray to
Jesus or something you just destroy the clue scroll pick up a new one
It says talk to the lady with the coconuts and then you can get it
But once you've completed the clue scroll and you've got the chest that you get at the end of the clue scroll
You have to swap back to a members world to open it. Otherwise, you'll get non-member rewards swapping that - wow, I'm hungry
I'll get some food off this swapping back to Nios because we have a question see how this works is great
is there any documentation on the number pad key binds on the
Camera and 360 camera launch modes for Nios there are not I didn't know that they had number pad key points
Used to be is no no no news on that
I'll have to add that to my documentation list which is like huge. We are now at half past so
Our final bit on runescape then once the beach ended they added this last wills event lost wills event
And that's where like when you do random activities you gain wills and you exchange wills to a skeleton man
And he gives you chests and you open those chests and you get random rewards because I've been mining during that I have like
5,000 of these lost wills like every couple of days I go in there and I just get so much junk
I've got like
Seven or eight rings that make me look like a zombie and they don't they can't sell them or trade them
But I've got seven of them and it's just like why am I getting duplicates? Why?
Anyway, we will leave off there as there are no additional questions, and this is not a runescape of ourselves
So I'm gonna go ahead and call it there. I will speak to you guys to next week where I will be
Where I will be in the new place. I just processed the audio for last week's
I would endeavor to process the audio for this week's now
I do need to do some more packing so that that will be where I don't need to use my computer
It does slow down the computer a lot and then I'll get that all sorted Lex understood
I'll try and get to those to you as soon as I can
Apologies for the delay there. I am quite busy trying not to die with my boxes. I will speak to you guys later