Okie dokie welcome to prime time this is the half hour segment where I answer
questions from you guys so drop questions in the questions and help
channel. Go ahead and just ping the role again just let people know that we are
getting started and then I'll get started with the first question which
has been queued up here by Zetaphor. Thank you for that question. They are
asking hey prime we're all noticing some interesting arrow logs showing up in our
temp folder indicating the use of caffe2, a machine learning library these
spaces to be correlated with us running our Neos clients and only started
around a week ago. Do you have any insight on this discussion here? Are you
sure you can't find that like anywhere else? We haven't updated any of our like
libraries or anything. Alright let me go to my temp folder like it's not that I
don't believe you guys it's just that I'm trying to find the fastest way to
get an answer here and so if I have files as well data doesn't exist for
some reason. Local temp just in local temp like no other folder or anything
like in the root of local temp yeah I got them. Weird. Alright I'll have to dig
into that one some more it's a good on the ping there I did see the ping come
in before but we'll start it with like I'll dig into this after after this
office hours segment we'll move on to questions if they are there if they're
not I'll just mute and dig into this way let's take a look there are no
additional questions right now so please get some questions into the questions
and helps channel not the questions help channel sorry the questions prime time
thread within the office hours text channel I'll get to them as soon as I
can whilst we wait for questions I'll be looking into this log awareness I thank
you I don't answer questions about food it's just questions about Neos so one of
things about these log files is that is the temp directory and that the temp
directory is bombarded with just absolute bullshit 24-7 so yeah no it's
not so the next question we have from Zetta is it's possible to drive
rotation from a pan of 3d or other 3d components no quaternions are
four-dimensional vectors that are like they have different rules completely
different rules to regular mathematics because of what they need to do and how
they need to work wiggly would be the any way that you could do that honestly
like some form of other components would be better at that point it is float to
Q not float 3 we render it as float Q and sorry we render it as float 3 in the
inspectors because float Q's don't make sense to the average user so we do
Euler Euler and interpolation in the in the inspector so that's just a display
thing it's not something that you can like use so just like find a component
that works if look you maybe value gradient drive will be a good way to do
Pana or just use logics the you know the amazing feature that we added to Neos
for you to use that it also says that they didn't using logics in the end for
their rotational issues just great they want to make sure that they weren't
reinventing a component yeah um there are a few like mapper components that
might do it for you but don't worry about like reinventing a component just
just do it whatever way works for you obviously if you need to optimize later
do it but for the most part it'll be okay just reminder for those who are
just joining or have not heard before this is office hours if your questions
please drop them in the office hours text chats thread for this particular
session that's a few channels about the one that you're currently in I'll ask
them in the order that they appear any questions will do thank you so no
question here from Zari who asks is there a way to load assets when joining
a world before one actually spawns into it for the chugging lagging when one
joints more properly session yes you need to customize it yourself though or
build a tool to do it there is a functionality in the open world logics
node which will prevent loading into like switching until the world is ready
I have heard it can be flaky but people use a lot for portals and well
transition systems to take a look at that there we get Lex has made a world
preloader which is the the tool that I was referring to moving almost stars as
a question is there any way to get a single float value to drive let's say
just a Y value in a float to with just components of needs to be done in logic
that's fun too well in logic you would just do a pack XYZ or a pack XY to get
it into the appropriate data type that you wish to get into for non logics
methodologies look at the mapper component so there's a transform drivers
mapper something there those do very specific things which are often not
usable for this situation but like sometimes are if those don't work try
the swizzle drivers which are in relation swizzle drivers or I think
relations yeah the swizzle drivers kind of snuck in mostly because people don't
know what swizzling means it kind of sounds weird
swizzling is really much what you're after though it just means rearranging
like a vector a little bit don't answer questions about cheese in the prime time
office hours I ask questions about Neos what is your favorite type of cheese is
rejected you can search the previous notes for answers to that particular
question for example that's a new cheese question so Fuzzy Fox you'll manage to
get that new cheese question that I haven't had before but we'll go to
pandas question first which is what you like to do on your spare time lost or
Neos I have no spare time on Neos like if I'm not testing random bugs or
helping out people then I'm just trying to chill in the world but often when I'm
trying to chill in a to a world it turns into someone will come in and start
talking about mods or plugins someone will start coming in and talking about
how so-and-so feature of Neos needs to be written because they poked around in
the source code and they found out that they didn't like the way it is written
and I'm right there with you I just can't really do anything about it right
now so maybe don't do that to a Neos team member thanks or someone will come in and
complain about something which is understandable given the current climate
those are kind of like bad interactions but then if people come in and ask
questions that's usually the best interactions right they come in and
they're just like I'm trying to learn how to do X I'm you know I'm trying to
build this avatar make this thing I love those questions right because we're not
like it it's almost like meta conversations about Neos are thrown in
the same bucket as like crypto conversations you know how I'm like no
one wants to talk about crypto and Neos this like signs and various worlds
crypto conversation users will be shot or whatever I want like meta-Neos
discussions to also be in that bucket what do I mean by meta-Neos discussions
I mean discussions about the current situation about the code base about the
lack of certain features about the roadmap about like plans like accepting
Neos at face value and moving forwards with that to build something is my
favorite interaction with other users rather than being in a corner talking
about mods plugins or which part of the code base they'd like to read right if
they could it's all good like I get why you're doing it I'm not faulting you for
it it's just you know I've been working for like 12 hours today and trying to
hit chill out and someone's like this so-and-so thing makes no sense and I'm
like yeah I agree so now jumping down to what's your favorite cheese model that
you've come across so that's actually a cheese sandwich made by sloppy
mcfloppy using the ring of the neolander they just pulled out then area in the
lander they made a cheese sandwich it is in the cheese folder which is in my
public folder art and then cheese that is full of like basically everything
there including cheese wisdom which is a series of audio clips which apanda not
cloud panda recorded with my permission I didn't realize the recording I gave
them permission post afterwards and then I misspelled cheese wisdom very badly in
the folder name so I need to remit the folder by keep forgetting to anyway
there's some funny sound effects in there including explanation of why
platypuses do not have udders or nipples I promise you that audio is in there and
it's interesting because platypuses are mammals which is very confusing when you
look at a platypus it's like that's a duck or a beaver I'm very confused sir
asks have you ever thought about an alt if you haven't trouble in game
recognition I've never used an alt it's just like bad like I understand why
people do it I just like it's it's it's not my my dealio the the gains that you
get are not that much as well because like even though now people don't know
that you're a Neos team member some people will then know that you're a
Neos team member and then you've been decloaked and then even if no one knows
that you're a Neos team member you know you don't speak like for example has
anyone thought maybe froppy is actually frugs they both start with F and froppy
is mute and they never speak and they're really cool and frugs is really cool so
like is froppy frugs or vice versa like who knows anyway that is you know one
way of doing it is being mute but so like even with that right if no one
knows who you are you still have that burden there right so if you're inside a
session and people are complaining then you can still hear that feedback and
internalize that feedback even though you're on your own so it just wouldn't
work out froppy you're cool I've seen froppy and frugs in the same
session so that they're fine unless they're like multi boxing and like you
know splicing their VR into multiple computers at once you know yeah they do
both have two O's let's move forwards on some additional questions sorry says
have you felt that the videos about reading the room have had a tangible
impact on the behavior in Neos or do you wish people would point people more to
them in game I wish people would point people to whatever resource helps them
understand how that sort of avenue of stuff needs to work maybe my video
doesn't work for you for whatever reason and you need some other sort of resource
or mechanism for that I wish we had more I wish had faster ways of doing it as
well a good example of that would be over on VR chat where in the loading
screen they'll put up random messages I'm one of the like your best messages
there is like don't do shit without people's consent or well banya but like
really worthy nicely worded I'd car with exact wording so I was like paraphrasing
there it's a good message right and yeah people don't read it because it's a
loading screen and they kind of just zone out but it's about like making that
information available to people and available in a way that can be consumed
that video might not be like the best way to do that I don't know what the
best way is what I do know though is that that video has led to a lot of
people give me feedback that they have enjoyed it and I also know that has
shaped a lot of people's way of you know interacting with people on Neos which
evidently you know will rub off on some other parts of the population as it sort
of spreads culturally in a sort of tribal way right so it has done good I
just wish there was some mechanism we could do to sort of like you know swoop
down into your brain you put a headset right we could add some like surgical
instruments to your VR headset and just let you know slot it directly into your
brain with some drills and stuff it's really the only way we'd get everyone
like on that information and hey my my videos terrible on all of the social
videos I'm like disclaimer I might be poo-poo poo-poo pee-peeing this up I
might be like literally being hypocritical and sometimes I am and
that's because we're all not perfect right sometimes I might fail to read
the room sometimes I might but in an accident they take over when someone's
helping someone like we're not perfect and so I keep that disclaimer there
because like hey you want to call me out on something go for it if we learn and
grow together we'll learn and grow together or as if we just like I don't
know get scared about and hide in the corner we'll get scared about it and hide
in the corner Zachary has a question here which is if I built a world and I'm
not sure if I did something an efficient way could I ping you and let you swing
by to take a look I do not have time to do that best bet is to ask in the
discord for a mentor specifically a mentor that is suitable for world
building the efficient in air quotes ways of building a world do spread
around a little bit again like that tribal knowledge we do want to write
them up on the wiki given the current climate wiki editing is is less of a
priority for me right now but we do want to write that up on the wiki
particularly dispelling any myths about stuff which does not improve world
performance such as the video I did on asset the asset the duplication system
and how that is frequently bypassed almost accidentally dorky confirms that
as an Australian who has studied wildlife that they are still confused by
the platypus fantastic thank you for being confused by the panelists also get
confused by the pangolin which I believe is also like a rodent or maybe they're
a mammal I can't remember pangolins are interesting moving towards two
additional questions Ruscio says for the delay or delay with value node when used
with no input can you blame the default behavior it seems like it's performing
some kind of delay based on its ability to prevent some loops going red is it
equivalent to a single update delay you mean the delay one with time I mean I
guess you can just look at both let me take a look delay no this is a base
class interesting delay the dot evaluate cool start with that so start delay
gets a second it looks like it'll do whatever the default value for a float
is but by its nature if you know anything about C sharp you can just go
figure out right it does task dot delay and then whatever the default value for
a float is and so I believe if you do like the equivalent of a weight a weight
task delay zero you still bump execution out of the synchronous you bump it you
still bump it to an asynchronous location even though there is a zero
second delay so that might be the update cycle that you're saying basically it's
like diverting to the next update loop because you basically said hey break
here we're going into async land and then come back literally less than a
second exactly zero seconds after that so yeah even if it was zero you'd get
that basically one update cycle delay I would much rather you use the updates
delay for those who are aware the delay and delay with value nodes take a time
so that's good if you want sort of like cooldowns or a time sequence or
something like that the updates delay node will delay events by a number of
updates which is basically just sort of everything updating in the world that's
sometimes needed you'll frequently come across it with dynamic variables and
reparenting sort of creating dynamic variables dynamic variable spaces you'll
know when you need an update delay node eventually again I'd love to wrap some
guidelines on those but like sometimes I literally just throw them in there
because stuff isn't working like if you've ever like got logics and you're
like I really really think that this should work and it doesn't work and it's
like 5 a.m. and I haven't had any sleep and I need it to work try throwing in
some updating relays try floring in some to update delay nodes two is usually a
good number and see if it works and then slowly start removing those elements
until it you know stops working again and then you'll figure out where you
need those particular items all right I didn't realize that I needed to scroll
down so if I was just sitting there in silence just cuz I didn't realize I
needed to scroll down so give me a second once I catch up just make sure I
haven't delayed any questions here so Zetta says during performance penalty to
the initial load of an avatar for slot strict assets that are marked as
inactive are they loaded and left inactive yes that exactly actually comes
up good way of thinking about that one is the good old sort of like drummed in
via moderation thing about do not have appendages on your avatar right even if
the mesh loader the mesh is right even if the slot is disabled the mesh renderer
is disabled I'm still going to end up with an appendage on my computer in my
cache so don't put appendages on your avatars by default and you load cloud
avatars instead if you need your appendage load into the avatar that has
the appendage or spawn the appendage and attach it to yourself don't keep it
there same thing goes with Zetta's question there which is if you don't
need the object in this case it could be something more innocuous than an
appendage don't have it on the avatar good example being like guns right so I
see a lot of people will have like a holstered gun on their avatar which they
shoot I don't know like once a week you don't need that on your avatar or maybe
you need one that is inactive and doesn't have logic on it if it's part of
the character that you want part of it to be you know it's there then they're
just it's an inactive gun then you'd have less of a cost there because you
won't be loading the logics on the gun and then hey if you need the gun you can
support it in or update it or cloud spawn it or do all sorts of stuff like
that socks I don't respond well to dots you'll please need to enunciate and
elaborate on your your thought Lux asks what kind of world building tools that
don't exist ready do you think people who are more artistically orientated
appreciate to help their creative flow I haven't seen some people get hung up
making stuff because they don't want to bother with delving deep into inspectors
or the gizmos and kind of wonky doing architecturally precise things
architectural tools are certainly something that we need a really good
example being the builder tip by Gehepe which is one of the amazing Japanese
creators that we have that lets you snap together various tile sets to really
really quickly make buildings and objects a little known fact about the
builder tip is that you can make your own sets so let's say that you just got
an amazing I don't know let's say city pack on the sketch fab and you know it's
got snappable stuff like a park and then like a bank or whatever you could load
that into the builder tip like it doesn't have to be walls it doesn't have
to be doors it could be like road pieces for a racetrack it could be stairs it
could be you know it could be fruit that you want to like tessellate for some
reason like it could be hexagons that you want to tessellate on a floor like it
doesn't need to be the default pack you can just add stuff to it
additionally sort of architecturally speaking it's just sort of like more
tools that like feel good to use a good example which I use a lot right now but
not a lot of people realize exist is if you go to essential tools and you look
around there there's the meter tool tip the meter tool tip allows you to measure
stuff in the world and not a lot of people need to measure stuff I do because
I do a lot of science it's important to make things off to scale but once you
start using the meter tip you feel like it feels good right there's no
inspectors to it you're like I want to know how big this appendage is I can
measure it using the meter tip I don't need to get an inspector it was too good
not to carrying on peach says do mirrors have an option to not show other
mirrors reflections if so please do a video I don't believe that is a thing
right now that would be more of a gains question I do believe we have a github
issue open about it where there's talk of mirrors and stuff like that my advice
there is just don't show a mirror to another mirror which I know is like sort
of a cop-out but like it depends on your scenario there was that MMC entry forget
what it was called but it had lots of reflection based mechanics as a puzzle
game so sorry I forgot its name but they must have done some tricks there to
figure that out with that I don't believe we got any additional questions
I'm gonna go ahead and cool things here if you have any additional questions
please drop them in questions and help DM me or anything like that and I will
get back to you as soon as I can thank you for sitting here with me today to
talk about tools and I will see you again next week