Okay, well we are now going to get started. It is 4 p.m. so welcome to
office hours. This is office hours of me, Probable Prime. I'm a member of the NEOS team and I'm
gonna answer your questions. As a reminder, which I've been saying like every couple
of seconds before this, if you have questions please drop them in the office
hours chat that's two above the one that you're currently in the community
meetings chat and I'll get to them in the order that they appear and I'll answer them. Let's go ahead
and take a look. So we have a question from Light Lotus who says what is
happening with NEOS? Why has nothing been said about the state of leadership? It
has. If you check announcements you'll see the updated information there. If
there's any additional information we'll share it in announcements. You'll get
tidbits information randomly from from various members of the team when they
answer various questions but like no news doesn't mean nothing's happening it
just means that there's no news. There's like there's a difference there right so
we can't say nothing's happening and we can't say nothing's not happening we
just we can't tell you like anything until we can tell you stuff like so no
news means wait for more news. Thumbs up. Cool.
Moving on ones to Duff's question. Duff says with the huge influx of VLC players
migrating over to NEOS what the scene what are the what are some of the key
things we should be teaching new players that the team and all the community
members would like to emphasize on? I personally and I can't enforce this of
course because it's not on any guidelines it's not me speaking as an
official capacity is for you to be considerate. There's a lot of sort of you
know cool stuff that you can do inside Neos but being considerate is incredibly
important. I have a list of ways that you can be considerate on a personal page on
the Neos Wiki once again this is not like mandated this is not like do this
or you will die this is just my personal opinion about how you can be considerate.
There's also the social videos that exist in my social VR playlist which
I'll go ahead and link as well. As Shifty says in the comments consent is super
important there are other social issues which are very important consent being a
very very large one in that ground. So they would take a look at the social
videos there and the social videos we have Reading the Room which is about
basically when you join a Neo session it might be unclear what's happening in
that Neo session you just take like a couple of seconds you know figure out
what's happening what type of session is this what type of users are in this
session how best can my existence my energy influence this session. In some
cases the answer is not at all in which case you can just leave there's nothing
bad about that you're just like hey it's the wrong session happens all the time
in over in VRC right you join the 20th black cat of the day to see who's in the
black cat and you're just like well this group are over here listening to
terrible rap music in the corner in front of a mirror I don't think this is
the world for me and you go on to the next black cat that's you know exactly
the same thing happening over here on all Neos if the if the session isn't
suitable you just just move on VRC for me is like vibe hunting a little bit
different in Neos because there's you know so much more you can do but in VRC
I mostly vibe hunt I'm like I'm looking for a particular vibe usually just chill
and not terrible rap music yeah there's also the myths list actually I do want
to cover that one so misinformation is rampant and so if someone comes up to
you and they say something on the lines of I heard this or he said this or she
said that or I heard this or the dev said this no they're doing this etc do
check that miss list it's not exhaustive there are other ones there those are
just the myths that like they they ground my gears on that day that I wrote
that page at the wiki is a community project feel free to add more myths to
that page additionally I have a screenshot from our friends and I say
that because we should be working together as you know social metaverses I
have a screenshot of a message from the VR chat team which I just want to like
signal boost here in a way that I know out it's my office hours which is like
hey do what you can to combat misinformation as well like a lot of
sessions I was in I would say 20 to 30 percent there were some people in the
corners or sometimes just blatantly talking about it they're like oh yeah
like you know VR just stealing credit card information now and it's like well
what is the like what is the source of your information like oh you heard it
from a friend okay where did they hear it from Oh friend and you trace it all
the way back and it's just like they read an offhand comment somewhere that
doesn't make sense like if you go direct to the source you'll get more information
there so there we go moving forwards let's take a look at more questions
Jin says question is anyone team set up a hardware wallet part of the principle
of cryptocurrency is anonymity and I don't understand why this doesn't exist
anymore my crypto wallets are incredibly secret I'm not going to tell you what
they are where they are who they are how many I have what they have on them
that's not the goal of crypto right the goal of crypto is that there is a level
of anonymity to it sharing information about my wallets publicly is problematic
and I don't know why we've got to that point I don't know why we have those
domain names you can link to a wallet address and be like yo you can see all
my bank transactions you can see much cheese I'm buying right so I have a
counter question to that which is could you please provide a transaction history
of your entire bank account over the last millennia and I'll take a look at
that and find all the weird stuff that you've purchased moving on to their next
question T asks what are the plans going forwards in regards to influx of ERC
players we actually scaled quite well we got some comments actually from this
these groups as well so we have two volunteer groups within the the Neos
community and the largest sort of Neos team is an umbrella term called the
mentors and moderators moderators are responsible for guideline violations and
and just sort of keeping things in check and I want to say police because they
aren't police right they're not beat cops they're not gonna arrest you they
don't have tasers they don't have firearms they're there to just try and
make sure everyone's safe and if there's issues that come up they're there to try
and resolve them and then there's the mentors and there is a lot of overlap
between this the mentors are a volunteer group that are designed to help you out
with inside Neos now it is not correct to say that if you're not a mentor you
can't help anyone and everyone can help at any time I was in MTC sessions
yesterday helping out and I'm a team member I had one person and one person
only who direct messaged me and said should you be working on the actual
platform rather than helping out new users and I just said no I didn't want
to entertain that with any other answer right we had an influx of new users we
needed as many people as we could so I was helping out new users I think I'm
entitled to do that those groups were scaled a lot sort of earlier on in the
year we scaled them a lot we added a lot more to them and and like I said even
from some of those people inside those groups they're like only scaling too
much like don't we have too many mods or too many mentors based on yesterday no
we have quite frankly enough or in some cases not enough like it was it was very
very very busy so we scaled quite well for those and we'll probably continue
scaling if we see additional upticks such that they can grow and scale as the
as the platform grows and scales for information on the mentor program which
is I don't to say free to join because that makes it sound like it's some sort
of paid service but like it is you know it is anyone can join it anyone can
become a mentor and remember if you're not a mentor you can still help it's
just like hey if you want to go that extra mile and become a mentor then you
can go ahead and become a mentor there's information on mentors when I can spell
it correctly here and there's also information on the moderation team
moderation team is a little bit more difficult to join because it's a
different level of commitment that's there actually don't think we have
moderation applications open currently but there we go
additionally there's also this lovely page I wrote called how to help which
talks about the ways that you can help us do cool stuff so there you go there's
how to help I know there's lots of links today but that's because I have written
a lot of those pages or collaborate on those pages with the community and they
just have so much information you'll see a lot of repeated questions in the in
the discord and we're fine to answer repeated questions of course but hey if
you're if you're nervous about asking questions or you think it might be a
silly question it's not but also remember the information is on the the
wiki there as well and if there is information on the wiki that you think
is missing go ahead and edit it anyone can edit it anyone on the planet your
mother your father your grandfather your aunt your cousin your dog anyone who can
access a keyboard can edit the wiki no permission is required if you want to
edit the wiki and feel like contributing then there is a page called contributing
to the wiki which can also help like I said lots of links here it's linked down
all right let's go ahead and move onwards let's take a look okay so we got
that one whoever's reacting with cues can you also get thank you for adding
the the checkmarks are you but it's Lex today thank you so much I do want to
double check I know who's doing it every day so we got dust question we got the
hardware quality question and we got takes question onto hacks question access
so a good way of handling syncing to inventory or things loading into the
world and it's recently it's been a bit slower than usual with making things to
appear making it harder to help people put their avatars together there was
some server load issues yesterday because quite frankly we didn't know
that we were going to get a larger like a scale event we have now adjusted our
infrastructure to handle that scale event including the registration cap
which may seem annoying for questions about the registration cap do ask I
won't go into it unless there's an ask though because I could talk about it for
like 20 minutes and I don't want to waste that time so if you're interested
please go ahead and ask um so we are adjusting things to make that a little
bit better what I would say there is if you are helping people out consider
using a more performant avatar I don't want to say look like it's a mentor even
if you're not a mentor but I don't want to say as a helper you need a uniform
because you don't need to abide by guidelines of course but like maybe a
lighter avatar might help because then when you're joining the session to help
them you're then not em what's the word for like burdening that's the word
you're not burdening that session with your avatar you're you're just giving a
light thing for your presence your character and then everything else
spawned in is targeted for them then that will give like a little bit less
load on that session steam randomly just disconnected from the internet that's
fine and jump scared me on my computer and then other than that is just just
think about what you're spawning there are some items that can also be created
without using the inventory for example if you add like a developer tooltip
component to an empty object it should automatically create a cone it'll be old
red cone rather than the new sort of gold sparkly dev tip but it still works
same with the logic step it will create a blue cone for you so can also be like
an emergency thing we still noticing issues do please continue reporting them
we do like seeing those we can do more I mean can we do want to hear about that
if there's any problems all right let's move forwards to TPW use question hi
TPW I see that you're new to the discord so welcome to Neos as was TK actually so
welcome to the discord as well while Neos has great tools for developers one
thing that turns new people that aren't tech savvy is the complexity of the base
menu especially with the influx of VLC players is there any vision of
streamlining things where it remain pretty much the same it will be like
night and day eventually so what we want to do is initially we want to first of
all replace all the old UI with new UI easy way to explain that is actually
using dark mode and light mode anything that is in light mode right now and that
includes inspectors because those are light it needs to be like entirely
reworked in some cases from the ground up to be in our new UI system there's UI
which is the old UI system and then UI X which is the new UI system once that's
all reworked it will have an initial pass which will improve the UI the UX
design of those those units initially but it also allow us to continue
developing that UI further in response to feedback from you guys and ideas
suggestions enhancements added to that because of the way that we build our new
UI it is entirely customizable as an example here to kind of illustrate
what's going on the world browser which is in the new UI scheme there's more
work that we need to do on the UI on the world browser for sure but it is in the
new UI system that is entirely editable by you as an example of that there is a
facet I made which is a simplified world browser that just shows the worlds that
you're in allows you to close out of them it's probably the most popular
thing I've made in a long time another example and I don't know if I can
remember the name of the world there is I think that's called Nexus portal I
should actually visit that last night seemed crazy something like that it's a
world that I made where I took the world browser and I made it 3d again and so I
made each world that is in the world browser as an active session a like
doorway in this like grassy knoll floating in space and it used to be
quite easy to make that render because there wasn't that many sessions open but
it'll probably be a mess these days but again that's just me editing the world
browser added to that parts of the world browser actually generic so for example
the search bar there's nothing in that search bar that determines that it's
searching worlds the search bar just says this is what's in my search query
and the world browser then picks that up using sort of interrupt between those
segments and it means that they can sort of be dragged around a little bit what
I'm basically saying there about rambling on too much more is once the UI
is over to the system you build it yourself hey you want an inspector
that's bright pink you can build it yourself hey you want an inspector that
is in still in light mode even if we default to dark mode go for it you want
an inspector with different font go for it you want a bigger font size go for it
want a small font size go for it people already do this they create custom
inspectors and feel free to continue using those but once we have that new
system in place for inspectors it'll be a lot easier to do that and it'll be a
lot less prone to errors and issues so and a short summary everything's gonna
change like honestly it's gonna look like you put you know your ducks and
your whites together in the laundry machine and it's come out like a
completely new garment and you're just like cool yes I now have a grey t-shirt
instead of a white t-shirt moving forwards let's take a look at what is
next okay so neko gama has a not a question just something I'd like to
bring to attention since I'm since I'm since I mentioned the miss list neko was
recently asked by decent our friends if Neos is owned by Facebook due to the
term metaverse just want to give a quick heads up I don't like this and there's
nothing I can really do about it asking whether Neos is owned by Facebook is
kind of the same as asking if any book that you own in your library of books on
your bookshelf is owned by Facebook because it's got the word book in it and
I understand the confusion and I wish that Manta hadn't chosen that particular
name but that's just the way that we were in the world that we live in Neos
is not owned by Facebook if it was we would have to declare it and if we
declared it it would be on the bottom of our website and it would probably be a
part of the UI and hey maybe you'd need a Facebook account to log into Neos so
we are not very easy to prove that I will add it to the miss list I would
also encourage those that have that kind of thought process to look beyond words
and and finding associations for that so the the word meta that's in metaverse
just means like different or adjunct to the normal thing so there's a good
example there being meta data so metadata is data about the data so a
good example of metadata is a picture that you saved to your computer the
picture which might be of your favorite cheese collection is a picture that's
the data there's computer you know code or binary on that computer which is
describing what that cheese collection looks like but then there's meta data
which is when you took the picture what like focus and zoom that camera was and
etc and that metadata also isn't owned by Facebook it's meta data additionally
there is a company called meta threads who I'm vaguely aware of because I used
to be in the streaming area as a job and they had really good outfits and
clothing they're probably angry right now and there was another company that I
believe currently is suing meta because the use of the name but I don't want to
comment on that because it's not like a good place to sort of comment on the
affairs of other companies scrolling down to another question Alexios says
and UI streamlining is desperately needed but you know the situation after
us is there any team members working developed at all or is everyone in the
protest thing it is difficult to use the word protest I've heard some people use
the word strike it isn't either of those we have stopped working because of
negotiations currently it is not a strike it is not a protest if it was a
strike or a protest I wouldn't be here speaking to you if you strike from let's
say a factory job you don't go to the factory if you strike from a programming
job you don't program and you don't attend the job we have everyone in here
like I saw shifty typing shifty has some messages I saw Canadian get typing
there's probably got messages from them on the scroll list but I keep the scroll
to the questions I'm answering so yeah we're still working but we're working in
other areas depends what you what you mean there is still stuff happening it's
just we're not releasing updates currently moving forwards to the next
question that's exactly the same question from index there yeah news is
still being developed we're still working we're just not releasing updates
Jin has updated the question hardware alerts which says I only want to know if
the news team takes seriously security seriously with hardware wallet questions
most crypto teams devs marketplace recommended hardware to users to protect
themselves based on a confidence of any on the team took it serious and an
advocate of such I am an advocate of hardware is and if you ask me what I
recommend you store your cryptocurrency on I would say a hardware wallet what
that's a different question though that's hey prime what would you
recommend to increase the security of your Neos account and I would say hey go
ahead turn on 2fa make sure you have a password not using on any other site and
when you create and turn on 2fa make sure you save those backup codes a part
of turning on the 2fa process will ask you to save the backup codes and I know
some people don't if you don't save your backup codes and you lose your 2fa
device you kind of screwed so when a computer tells you to save backup codes
and this is any platform of 2fa if they present backup codes to you you save
them so yeah I we are security serious like we have a security policy for
reports and security etc we take it very secure it's very securely we take
security very seriously was I was trying to say and we have a lot of looking
insight and information that we're looking at as security grows what that
doesn't mean is that I need to talk to you about my personal life or my
personal crypto wallets that is a bad measure if my front door has no lock on
it it doesn't mean that my code is insecure it just means that I'm
replacing my front door actually have a friend who's replacing their front door
it blew open in the wind and got wrecked and they bought the wrong size door so
they had to return it I'm like I didn't think that was like a thing that could
happen but it was a thing most the wrong size handle I can't remember anyway they
had to replace their door and it was a big sort of spectacle because you know
you need to get a door the right size moving onwards um it has an update on
moderation team which has applications on an as no-kneader basis fantastic get
also mentions that needing new mods would be identified like different
languages different locale stuff like that that would be good to see if you
haven't seen it already if you looked at the Twitter hashtag we have a large and
I mean quite large representation in the Japanese area Japanese locale Japanese
language they are fantastic they do some of the amazing things take a look at the
MMC 2021 2022 2019 it should just look at all the MMCs for crazy creations
from that community the same goes for Korean as well we have a lot of Korean
users that are amazing I have since some sort of rumblings of Spanish which is
cool so we've been looking into like that I know that we have a Spanish badge
we sometimes give out to people or actually don't know anyone that's with
I've not seen it um but yeah if you are in a growing area of language or locale
that you think that we might need we'll take a look and have a look at it
we haven't seen it as well we have built by the Japanese community actually we
have some translation devices where you can basically just like stick them to
your head and then when you speak the translator text in whatever language you
want will appear above your head and it's beautiful moving forwards to other
questions which is maybe we have another one from neko thank you for that I did
want to ask one thing I noticed is a bit of performance for high use accounts by
hardware not being even halfway utilized is this more of a network ish or
something bigger the force in the US is a very complicated beast I'll call it a
beast because it's one that the nearest team are going to tackle with multiple
tools and implements there are a lot of things that we just haven't done when it
comes to optimization and we plan to do one of those being we want to optimize
the IK a little bit and then another one being hey want to optimize entirely the
renderer by replacing it which will get us some optimizations we also want to
optimize the language that Neos is written in and by that I mean we want to
change the version of dotnet we're using which gives us again performance
improvements just simply because hey we're compiling to a different target so
there's a lots of things that we need to do there it is something that we know is
a is a miss on our part is that we can't have worlds with as bigger numbers as
other platforms but do know that we are taking a look at it if you want to know
what you can do to kind of mitigate that the the biggest thing you can do is get
out of an avatar that has full IK we call them head and hands avatar
sometimes they're called flatties I don't particularly like that one because
my head and hands avatar isn't flat but if you remember the default avatar that
you had when you came into Neos when you were creating your account before you
set up your avatar it just had hands and that floating headset you can create as
like those using basically anything if you import a bench a park bench into the
game you can go to avatar creator slap the headset the head part of the avatar
create on that concrete bench hit create avatar and you'll have a head and hands
avatar that looks like a bench with hands those are more performant I don't
want to tell you to do that all the time or say like you must do that because
again you lose the character there you lose the full body tracking you lose the
legs you know you lose the chest so it's it's up to you and then in addition to
that is to make sure that you're watching whatever you're spawning in good
often examples there being video players trying to keep video players low I've
noticed a couple of people will do the sort of thing where they like they'll
spawn in videos and just kind of like cue them up like a deck of cards each
video player is causing like quite a lot of performance problems so like just
try and keep that down that isn't a big contributor to performance but when you
got like you know a deck of cards of ten waiting videos to play yeah lots of
other things there you have a specific questions about what you need to
optimize do let me know so moving onwards Sven oh second it's not Sven
second I've been pronouncing that one right so second asked her to confirm on
blend shapes if they are zero are they still a performance problem is only when
they have a value if they're on zero they have a performance problem if they
exist they have a performance problem the performance problem occurs because
we need to load data into various parts of Neos that determine what will happen
if that blend shape changes so a good example here and it's a really silly one
I wish I you know but it's a really good example is there are a lot of avatar
bases which have a I mean I'm gonna like generalize here a little bit apologize
for that they kind of have a male female slider it might be boobs it might be
butts right but you can change the presentation of the avatar to be male
presenting or female presenting if you have made the decision about what you
want that character the avatar to be that blend shape needs to not exist and
you can do that by baking your blend shapes I'll go ahead and link that
tutorial in the in the chat here what that does is it takes the current
position of all those vertices with that blend shape applied and then applies it
to the the base blend shape or the basis if you've made a blend of terminology
and then it deletes that blend shapes would no longer needs to exist and what
that does is it signals to the to the engine to Neos hey I'm not going to
change wherever or not I have breasts anymore in this avatar I have locked
that choice in and again I'm not saying that that needs to be permanent if you
save two copies of the avatar one that has those blend shapes baked and one
that doesn't then the one that has those blend shapes baked is more performant
and if you ever want to change those slides again you can load the unperformant
one and then make those changes I'm searching YouTube for Baker blend shapes
and I got some very weird results I need to go to my youtube channel and search it
there like how to bake a cake no bake your blend shapes not a cake here we are
moving moving forwards to an additional question where I scroll the scroll the
scroll the scroll the scroll toy says a bit of an off-topic question any cool
hardware it's popping up that's got your attention lately I'm still a streamer at
heart I used to stream a lot I don't anymore but I am like really wise to the
streaming hardware area the coolest piece of hardware in that area that I
bought recently not recently it was actually like almost a year ago now but
I still love it every day the reason it comes to mind is because the place I
bought it from was like a local store because they had it in stock and Amazon
didn't and that store like still every like six months sends me a little letter
with their catalog attached and just says like thanks for being a customer
here's our catalog in case you need anything else and it's just like it is
like slightly annoying but also kind of cute as a company doing that but anyway
so yeah it's the go XLR mini it's what I'm actually talking to you on I like
it is every day I don't use it to its full advantage but like it solved a very
big issue I had with microphones so that was cool as for new hardware more in the
realms of the like VR space I'm a backer a backer I'm a pre-order of the
ettie controllers and I'm really interested in trying them because I I
think I might like the feel I don't know if I'll actually like them but I
pre-ordered them so I'm kind of like biased to be like I want to try them
just in case I've let you know waste my investment here unfortunately the ettie
controllers have had a couple of production delays they are very
understandable it is very difficult to get a new product to market when you
need to build circuit boards and also like the actual plastic that goes around
that so I am patient with them and I'm excited to see what they can do with
them we do have limited support for an earlier version of the ettie controllers
they will probably need to be additional work when they're the ettie controllers
in their final state arrives but I will be quite motivated to do that seeing as
I'll have them lying in my apartment let's move along why the Duff says why
do people from VRC keep asking if they need to buy dinner bones for Neos this
is an unfortunate naming problem that we have so when it comes to Neos we have
dynamic bones that are very very very similar to VR chats fizz bones and VR
chats dynamic bones which actually aren't owned by VR chat long story but
you know like we have very similar things but they are completely different
so if you want to draw a Venn diagram there is like no overlap in terms of
code like VR chat fizz bones completely different from dynamic bones the asset
library thing and then our dynamic bones completely separate from both of those
other two the problem there that then happens is because dynamic bones are
called dynamic bones in Neos they think that they are the same thing and that's
quite perfect like it's it's a perfect mistake and a confusion to have and
that's why they ask if they need to buy it if you are a member of our community
please get a banner get on a horse and charge into the sunset with a giant
banner dynamic bones on Neos are free the reason why they're named dynamic
bones or close to that language is because of the opposite of that we
didn't want to name them something really obscure because then people would
have the opposite problem they wouldn't feel that they're familiar they wouldn't
know how to talk about them etc that's also the case with the case with fizz
bones right whenever I think about fizz bones which is what PRC uses now I'll
find myself calling them dynamic bones just because it's in my vocabulary even
though they're completely different you need to call things what they are and
that association has power and so therefore calling them dynamic bones has
power I added them to a couple of avatars yesterday and I said like
there's lots of controls here you know you can do what you want they are quite
similar but they are different and the user is helping took a look at the
inspector panel for the dynamic bones and when I could work with this it looks
quite similar and they just were off and playing with the dynamic bones and that
was perfect and yes just clarifying that dynamic bones was a paid add-on for the
ERC made by someone who doesn't have any investment they're not employed or
anything at VR excuse me at VRC they just need they're just it was just an
add-on you could buy I know a lot of people didn't buy it and that makes me
sad but I do wish I could buy I don't know interview the original creator and
be like did you know that this add-on was gonna be used for it was being used
for because I don't think they did like they made it a long time ago moving on
with lots of questions here we will run over if there's still questions go and
it is a busy day because of the new influx so don't worry about that we'll
just we'll just keep keep on keeping on if I get to the bottom of the list and
we're starting to run a bit dry I'll let you know so on to egg roll force that's
a crazy username that sounds like I don't know if you know the video game
series EDF earth defense force it sounds like you'll be right at home playing
that one so egg roll force ask is there a best practices for hosting instances
specifically for running more sandboxing instances on a headless yes first thing
I would say there is have rules so we do have guidelines you'll see get like
basically banging a drum about guidelines I do as well those are the
guidelines which are platform global right we don't care what type of session
you're in you need to be following those guidelines when it comes to hosting your
own sessions you can add rules to that so it would be perfectly acceptable for
you to run a headless which had a rule which said no yellow things and then
fruits wouldn't be able to join perfectly acceptable weird but perfectly
acceptable so do come up with list of rules for your session if you want
recommended rules like I said keep the video players down don't build on spawn
I hate it when people build on spawn move away from spawn to build people
don't want to spawn into your creations and then other rules like that you can
see some example rules in the MTC we recently added them because we needed to
like add some couple more rules to the MTC we'll just join a couple of
headlaces to do that I might write up an article on like some other rules I would
generally have it's just a little bit like wordy to go into as for a sandbox
the incidents do know that it's gonna crash a lot if it's on a headless it's
gonna crash a lot you're gonna need to probably like make sure it's got like an
auto-restart or something like that if it's sandbox see as in people can do
whatever they want it will just accidentally crash that won't happen if
like only certain people can build only friends can or a limited audience but
anyone can build the chances of crashing is like it's gonna be higher as for
hosting instances personally if you are a host in the world rather than on a
headless your unfortunate job is to sort of be a gatekeeper of that session if
you notice problems particularly problems involving the guidelines please
enact self-moderation that's where you can sort of kick or ban someone from a
session report stuff that happens we love tickets we're not gonna like
penalize you for making a ticket that isn't good or isn't spelt right or
anything like that if something happens let us know we'll take a look at it but
do remember that like you have a little bit of responsibility as the session
host to kind of keep keep things to how you'd want them to happen imagine that
the session is your house and the people are coming around to visit if someone
comes around to visit and they spread dirt all around the floor or horse me
that was the meaning for the previous one they spread horsemen you're all
around your apartment you've kicked them out the apartment so do the same for
your session please if they come in with a loud obnoxious firearm again you'd
probably call the police and get them arrested so maybe do that in your
session unless it's like a I don't know gun range session in which case hey
fine so next question from is it a set so is it a thesis I'm kind of our shy
for asking questions in a large group being a new players and I think that'll
make my experience best when I finally get into Neos actually um I have a great
example of that which is about attitude so I've seen great attitude from the
people I've recently been helping but in the past I have had a couple of problems
with a little bit of attitude so when I say attitude I don't mean the way that
like a school teacher would tell you like oh you need to have the right
attitude to learn I just mean the right mental model to go into Neos right so
when you go into Neos as a VR chat player or as any other platform player
coming across you're going to sort of try and make a lot of comparisons you're
gonna try and be like well it's like this over on VR see it's like this or
Neos what I want you to do is is try and sort of see beyond that and have
patience and understand that we have a little bit of dust going on right now
you know if I could wear a hard hat I'd probably be wearing a hard hat right so
some stuff is confusing some stuff is unclear some stuff is more complicated
we've got people all around that are gonna help you out look for the the
green icon above anyone's head if you're in an MTC session that they'll probably
be there and then above all else is just like ask questions if you got them like
I will answer the same questions all day if I need to like if it helps you go
through it if you're shy and you don't want to speak using your microphone we
have a number of tools available inside the Neos Essentials folder called the
Mute Helper that lets you type text-based messages which will appear in
a speech bubble next to your head and that's a great sort of advantage to many
many people who are for whatever reason and there's no judgment here don't feel
comfortable talking that's absolutely fine you know was fantastic for that
also remember that everyone had to learn at one point I'm just rambling here if
you like the rambling cool if you don't let me know my first session in Neos I
was in an avatar tool world by a user called business lawyer Nexlin came in
and there was a cart like a sort of metal cart in this world he he'd
selected with the inspector and scaled it I'm just like whoa and I spent the
next like week or so just completely confused I had no idea how anything
worked and so everyone had to learn even me that was like two three years ago but
I everyone has to learn Duff has a statement as well which is be kind ask
questions and know that you're generally in a helpful community yep it's good
advice as well I'll also take a look at the guidelines I hate you know banging a
drum about them but like the guidelines do have some important information
they're good for you as a person just to know what's unacceptable to do but it's
also good for you to know what we value right the guidelines show what Neos
values in a community so we value people being nice to each other because it's on
that guidelines to not be not nice and do again make tickets if you see
problems we love tickets tickets are a great source of substance for us moving
forwards Nash has a question which is how easy would it be in port my avatar
do I just drop in to adapt do I just drag and drop the FBX I've ever done it
before in a lot of cases you are like a little bit ahead of the game because
what we start with usually with with with VRC players or platform players is
they don't know where their FBX is that's perfectly fine if you know where
your FBX is you're already at like step two so you're already having an easier
time then then someone who doesn't know where their FBX is drag and drop your
FBX into the game you've got to click a few buttons it is a little bit of an
evolved process someone can show you it or there are tutorials available which
I'm sure people can sort of point and take a look at gray has linked one for
example just underneath the question and it will import things that might not
work when you import things are things like textures materials and in some
cases as well rigging there are subtle differences between the way that unity
is able to rig a humanoid and Neos is able to rig a humanoid but depending on
which avatar you're using it's absolutely fine I'm gonna take a look at
your profile picture here and assume that she'll be out your avatar if it's
so probably be fine I think I recognize that one from being imported do just
take it slow ask questions and you'll be there it is not impossible people
import all sorts of stuff Corey asks will there ever be will there eventually
be a wiki page and the recommended avatar optimizations yes it's on my list
to write I just don't wanna get it wrong so I am like writing it and editing it
and writing it and editing it and then waiting to send it to fruits or or gains
so gains is our graphics program ideals of all the rendering and fruits just
knows everything about Neos because they wrote a lot of it I want to say like
most of it but these days like it's a little bit untrue because like hey I
write code gains rights code you know it's it's cool they know like a lot
fruits knowledge is insane you just be like this component you wrote three
years ago and they're like oh yeah that one it does this let's move on Corey has
an interesting statement which says it's tedious to import an avatar I agree that
the first few avatars that you import are going to be tedious and that's a bit
that I was talking about with that attitude if you come up with an attitude
of this is tedious I am bored I'm I'm fed up then you won't get it done but
becoming an attitude like hey this is gonna be a bit tedious this might be a
little bit confusing and you get it done they're like four fifth sixth avatar you
import it'll be much easier the first couple they are gonna be a little bit
tedious let's move on does this can we empathize that you can use f8 to swap
between VR and desktop mode assuming you stop yeah I told that to a user
yesterday and they were like mind blown it was crazy to just elaborate that on a
little bit if you start in VR mode that start the game in VR mode right you know
if you use base stations they start wearing your headset turns on you can
just focus the window on your desktop like with your headset off push f8 and
you'll be in desktop mode push f8 again you'll be back in desktop no VR
whichever way around it was that I was talking there is no need to restart if
you start in desktop mode you cannot switch to VR mode you have to start in
VR mode to do that switch myself and many others of the community we always
start in VR mode and there are some days where I started VR mode instantly f8 to
desktop mode and then never f8 back my headsets just like lying there on its
like usual resting spot on my desk and it's just like play with me and I'm
like not today it's like but I'm on like not today I'm f8 let's move along
Lupo says is there any word or timeline for the solve of the issues from anyone
the reason we're not pushing updates it will talk about it in announcements when
we talk about it I said it earlier but like if there is no announcement in
announcements don't assume nothing's happening just assume we can't talk
about it yet and says you've got a lot of people listening to you rabbi about
so these stuff today else took about your door earlier that you're replacing
moving forwards Jin asks is Nia is looking alternative rendering engines
such as web 3js or Godot we are looking into other engines not 3js and not Godot
we were looking into they're all called silly names so I've forgotten them all
all right now we're sort of working on our own rendering engine as a separate
project it's called sauce not sauce the half-life 2 on the sources in like
tomatoes sauce I honestly don't know a lot about it and that's because my
strengths don't allow in the rendering side of things that's more kind of like
easy question to go over gains did used to do office hours they're just sort of
on hold right now but it will not be Godot or 3js or unreal that's like
another common question yet we will not be unreal before it says can we hit
hundred people in primetime I don't know if you can make it happen go for it I'm
too busy scrolling down asking questions I'm looking at my scroll bar it's just
continually going oh let's keep going fuzzy says last I need for Japanese
makers they make amazing things but usually very optimized I've seen some
advancements in that the the biggest part about the the Japanese community
that I like is how fast they are I have no idea how they do it and how fast they
do it they're also incredibly well organized so when they start our project
it just sort of like happens and it's insane and I love that about them and so
there's any optimization issues I'm sure they're working on them Quincy I think I
saw you in nears if I'm remembering that name hello again a translation device
would love to find that where can I get one essential tools essential tools JP
tools and then in there is the translator I don't know which row it's
on or anything like that but you're looking for a red and white rectangle I
know that's not useful and I apologize on behalf of nears that we don't have
search yet but it is in there I do have a version I'm working on that's sort of
working but mine is just an edit and I do have a video about that on my channel
but I do always want to point to the original source as well because they
deserve all the credit they figured it out I just have tweaked it a little bit
to make it easier for my purposes shifty states IK is incredibly optimized more
particularly as minimizing cost of slot transforms in the data model I thought
there was something we want to do out okay I might be out of date yeah anyway
the point there being an optimization is there is stuff that you can do which
will make a wiki page for and there is stuff that the nears team can do which
we need we know that we need to work on so that has another question fantastic
which says Disney is having hard limits in terms of avatars of worlds not that I
can think of there's nothing stopping you from importing a like million
polygon avatar but it will lag people out and they'll hate you for it there's
also nothing stopping you from doing that on the world level and again it
will lag people out and they'll they'll hate it and they won't go there but
there's no real limits the only limit I can really think of is what beyond like
hey your computer might crash is the file space limit that you have all
accounts start with a default storage space of one gigabyte beyond that you
will need to subscribe to our patreon to get more space and that will enable you
to save more I have currently have about 25 gigabytes of space based on my
account status and I'm using like 5% of that and I've been playing for three
years but I don't save everything I I don't know like recently like like half
a year ago or something I just stopped saving stuff that I like I don't I need
like it's cool but I don't need to save it I just remember where it is and then I go
there and spawn it out again or go find it if I need it that way I keep my file
space down and I have really really dense polygon meshes all sorts of stuff
I have a really really high high density chicken nugget which has an amazing
story about it
speedy baby another crate username here I like these these strange strange like
usernames ever ring to them they're good they ask what accessibility things are
in the game so it depends what type of accessibility you're talking about I'm
happy to go into specifics if you have a particular thing in mind that you're
you're concerned about ones that come to mind are the mute help which I mentioned
before that's for users who for whatever reason again no judgment from me don't
wish to speak they can use the mute helper to have that speech bubble appear
next to the messages that they type there are various versions of the
help there's even one that's sort of hooked up to text-to-speech so that the
message that you type will then be read in game using a text-to-speech voice and
text-to-speech is getting a great right now I know text-to-speech has a sort of
reputation in the older days of computing as being very robotic but I've
seen some text-to-speech on those avatars which is quite human beyond that
if you are colorblind I'm partially colorblind we do have a way to correct
for that it is a little bit experimental but there are filters that you can put
on your head that's sort of like a material you put on your head and they
can adjust the color spectrum of a world such that it might be a little bit
better you know we can make blues more blues or less blue whatever whatever you
need there if you are light sensitive I know that a couple of people like
sensitive we can also do the same thing as that colorblind filter but with a
darkening filter right it'll just take some of the intensity of the bright
lights out of the world I have some glasses in my inventory which I very
rarely equipped these days and I don't really know why I used to equip them all
the time in the early days moving beyond color if you are low vision there is the
ability to just arbitrarily create cameras in the world and I've seen a lot
of people who will I don't know where they are if anyone in chat is here and
there is where they are they've got sort of devices they parent to their avatar
that let them kind of zoom in on things a little bit like or similar to Windows
magnifier so I like seeing those we also have on that note we have disability
awareness badges which you can add to your account if someone below can link
the badges with the article we have a badge that says that you're colorblind
we have a badge that says that you are have vision issues we also have a badge
that says that you are deaf when it comes to the deaf community there we
have a lot of techniques and abilities that you can do in there we also have a
prominent few people that are in that community and are fantastic Danny comes
to mind Danny is fantastic they make just crazy stuff with the finger
tracking that we have and the leap motion support that we have we see a lot
of people that are able to sign a lot better inside Neos because they can just
sort of you know move their hands around we also have a couple of sort of hands
that are set up such that you can manually trigger letter fingerspelling
signs in a sort of intuitive way we also have native subtitle support for videos
although I don't know how it works is on my list to make a tutorial about but I
was reading code earlier and I'm like oh yeah you can import subtitle files I
forgot how but you can and those can be hooked up beyond that though because I
could wear on for forever literally if there is a problem you might be able to
build something to fix that problem and people will love to help you like if you
go into a world and you say I am for whatever reason I am unable to
comprehend the existence of yellow like someone will quickly build you something
you can put on your head and it just removes yellow somehow so much he handed
me there yesterday when I was playing they handed me some glasses that gave
you the vision of a dog right so they remove the colors that dogs cannot see
and so if I looked at green grass for example it was actually yellow my color
blindness means that I can often not tell the difference between green and
yellow anyway so I was very confused I'm like this isn't any different and they're
like are you a dog no I'm not a dog I just can't tell the difference between
green and yellow sometimes moving forwards
Zillowsef has another question here which says what is the most difficult
thing that new players will have to deal with people have commented with emojis
to get logics and I would kind of agree but I would actually say is getting the
avatar imported the thing that like is is difficult about particularly people
that come from another platform that doesn't have the in editing ability is
you want to just get comfortable and I used to not understand this but after
like a month or two of playing VR I got it right people want to feel
comfortable in the avatar that they're wearing getting to that stage where
you're comfortable is going to be the most difficult part that's why you've
got an avatar that you're comfortable in it's moving correctly it looks
correct it's got your colors your textures on it and when you look in the
mirror you're like that's me once that's done that's probably the most difficult
hurdle and then beyond that it's up to you about what you want to do again like
I see people have said logics if you don't want to learn logics that's
totally fine you don't have to if you don't want to learn any of the engine
that's totally fine just get the avatar in ask for help and and you'll get it in
and then you can just socialize right so it just depends on which path or journey
that you want to go through on Neos. Slinkah says ET controller the one with
the driver already Neos yes the driver in Neos for ET controllers is like
really old it's from before they had six doff now they have a six doff version
which is the right image on the thumbnail from the link that Alex posted
it's got like a chunkier bit attached to it which is basically like a five
tracker but a neti version of that that's six doff six degrees of freedom
that means and that might mean there's an updated driver and if there's an
updated driver would have to edit that. Aaron says does Neos currently spot any
haptic gloves I believe we support the B haptics gloves those just give you
vibration feedback on the gloves they don't give you the haptics that I
believe you're talking about which is where you can like feel stuff in VR
speaking of feeling stuff does anyone remember the Novant Falcon if you
remember the Novant Falcon let me know there's any Novant Falcon remember is
let me know you don't know what it is you can go ahead and take a look at it
moving onwards Traderos hope I'm pronouncing that correctly another
interesting name is there currently any estimate of time frames when the key
updates would be applied or would there be some way to see updates on current
systems in the works although I generally do not like products and
services to be crushed the current state of the market is very competitive and
falling behind becomes problematic we are very aware of that there are lots of
things in progress here the announcements channel I don't want to
sort of dwell on that too much that our existing that are preventing us from
doing updates beyond that though I would encourage you to go look at our roadmap
on github if someone wants to drop the roadmap link in the in the chat that
would be great that shows you what we are working on or at least intending to
work on and also gives you our backlog which is large but it shows you that
we're thinking about stuff we want to feed back in each of those items as well
if there is a job issue that you found that you have and it's something to say
about comment on us let us know let us know how you feel let us know what you
want to see in that future double stick says it's called dynamic bone no s by
will Hong that's the original thing yeah yeah I'd like to meet will Hong make you
say like hey how much like did you buy a house with about money you may I don't
know like yeah we have some love for EDF fantastic EDF is earth defense force is
a very crazy game and if you have a chance to play it please go ahead and do
and just like roll into the hilarity EDF is amazing egg roll face says I they
might have worded that probably because I was playing a hosting an instance I
would have to scroll up and find that question if you have a further up
question about hosting an instance do let me know spec says can you explain
for news is how to stop an avatar for face tracking so long as the blend ships
already exist yes when you create an avatar there's a bunch of check boxes on
the right hand on the like middle of the avatar credit just check them all I know
some of them are off by default I don't really know why just check them all
they're all useful one of them will automatically set up face tracking that
works at the HTC Vive face tracker I have one of those stuck to my face on my
headset and it makes me sometimes look really weird because my eyebrows do
wiggles but like that's fine for the face tracker itself it is based on the
blend shape definitions which we got from HTC in the tutorials channel of
this discord pinned is an image by gabell who made the sort of pivotal
example face tracking avatar which has all of those blend shapes set up you
don't have to name them exactly like that image if you have blend shapes that
are close enough then you could hook them up to the facial tracker I have a
video on that on my channel if someone could go ahead and make that that'd be
great as an example here many avatars have a smile blend shape and it's named
whatever it's named sometimes it's even named in Japanese you can hook that up
to the smile face tracker preset and it'll work even if it's not named
correctly and just that just having a smile adds so much more like emotion to
an avatar that you're wearing okay we're still my scroll bar is still huge let's
keep going I will answer all questions I know it's a little bit of a crazy day so
I'll just keep going till we run out of questions no user found welcome to the
discord I see you a new from the plant icon like meant to be like a flower I
don't know it's a plant icon who asked how is the crypto stuff incorporated the
game and are certain avatars what locked behind NFTs or crypto nothing is locked
behind NFTs or crypto at all there might be some community products which you
have to buy using crypto but that's nothing to do with us that's the same
thing as buying an avatar off gumroad and then importing into nius we have no
worlds locked behind crypto or NFTs if you're asking about crypto being
integrated in the game the steam build has no crypto and functionality the non
steam build does in the non steam build you can deposit our currency and CR into
your in-game wallet and withdraw it you can send it to people and you can buy
storage with it that's it yeah moving on good questions today mr. Aaron Aaron's a
good friend of mine he says what are your opinions on the recent influx of
people and how it affect non-time news I am a bit puzzled about what might happen
long term for anyone here that's new I love having you here as just the rest of
our community we love helping you I just I don't know what's gonna happen in the
future like well VRC reverse their decision to add EAC if VRC does that how
many of you will stay I don't know and that's the bit like I'm unsure about I
would love it if all of you stay I understand the that might not be
realistic so if you choose not to stay that's totally fine thank you so much
for trying us and hope to see you back time some there sometime soon I'm
running out of English at the moment as to what I think about it is great it's
also unexpected I wish we'd had some notice it's a bit difficult for VRC to
basically be like yo we're dropping a big update you might get some users
because they're gonna hate it like that they wouldn't do that that's not like a
business thing that exists but it is unexpected like I had other plans for
this week but I guess they're kind of like thrown out let's go ahead and move
on see if any more questions is it there says I so I'm thinking this is the
official VRC killer no I disagree um the important thing to think about and we
encourage you to do this based on the guidelines channel of this discord is to
think about how think about the the metaverse platforms is like a family
right we should be getting along we should be talking to each other we
should be sharing insights I myself am friends with the head of trust and
safety at VR chat and I sent them some kind words yesterday I didn't like say
hey this is a bad decision or anything like that I just said hey good luck I
basically I read the update and I just said hey good luck you know let me know
if you need anything because like I know that they probably had a really really
tiresome day yesterday and that's the kind of dialogue that I want between
those platforms so it's I don't think it's appropriate to say one is better
than the other I think it's appropriate to say that they are different and that
they have different uses you'll see that sentiment a lot from people you also see
the opposite sentiment which is like no this is better than VRC no VRC is better
than this and like it's not my place to comment on that because I don't think we
should be coming on it a good way to think about it is how you think about
beverages food and stuff like that like the Pepsi Coca-Cola thing right you guys
have a preference we don't need to talk about it we'll start an argument but you
have a preference that's in your mind right now Pepsi or Coca-Cola but if
they're sold out of Pepsi or Coca-Cola in the grocery store you're gonna buy
the other one and you're gonna enjoy it so it's a matter of preference rather
than like a clear-cut distinction between the two platforms let's move on
llama with two L's hope I'm pronouncing that correctly welcome to the discord
is there any plan to add a reset password button to the web UI the
person's a little confusing you should converge the login to the website you
can't reset your password about being in game and I find a little clunky yes we
have like three websites it's problematic but we're doing our best
we're you know like I said we're working on stuff so we have the the main website
and that has all the information about it and then we have like the account
website and then we have a third account website which is what we're trying to
move everything over to I believe that actually has a reset part of
functionality on it it's just not like it doesn't really do anything other than
account right it's stuff so that might be an option to do that but we
absolutely have plans to sort of put that all together like a jigsaw puzzle
until it makes sense in the future Nash has updated their profile picture so I
can see their avatar a little better yeah that looks like it will work quite
well great let's move along egg roll fails again hope if you're fighting for
the EDF quite well anyway also is there someplace where there's a complete list
of desktop controls it seems the only one I can find is outdated wiki has it
the wiki shouldn't be out of date if it's out of date yell at me I'll update
it basic controls is the page on the Wikipedia on the not the Wikipedia the
Neos wiki moving forwards Aaron says what are some suggestions for getting VRC
users who may be on the fence or simply just trend follows to stay on these I
think we can do that based on the way that we handle the experience right so
if you come over to us to try us out thank you so much for trying us and if
you like it stay do make sure you give it a good try do make sure you come in
with attitude of like hey this might be a little bit difficult there are some
rough edges give it a try let us know what you think and if you don't decide
to stay that's fine thank you for trying moving on we've got delirious Jax's one
minute avatar I love that so delirious Jax's woman avatar is meant to be
slightly satirical and the reason why that is he has a perfect avatar set up
the textures import the IK is fine so you can just import that model and do
that and the reason why he's able to do that is because he knows what Neos needs
and he's able to craft an FBX file that works perfectly a lot of users this
might be the first time that you've even looked at the files inside your avatar
you might have been doing solely with like download drops of unity packages
from avatar creators and that's totally fine like if you are a knowledgeable
user like Jax there should be able to just make an FBX that works I had that
actually yesterday with null user they brought the avatar in and the like rig
was just messed up and I explained what was wrong and I apologize that you know
there was no way to fix it in game and they went oh it's okay I can fix in
blender they took off their headset crumpled into a heap on the floor came
back five minutes later with a working file and it was beautiful I'm like my
job is done baby they understood my statement and they did it
Zillow says says what is the history of Neos had it will start I'm gonna bridge
this some people might have some links if you've got some links to better
histories of that but I'm gonna bridge it because I don't want to go on too
long Fruxius is an original backer of the original oculus rift and when they
got the oculus rift they went to a lot of like meetups like you know hacker
meetups stuff like that jams stuff like that and they created a bunch of cool
stuff and they noticed that they were doing the same thing over and over again
when you start a new VR project what's the first thing you do you make hands
the hands work and then maybe once you've got hands you do grabbing like
think about all the VR games you have they all have hands and grabbing and you
might have to grab a gun or a ball or an object and he was getting tired of
repeatedly doing that he's like I've just started a new project I've got a
copy this code from the other project that sets up hands into this new project
that sets up hands and so originally he was like what if I made the project
project which was Neos and it's like cool now I can make my other projects in
Neos and then it was like well now I can have multiplayer and this collaboration
and people could join and talk to me and it's like well now we have avatars and
then slowly it sort of evolved into a social metaverse but with that also
creation around as a metaverse that's how it all got started specs has a good
point there which is the first time that they imported a VRC avatar they found it
tedious I agree I was completely confused I'd not done unity much before
so I was just like what are all these buttons as well as for Neos they say but
now if he had to choose he would start with Neos because it's simpler and I
agree that's the thing as well if the roles were reversed if you were coming
over to me and I was representative of VR chat and you just you know hopped over
from Neos and I'm like hi welcome to VRC to set up an avatar you need to do the
process that you do for VRC avatar set up you might have the same feedback you
might have the same feedback this is tedious this is confusing and that's
again all about the attitude if you come over naturally if it's confusing you're
gonna have a bad time if you come in the attitude of I'm going to try this I
might get confused I'm gonna ask for help then you'll have a much better
time so Akki Adachi says when will we get the an option to stay logged in
forever that is a colon problem that we have we're only able to remember your
login for seven days due to security and that what that means is if you log in
we'll remember you for seven days and that's like a rolling window so if I
log in today it will remember me till next Tuesday if I log in on Wednesday or
remember you need to next Wednesday so if I continue to log in each day I'll
never have to I'll never have to enter my password again and as I use Neos a
lot I never really have to but we're unable to remember you for forever
because of our security policies we may change that in the future but it just
requires us to sort of evaluate the security problems with that and and
adjust them moving forwards Alex's is there a patreon in fact yes you can
technically make a world which is only accessible to patrons I have no idea if
anyone's done that or why you might do that Lexis that there should be a hard
limit yeah okay we'll sit a hard limit we'll say a hard limit for for quarter
past I would say ten past but we're already like four minutes quarter past
we'll say a hard limit for quarter past you're right I do have other stuff to do
today um Zilla says is the game enjoyable without getting any
subscription yes provided you only upload your avatar and you are wary on
what you save absolutely absolutely don't be a pack rat nowhere stuff is
rather than than saving it as well so if you have a public folder full of cool
stuff that someone else has saved cool that won't count to your storage space
and you can just spawn it if you want to just chill out and and see yourself more
as sort of like a chill out not the platform just a person who chills out on
social VR then all you need is your avatar uploaded you can do everything
that you've ever done on VR chat without a subscription for sure if you want to
build stuff you will maybe at some point run into that up where there's a you
know hey you're out of storage space but if you're careful there's a lot that you
can do about running out of storage space Zilla says so wait is all the
storage in the cloud yes all storage is in the cloud for the most part there is
a caveat to that which is not used a lot when you open Neos you'll see that two
worlds opened you can close these there's ways to do it I'm going to that
by default two worlds opened there is the local home and the cloud home
anything saved to the local home as in saved inside the local home you drop it
in there you hit save will be saved on your computer it doesn't touch the cloud
anything saved anywhere else including your imagery will be saved to the cloud
it is also sort of slightly higgledy-piggledy magic saved to your
computer that's just a local cache of it a local database of it and a local copy
of it but it is saved to the cloud as well I'm forgetting all the way down to
all the links I requested thank you froppy for linking badges thanks June for
linking that mod for the zooming in beautiful by the way yo we do support
odds we have a modding policy and the modding community are upholding that
policy to a better level than I believe even I can like they are basically like
guys if you're being malicious with your mods get out of here like they won't
help you and all sorts of stuff like that I really do like them
well it's don't break the guidelines read that modern plug-in policy also
read our security policy because it's very important that you read all the
policies we have I wrote the part of the modern plug-in policy I also wrote this
is the security policy so just I'm kind of proud of them anyway moving on
zilla says now is there a roadmap for this yes you can find a roadmap on
github someone can link it froppy did thank you no user found says they don't
worry about force crypto NFT why the crypto stock prices and telegram and
also the nearest metaverse website read announcements moving onwards okay no
more questions specs links an issue great lego creator is asking about low
vision stuff if anyone has any low vision assets please do help lego
creator out I know of some but I don't know where they are located so please
please do help them out I don't want to like call anyone out and be like oh yes
I remember this user hello vision but I will direct message a user I'm aware of
and ask for their permission to connect you two together because I know that
they have a lot of tools on their avatar and I'm sure if I ask them politely
enough they'll be happy to show to show you how they got set up so they feel
sorry for asking so don't worry about it if it was a problem if I needed to go
if my house is on fire I would I would I would quit it I would just get rid of it
okay I'm not seeing questions I'm seeing a lot of responses to questions that's
fine see a lot of links to videos face tracker setups excellent videos great
Quincy says speaking of which can people make shops or on the earth to sell
avatars and worlds yes absolutely we actually had I forget I'm so sorry I
forget which furry convention it was but they had the equivalent of the the
dealers den or the like the show floor area as a world and you could go in
there and each person had like a market stall with a hyperlink that could be
on there and that allowed them basically say like hey here's a sample of my
artwork click here it'll take you to their their Commission page stuff like
that you could also do if you set up commissions correctly you could also do
a few demo worlds to demo avatars that wouldn't be like entirely secure like
you know cuz you're still risking it by giving them the avatar to to where but
you won't be able to save it you could do that you can also use Neos on your
like gumroad pages or whatever to be like hey look here's a video of my
avatar in Neos look how expressive it is look at how you know the face tracker
works the dynamic bones work you know that's fine how did I end up scrolling
up I don't particularly know I just like read another question I'm like what
llama kelex bit kyun thank you for letting us know let's try and keep VRC
discussion about that breaking news not here or be here forever it is not a
time to talk about EAC or VRC in this particular I mean VLC a little bit but
not easy basic controls has been linked fantastic
Nash had issues loading their homework last night is that fixed now I'm sorry I
don't know what your homework is I understand that's a nice normal typo so
yes it should be better if you still see issues do let us know we're still keeping
an eye on and based on why I just read we might have to like push a few more
buttons okay moving forwards kip says word from the wise organize your stuff
in folders you will enjoy agreed there is actually a video on my channel about
how I organize stuff in folders coffee has added coffee kai sorry there's a lot
of coffee so I have to be specific coffee kai has asked as added a link to
the Neos modding discord go there if you'd like the one ask I have and I'm
sure the Neos modding community won't be offended by this is do check Neos's
features before you start modding there are a lot of mods that you you think you
might need because you're coming from a different platform that you don't need
good example there being like grabbing other people's bones before the fist
bone update I knew that that was a mod that was in play in VR chat you don't
need that over here so you wouldn't need to mock that so do just take a look at
Neos's features before you then get all sort of embroidered in the modding
community there are a lot of cool mods there but you might not need any is what
I'm saying just like keep in mind what you might need race is one another team
member in the stage of you um we're good for now maybe another time hey wraith
you could do your own officers if you want nothing stopping you you could do a
UK time one as well that might be better for Europe
dresen said that is for ality yes that was a for a further like oh no
funnel equinox kip says um I get the names of them confused if you are a furry
convention creator consider not putting fur in the name of your convention I
know it's like a really easy way to signal to the community hey this is a
furry convention but like for Prime's brain it just is like they all get
bundled into one and I get confused I apologize for that I should be better at
that scrolling through stifle has linked how to organize my
venturi thank you for that that was a Christmas tutorial I've got that sent
out on oh yeah Rafe does do the moderation office hours I am at the
bottom we are at 1715 Sarah kitty and dries on if you are typing a question
you are the last two questions no other questions will be accepted thank you so
much for allowing us to get through this there will be a recording of this on the
on the sounder I use sounder because it's got like transcription the
transcriptions kind of bad but I'll actually click around and and navigate
through the audio quite quickly that people like I'm still waiting for them
to update their transcription editor so that I can actually edit this
transcriptions to be even more accurate so thank you all if you have any other
questions please feel free to drop them in the questions and help section find
a mentor in game read that wiki I'll be back next week and just keep trying guys
well you know we're happy to see you I will see you again next time as you
might see you in nears a little bit later I've got some work to do but I'll
be there Aaron I'll come look at your trigonometry thing I've got a books and
flights well they