All right, welcome to office hours. It is 4 p.m. So we'll go ahead and start if you have
Any questions, please drop them in text a channel and I'll get to them as soon as I can
We are recording but their recording levels are showing is really low for some reason, but I hope it's good
I mean like the the monitor on on audacity says it's good. So that's cool
If not, I'll just boost it there any issues in audio. Let me know. I did tweak things the other day
Oh, thank you. Lex like put some questions into the form. I do sometimes forget to perform this to me. I can lost a cough
Okay, we're done coughing. I can go ahead and look at that form. Oh, there is a lot of questions
That's a question for moderation. So I will go ahead and put that here Sunday. Whatever they do. Anyway, um
Okay, two questions from Lex. Lex says
How should we go about documenting legacy features or features that used to be inside Neos should documentation include when the feature was deprecated?
And what was placed for us all superseded with?
Yes, you should document them if you'd like to if it's removed entirely
There's not really like a need to but if you want to for historical purposes, go ahead and go for it
You can like put a notice on the page that says it's deprecated. Yes, lots of coughing today
But notice on the page that is deprecated usually a wiki would have a template like
Deprecate which would then put like the same consistent banner on them
I don't know if we got one and then check it up there
The only thing that comes to mind that we you know
Might want to document is the legacy of the sphere detector cuz that was such a cool node
Which is entirely not performant not performant like don't use I mean you can't now but even when it was there don't very bad
Um for that question on to the second question, which is would be good idea to document update logs on the wiki
Yes, there was actually a lot of update logs done
on bit man Bob was a hotel room or something and they didn't really have much to do and so they decided to
They decided to just do that for lots of the updates on there
So there is a page somewhere on the wiki that has a lot of the updates
Um bit man didn't keep that up-to-date with the the changing times
But we have an ample opportunity to make that up to coming up me updates for a while
So go for it. If you'd like to just find the old page copy the formatting go for it
So that is the the questions on just got a new tape to the date that I did those at those
It's already uh, it's already July, you know, I remember it being in January and I always have that feeling in January
I'm just like this year's gonna be so long and it's just like ah
Nope, it's it's it's July
Haha
Aaron this what did the sphere detector do and
What should we do in place of the sphere detector was an active sphere collider that existed in the world?
Like it was the only node that did this it had like a visual world
representation at a circle that would be in the world of and anything that was placed
Inside that sphere or touched that sphere would then cause an event coming out of the actor node
it's bad because
It wasn't really clear what happened if you pack it like if you pack it
I didn't think it would work, but it might have left that sphere collider there
What you should use in in place of that is colliders that are set up for your particular kitchen
Active colliders are totally fine. Active mesh colliders are not fine. See my video tutorial series on colliders for more information
I still regularly hear people say that active colliders are bad and should be avoided. No go away
A good example here, which I always give is imagine that you are mining so you're doing you know
Like mining you name it RPG mining you have a pickaxe
There is an ore vein in front of you. You want to whack it with the pickaxe?
some people were like doing crazy stuff like I'm gonna shoot raycasts at the tip of the pickaxe and
Detect if they hit the ore vein and then based on the distance
I know if you're actually hitting it just like what what you're doing there is basically emulating colliders instead
What you should do is place a small sphere collider
Or capsule capsule might be better depending on the gameplay
You're going for on the tip of the pickaxe that is only active when the pickaxe is being held
So let's say it's on your back because it's like back equipped or on the floor
that collider isn't active or maybe you can detect hey there in the mind and when that sphere collider that's active collides with the
Collider of the of the ore you could be like cool
They hit the ore and then you can count the hits or make noises whatever you want to do
Perfectly fine to use an active collider there. In fact, I don't really know how you do it other than you know
I'm gonna shoot raycasts out the
Collider the pickaxe which is essentially what colliders do colliders in a lot of cases are like actually raycast for sphere colliders
Which are the most efficient colliders that are out there?
They do like overlap sphere these which should we just tutorial that pickaxe
Example, I keep giving people can see it. You can see an example of it in
One of the recent creator gems is the one about bread called carb jam or something
Everyone was making this sort of bread stuff. There was a user a Japanese user cannot remember their name fantastic job, whoever you are
I'm sorry name. They made this bread
Kneading thing you go up into an oven and you can like pull out some flour add some water and then you actually need it
It's just like shape keys that like distort this sort of oval of bread when you're like putting your hands on it
It feels kind of good and then you can cook the bread. I'm like, well, where are they getting the flour from?
That's why I made this like farming game a really mean one where you can grow
You can grow wheat. It's all very basic because it's create a gem
So I just used you know free assets that didn't really bother what it looks
But once a single crop of wheat is grown you use a scythe to harvest it and that does the active collider thing
I basically turn on the anti-collider when you're holding the scythe if it hits a fully grown wheat column
It will delete the wheat column replace it with a wheat bale
Grind that now before you say I know that's not how flour is made, but this is a video game
We were making it simple because of course in wheat you want to separate like the top of the plant from the store
That's why windmills exist as they did it more automatically for you. Those are the questions we have right now
I know I was what you're not about wheat and farming for a long time. So if you have any of those you
Oh, I love rumors. So we have a rumor from electronics. Let me go ahead and read this out
So electronic says there is a rumor that you cannot add touch tips or only add partial connection touch tips to your avatar for security reasons
However, in my and some of the users testing they work for all kind of buttons
But it seems you just need hand data component
Um, there is a flow which will disable a touch tip that you add based on a couple of sort of patterns or something like that
This isn't a rumor by the way, like when everyone's like, oh, there's a rumor that like well bad stinky poo-poo thing
I'm like, that's not a rumor like that's documented behavior that exists as a feature. Anyway, what I'm saying is if you add a touch tip to
Another area on rabbit are there is a way to make it work
But touch tips will have basically like a safety switch in them that will be tripped very very quickly
That prevents it from being used
Remember in the exact qualifications there
I don't think I should give those out because then there's easy ways to get around it
But the security preventative measure on those touch tips and the way that that works you can thank me for that
Like I am the one who found that bug a long time ago, and that's how mr
fruit I was looking to try and export a text file from a
scientific experiment and I figured out that if you added a touch tip and a button you could kind of fake it and then you
Could arbitrarily write files to someone's computer and I giggled for a bit and then immediately reported it. I think my
directions for
Making touch tips work like I know some people want them on their feet or their nose, etc
but
you need to add the hand component the touch tip component and then
Save and re-equip the avatar and that should but it should hook it together
If it basically like if that component if a hand component or the the touch it component see something fishy
Then they'll just like disable themselves and then she'd like re-load the object cetera. Yeah, I'm getting kind of like sick of like
Oh, there's a rumor like our space. We're here. That's what here for there's a rumor that Neos is doing Bitcoin mining
We're not like you can actually check. Yeah, it's good. It's not your fault that Tron is
It's just like the way society works
Especially the way a community works in a game like this which are that many updates recently
I heard this Bob heard this Janice at the circle circle circle a little bit of telephone
And you end up with stuff like that back in my day would call that game Chinese whispers
That's where my children would sit in a circle and then some person would come up with something and then they'd whisper it around
In a circle and come back and it would usually get distorted
I feel like that drawing game where you handed like a drawing around and say redraw it
So, you know, I would get a card that said
Monkey with a banana I would draw it and someone else might see that as like monkey of a microphone and it goes round
Yeah
We you I say we used to call it Chinese whispers because I was informed a few years back that we don't call it that
Any children call that a game of telephone and use that as a corporate phrase now as well when when there's a misunderstanding
As it goes through like multiple layers of like corporate hierarchy, we call that a telephone game, you know
Maybe like my manager's manager would be like hey
We need to get this done and he says are this done and then I'm talking to someone to try and get it done
Yeah, it's crazy. Anyway, so now I've got a game of telephone. Yeah, I've heard both too like this
I'm just I'm just very interested. I
There are a bunch of terms that where I work which are
You know on a list and those lists are like instead of saying this say this
so you'll have seen that github recently changed the
Main branch that is used that's like the main development drunch. They changed it from being called master to being called main
and
the term like whitelist and blacklist is like avoided usually now we use allow list or
denialist or
As a friend wants to call it the no-no list and the yeah. Yeah list, which I think is amazing
You don't want to be on my no-no list
No-no list
Anyway other questions so Kyra says bring a good question from elsewhere
What's the reason behind me as having multiple cache locations for data for download assets or whatever the terminology is used?
There aren't actually two
Cache location the important thing to note here is and I'm gonna do a preamble here, which is completely off track of your question
I know stop deleting your data location
You can delete your cache
However, you want stop deleting your data location and stop deleting both of those to fix a problem
Like the one reason I allow you to delete your cache is if it's getting too big and you need hard drive space
That's like the one reason you need to people like oh, no, my knee has crashed once today
I will delete everything and reinstall the game. Please don't do that. Doesn't help me out doesn't help anyone out
I have no idea what's going on. Stop doing it. Just follow the troubleshooting steps
We have which mostly is asking questions and help and you'll see no one in there is like believe your gosh
Sometimes you need to and that's why it becomes a sort of like a solution people like maybe that
But that's usually once we've done a bunch of other steps to see if we can get away without doing it
But on to the actual question, there are two locations
There is the cache the cache will store downloaded files from an assets from assets and stuff like that
So if you go to my world and in my world, there's a model and textures of a cheese sandwich
That's downloaded to your cache
The reason it does that is so that like hey if you go back to that world
Do you see that I am again? You don't need to redownload that
Information from me is cloud you have in your computer. You can just load it. That's the cache
the secondary location is the data folder which has a
Database in it and a bunch of other stuff and also has anything stored locally if you store anything in your local home
Both worlds and items they are stored literally in that folder
And so by deleting that you're deleting basically everything Neos knows about you and any items that you have stored locally
That's why I say don't do it also stored in that location is like the local copy of some of your stuff
That's like to do a syncing etc
So when you delete that you may lose progress, but you sometimes need to delete that when there are syncing issues
But that's after you have tried the sync
Resolution commands which will fix the syncing people are too willy-nilly to delete essentially
That's the to locate you've got cache which is like I'm gonna air quotes this because it's a little wishy-washy
But like other people's stuff is the cache right other people's worlds other people's items other people's crap
And then the data location which is your stuff
I mean it like I said it can go between those is like a Venn diagram, but it's like your stuff
So your items your worlds the stuff stored locally your database
Which is basically like a lookup table for everything is if you know like index cards in a library
That's what they did as well as settings and things like that are also stored. So those are those two locations
they are stored in different places because the Windows file system encourages us to do so everyone is aware of the
temporary folders those are known and
Windows and other tools know that temporary folders exist there and that they can be cleared
That's there is a temp directory on other operating systems
And it's just known that like hey if you need to you can trash the temp folder
That's what that is you so believe that's that question if you have any follow-up questions. Do let me know we'll get to it
Electron says deleting the database makes it harder to help. That's correct the easiest way to help you is to give us log files
Give us log files sometimes the log files don't actually say anything and if the log files don't say anything actionable
That's where it might become
Suitable to delete your cash and stuff like that usually I remember a friend of mine
they bought an oculus headset like the CD one long long time ago 2019 or whatever and
Saying 2019 was a long time ago. It makes me feel strange anyway
And they just couldn't get it working and they were talking to support and support were doing everything
In a diagnostic cetera and it turned up to like they were then like after like a couple of like back and forth
It was okay now try reinstalling which he did it didn't and then they were like hey
Try reinstalling windows that might fix it
And he actually did and I told him no like if a support person tells you to reinstall windows because their software is wrong
Nope, nope
Mm-hmm windows should be nothing to do that there are things that can happen of course
But like they should know about those things anyway
So we did reinstall windows and it didn't work and the support our person was then like could you reinstall windows again?
And at that point he returned the oculus headset and went for a vive
Oh, I have another question here from electronic who asks
Oh, I have seen a couple of log files talking about not being able to find local files to sync
I assume those messing with the fault yes, so when you mess with the folder particularly if you do it in a certain way
Which is something I've always seen people do they like to leak like half their local folders or whatever
We end up with is sort of like a referential thing so again if we think about light
Indexed cars at a library you go to the indexer to look at specially index cars are because or computers
Before there are computers which told you where a library book was or you know before computers where you you needed a books
You would go to the library and you'd go to like an indexer
Which is like a big collection of cards and you would stop like sift through those cards and pick one up
And it'd be like ah yes primes cheese recipes and it's in aisle four row two
And then you know exactly where it is to go fine
So now imagine that you went to the indexer you look for the card
Then you went to grow whatever I said, and it wasn't there the books not there that means that there is a
Can't find that file, and that's what the library in ages like I don't I don't think I'll need another reference
But like you know at school you always had reference books sometimes you had to buy them sometimes school
Would just like you know have a collection of them which they passed out and most of those had graffiti in them
But you know like I think I need one back in the day. I bought actually still have them
I've got like four books on pearl because pearl is the language I
Learned to get start in this like industry and so I have like all the pearl books you can have and I haven't touched them
Ever I wanted to learn like a new language now. Let's say like rust or stuff
I wouldn't need a book like I don't think I'm gonna buy another like reference the only books
I think I'll be buying is like none. Those are all the questions on the list so
If you have more questions do let us know otherwise. I will be sat here in other exciting news
I have a laser level arriving. I bought a
What's a picture to go above my couch?
I always hang paint like how can it because I'm in a rental I use the command strip which don't damage the arm
But for those to work and for you to hang a picture straight
You need the command strips to be straight the command strips on the back of the actual painting be straight
I hand them to be put on the wall straight. I'm done so I get to play of that if there any other questions
Please drop them through you got about eight minutes before I vanish and turn into a pumpkin. I do have a random
Good life pro tip or message check your subscriptions if there is money coming out of your bank account
Monthly add it up and figure out if you use like I found I thought I'd cancelled it
But I found that I was accidentally still still subscribed to uber one
I was using uber one to get better deals on uber eats, but now I'm trying to
Avoid uber eats, so I'm like okay. Let's cancel uber one then that was ten dollars coming out of my month bank account every month
I could put back into so so check that account check your statement. I had one the other day
I didn't recognize I googled it, and I'm like oh, that's my home insurance
Okay, my home insurance company changed name, and I so electronus has provided a picture of the log file
Yeah, that's exactly what you're talking about
Yeah, that is basically like cannot locate that well so here if you're poking around in your local files
And you know trying to sort of see how they work. It's a true keep in mind that they are
Like not encrypted because it's like really weak you can like figure it out, but like they're a little bit like
Obstificated I guess
Some of that is optimization some of that is less curious like I say it's not like strong
It's just like it's like we're dumping files on your computer in a different way that isn't illogical
And so if you see anything weird that's for example if you see in in
electronus is
Screenshot there, it'll be like local colon forward slash and then like a bunch of crap that like random string is like a
Lookup in the database. I was talking about and that database then knows exactly where that is
It maps it to an actual fault of the future and a father for anyone in news
Actually, I forgot. I built it yesterday because I was a bit. I don't know I was bored, and I did it
It was pretty quick. I put a new meme in my memes for this to go to public purple prime
And then go to memes there is a new meme peace weapon
The typing I have lots of time I love it when I mention people that are typing and then they stop
So we have a question here, which I will read and give my interpretation to but it is a moderation question
So I will refer it to the Sunday moderation office hours
So it's within us when it comes to figuring out guidelines and such could having a poll over different future rules guidelines be helpful
tool no um
Polls are great because they give you like a quantity of data, but they don't give you what's called qualitative data
I always get this confused. I probably did it wrong. I did it wrong. Don't yell at me
The point being is like I can see cool 50 people think that this is cool and 50 people think that this is not cool
Great. What does that give me? I don't understand we need more like opinions and stuff like that
Do you remember that the anonymous feedback forum is there also remember the regardless of what you say? This is gonna sound rude
I apologize regardless of what you say as an opinion regardless of the poll result
Moderation have to make the best possible choice factoring everything a good example here being in the clothing area. We are
Fortunate enough to be our own platform and so we can decide what we would like to do there
If you think back to the days of mixer
Which I used to work for
Mixer was under the umbrella of Microsoft
And so even though mixer itself had a view on clothing we had to conform to the big corporate agenda on clothing
Which meant it twice as complicated but also meant we couldn't like people like it should be like this and we're like, yeah
We know but like we can't but we couldn't even say yeah
We know because that adds doubt to like your customers like brain space of that brand. So we're just like no, sorry
This is this this is it. We don't want to do that. And I know that moderation don't want to do that
That's why the conversations are open and feedback is being held but polls are just like not the way should be doing it
I know that's the way it's done in like a democracy, right? But like no no
Yeah, nice isn't a democracy. We try and be as
Good the community as possible
But in some cases, you know can't now I know that nears his stance has always been that we wouldn't take outside venture capital
But I'm providing this as an example if nears if don't quote me on Twitter later
I'm saying the word if a few times if nears took
Venture capital of a substantial amount from another company. They may be able to say hey
We need you to change your clothing policy again, and it needs to conform to you know business needs
business business business business and so
Just like think about that the next time you are the next time you're mad at a company for changing their policies
Just just think about all the things in play there
Another good example here being what happened to OnlyFans. So OnlyFans had like advertisers
Sponsorship venture capital etc. That was just not okay with them having
pornography on OnlyFans and so they tried to remove pornography from OnlyFans and of course the community were like
Screw that and then OnlyFans had to then probably change up a bunch of their ad deals such that there could be same thing happens
with
YouTube people like why is my YouTube video being
Demonetized YouTube hates this the reason is because monetization through YouTube comes through adverts and if no one wants to put adverts on a particular
Type of content let's say you know none of the advertisers that are registered with the other side of monetization as in they are paying
YouTube to put ads on videos
They don't want to appear in any cheese related videos then the fact that you mentioned cheese in your video would cause it to be
Demonetized isn't YouTube's fault
It's the advertisers that they're working if they could find a cheese advertiser that wants to be monetized on cheese videos
Beautiful and they probably have cheese adverts somewhere
But when it comes to sort of real edgy topics some advertising people
Just don't want adverts on there and so that video gets demonetized. It's nothing to do with YouTube though
There are no ad money. We cannot pay you
Moving onwards to another question we have here from SLS doesn't Rothenberg Ventures own 10 to 15 percent of strikes
Rothenberg Ventures doesn't exist any so
Rampa if you're typing question go for it
Otherwise we'll cut off at the point as we just run over by two minutes with me ranting about demonetization on YouTube
Like I've been on the other side of it like I've been on the other side of advertisers
I've been on the other side of monetization. I've been in the side of that so it makes a lot more
Okay, that was a question so go ahead and end up here, and then we will carry on on anyway
And as I said check that new meme and my memes for if any of the questions
Please feel to demand me or follow the contacting the Neos team guidelines. I'll get this posted soon and
Tag the office hours notification do that when it's ready speech you next time. Bye