Alright, welcome to Primetime, it is 4pm so we're going to go ahead and get started.
Before we get started I've got a link to share, which is something I put together
it was yesterday. This is endeavoring to help out Git and the moderation team on
Thursday, not Thursday, Sunday, yeah Sunday, I don't know why I said Thursday.
But I put this together as a wiki page for you all. There are notes on this page, but
do reiterate them. That page is not part of the guidelines itself, it is generated from
interpretations of the guidelines. I have checked it over with moderation and it seems to be okay,
but it's still possible to have guideline breaching activity in any of the sessions
featured in that table, but hopefully that will cut down on the amount of times in Sunday where
we get "can I have adult content in this session?" So maybe that will help, so take a look at that
link in the thread. I don't know why, but every single Sunday the moderation team get the same
question over and over again, so maybe that would help. Anyway, moving forwards to actual questions,
we have a question from Jackal, who says "I've been having a lot of trouble with objects' rotations
when trying to parent objects to other objects by drag and dropping in the inspector. I know that
this is most likely because the order of operations matters, but do you have any advice for practices
on this?" And they've added background as well, which is great, to add background information to
your questions, that sometimes helps. "I'm making a clock as per your tutorial, but messed up the
logics and am having trouble with the hands, they keep rotating in weird ways when I try to put
everything together. I'm sure I'll figure it out, but if it's best to assemble parts of an object
in a particular order, that would be of real help to me." I kinda need more information about what
you're seeing. Like, rotations are complicated, basically. Just generally, for general tips on
that, is to avoid using Euler angles wherever you can. There is always a non-Euler angle way of
doing things, and I am always surprised when people just won't learn the tiniest bit of maths to avoid
the Euler angle problem. For those who aren't aware, if you use Euler angles too much, too
much, too many, too much, when you're dealing with rotations, you'll end up in Gimblelock, and
Gimblelock is just very confusing. We don't represent it well inside the inspector, and so
you end up with basically not realizing that it's happened. If you ever see axes other than the one
that you're editing in the inspector change, that's because we're avoiding Gimblelock by adjusting
those. You can't represent the complete possible rotational set of rotations, if that's a phrase
that makes sense, whatever, in Euler angles, it's impossible. Quaternarians, quaternians,
however the heck you pronounce that, I still don't know, you are able to represent rotations in,
and it's very simple. A particular note for that one is the axis angle mode, which I believe I do
cover in the tutorial, which is why I was confused how you may be struggling, but I'll have to take
a look at that in-game to see what's going on there. I'm not entirely certain. Something that
also might help is the origins tutorial. I will go ahead and link that in the thread as well.
Rotations are origin-dependent, and sometimes origins can be problematic, particularly with
random 3D models downloaded from Sketchfab where the developer of the model is like,
"Yes, the origin is inside the moon!" Moving forwards to Luzanth's question,
they are asking "Is there a way to change spawn points per player? I won't have myself spawn in
my Cloud Homes bedroom, but I'll play a spawn at the doorway." You should be able to use value
user override on those, I'm not certain though. I will go ahead and open up the codebase, that'll
take a few minutes though, so we'll jump back to that one, but you should be able to value user
override and turn off, like have the default value for the spawn point to be off. But I don't know if
that's the case until I open up the codebase, so give me a second and I'll get that open. I just
gotta click like 17 different buttons to get that sorted, because you know, life. Okay, there we go,
that's opening. Jackal asks "How is your extended trek across the wasteland next door going?"
That's kind of on pause, basically. I'm happy to move over there, what I need to do is wait
for the renewal note for this place, and then we'll see what the price of that is for anyone
who doesn't know what I'm going on about. I'm most likely moving locations very soon, so I'm
moving like literally one building to the left, so that's going to be fun. That's sorted. Okay, next.
Actually there's a note from them, "Thank you for the advice about dynamic variables." Yes,
dynamic variables are the best. Dynamic variables are literally the best. Beagle says "Is there an
easy way for people to pull members out of a hidden lair?" There have been some instances
where people lurk in hidden lairs, kick them from your world or ban them from your world. Like, I
hate to be blunt when it comes to that shit, but like I really just don't have time for it.
If they want to hide in hidden lairs, they can go elsewhere and not be in my session.
Depending on what methodology they're using to create such a system, they will have anti-pulling
out systems, so you know, it's difficult. Of course, if it's not your world, you might be
limited to what you can do, which Froppy is updating their response with, but if it's your
world, just kick them. Just kick them. The only way that we can challenge behavior like that is by
making clear that it is not okay, and that's just not okay. So, cool. Usually what happens
with the hidden lair system is it's something of the equivalent of they are parented under a slot
which is disabled for a select number of people in the world. I don't care the reason why you're
in that. If you're in my world, as in if I'm the host, you're going to be visible, and you're not
going to be in that. Additionally, you're not going to use one of the annoying systems which
goes like, you know, it makes like a space-age blink noise and like, you know, purple sphere,
as far as I remember, when you go in and out of it. If you're inside my session, you're in there
to be in my session. If you want to hide from my session, you can go to another session. That's the
easiest way to hide from my session. If that makes you not want to hang it in my session because I
don't allow you to use your special hidden lair system, that's absolutely fine. Don't come.
Really sorry to be blunt, but like, that's the way I see it. I don't have time for that behavior.
If you think it's cool, I want you to think about what you're doing. I want you to think
long and hard about why you are going to someone else's world to hide in it.
Beagle has another question. Let me just make sure I've missed any before the video I posted.
I have not. Okay. Beagle says, "For some reason in one of my buddy's worlds, when translating using
the gizmo, and then there's a weird crust like you see on the Avatar collaboration appears,
and it'll snap the translation to that." That is native snapping. So here is a, albeit long video,
but here it is. That is native snapping that's occurring. There are a few ways to kind of make
that happen less. Something I've noticed is that if you're playing around with gizmos near a picture,
the picture will have a snapping component on it, which means that gizmos will snap into the
picture. So go into the picture, you'll find, I think, snap plane for a picture, you can remove
that component and then it won't snap to those pictures anymore. Various other things have that.
Where can that hide in the world? In the same world at random we kick people to...
That snapping issue shouldn't be causing people being kicked. There might be something that's
sort of left in your world. I remember one of the trolliest things I ever did. Oh my god,
I'm just arming you with stuff. One of the trolliest things I ever did was accidentally
parent a snap grid component to the world origin somehow. Snap grid will set up a grid of points
that will do that kind of lock thing that you're talking about. And I just put it accidentally in
the middle of the world. It was like, cool, gizmos just don't work in this world. Sorry, my bad.
That's pretty easy to fix. And hey, if anyone is listening and decides to take that and start
doing it to other people's worlds, it would constitute this harassment and maybe reportable
under the moderation guidelines and may cause account restrictions. But there you go.
I've told you how to do it and also told you how to mitigate it, which is go look for that
snap grid component. There is more information in that video above there. Mentalish says that yes,
some people have built systems to fight anti-layer systems. Yes, there is anti-layer systems,
then there's anti-anti-layer systems, and then there'll be anti-anti-anti-anti-layer systems,
whereas the actual soul for that layer system is a behavioral one, which is why I'm telling you,
just kick them. I can't see that player. They must be doing something malicious. Kicked.
Thumbs up. Move on with your life. If they get angry about you, cool, ban them.
It's just like, you know, I can ban people because I don't like their avatar. Like it,
if it's my sessions, I don't need a reason to. I've also seen one person that was using like the
equivalent of a hidden layer system creatively. And I accepted that one because they were doing
like a bit as a character. But it was still annoying. So keep that in mind. You know,
it was sort of like RP related, which is like totally fine. You can state a reason for kicking,
but there's a problem in this community, which is basically like, if they break any rule or do any
infraction, even if you tell them exactly what they're doing that's wrong, they're not going to
listen to you and they're going to make you the problem. It is problematic and yeah, okay, you
should give them a reason. But if they don't listen, proceed with just kicking them. Cody
said, I assumed it was possible to manage people or objects that spawned in by having a spawn point.
You can indeed have a spawn point, but the problem is even if you have a spawn point, which sets a
parent, they can have logic or system on their avatar, which goes like, I know you want me to be
parented to this very precise anti like this culling system, this management system, this
world organizational system, but I don't care because I'm an inconsiderate person. I want to
be parented to the world route or my hidden layer system and make a lot of noise. And then when I
open up my context menu, I want it to do the entire corestral Halo soundtrack for no apparent reason
in global audio at a hundred percent volume. So, you know, like I said, the only way to combat
this stuff is to just stamp it out. For anyone who thinks I'm being unfair, just imagine going to a
real world party, okay? And the party is hosted at Prime's house and I open the door to my front door
and I say, welcome, welcome, come on into the party. You hand me a bottle of wine that you
brought, maybe some nice cheese. And I'm like, please take off your shoes. And you go, okay. And
you take off your shoes. That's exactly how it should be in someone else's session. You know,
and then you don't go into someone else's party at the house. You don't come into my house, you know,
and you're like, I'm going to hide in a hidden layer and sit in your sink. No, that's unacceptable.
You're not going to sit in my sink. I'll happily get you a chair. I'll happily get you wine and
booze or whatever you want to drink. I'll feed you. I'll entertain you, but you're not going to
sit in my sink. You know, the party's over, everyone's left. And I go to bed and I hear like
giggling from my cupboard. I open up and it's like, sorry, I was in the hidden layer system
inside your cupboard. Get out of my cupboard and leave. It doesn't make any sense. If anyone is
like, oh, it's their computer, right? I understand that it'd be different if we had like servers or
if it's a headless or if it's not, you know, they're not being hosted, but for the majority
of sessions that aren't headless right now, they are, you're literally on someone else's computer.
Like the host's computer is controlling your access to that session. So be considerate, please.
Moving forward to other questions. So I stopped ranting about that particular topic because I
could rant for hours and people won't listen anyway. He'll still have that problem. Years
to come, you know, it'd be like, you know, the year is 2050 and people are still in hidden layer
systems. Why? We don't know. So we have a question here from Lex. She says, is there any way to make
facets spawner desktop not parent to the overlay layer without mods? Not that I'm aware of.
Make that font size just a little bit bigger from me and then you've got an amazing meme.
There is, I say the font size a bit bigger so I can read it without zooming in, but otherwise
amazing meme. So unfortunately I don't know the answer to your question next. I'd have to take
a look. I remember that we don't, this is like a really annoying cop out and I understand that it's
frustrating. We don't technically support facet editing in desktop mode. And I hate that I'm
saying that, but like, you know, I guess you could like write some code into the facet, like a little
bit of logics that's like detects if the user that spawned it is, um, is a desktop user and then do
some re-parenting there. That might work. There we go. Beautiful. Beautiful. Speaking of like RP
characters like that, I did have one person at one point that had like, I don't know, like an
Iron Man style landing. Actually no more appropriate one would be if you know that film Hancock,
it's got Will Smith in it. Um, at the start of the film Will Smith's basically like a drunk superhero
and his landing is like, cool. I'm going to completely wreck the road and the pavement.
There'll be a crater every time I land. That was their like character's system for landing. And it
was like, I know that you're like a character and you're trying to have fun here, but if you could
stop like completely destroying my pavement with like sound effects and particle systems when you
land, that'd be amazing. Thank you. By the end of the film, he can land without destroying the
pavement. So maybe you should watch that film again. Angry Pilot asks, "Any info on button
delegate relay?" Um, you shouldn't really need to use that. There's probably ways you can do it,
but that usually is covered by like button action trigger or something like that. Let me see why we
have that component. Button delegate relay. Let's see if we use that anyway. We do. We do use that.
Set up delicate action. Oh, it's used on the audio reverbs and component. We use it to make all the
buttons appear for the presets on the reverb. Yeah, it looks like just that. Hold on, there's a
couple of other uses. That's the one I wanted there. Symbols about reference. Yeah, that's
literally the only place we use that. So in some cases, there are components which you can attach
and can technically use, but they have no real use that makes sense. The better question always is to
start with the problem, not the solution. So there are a bunch of components which are just like
completely nonsensical. In Uncategorize, look for up down controller or something. That's a really
funny one. Ask Syro the next time you see him for his up down platform that uses that silly component.
I might have it too. I don't remember if I saved it. Okay. Jack asks, question for dynamic variables.
If I'm setting a variable to reference the user who turned the object on and when they turn it off,
I want to clear the variable. Am I doing it correctly by writing basic user node to the
variable? It seems to work. The variable comes null. Yeah. Like a dynamic reference variable
of type user with a value of null will be okay. Something you should keep in mind is that some
nodes will take in a null user ref and do different behavior. Particularly fire on true
and fire on change, I believe they do custom stuff if you pass in a null rather than empty. I think I
have those documented on the wiki because I got tired of talking about fire on true, so I went
through and was like step by step here's what happened. So I'll see if I can find that. Fire on
true. Fire. And then someone asked me a question about... Yeah, just double check that. There's
actually a bit of any null handling that I've written there. But it's fine. Sometimes what I'll
do as well is I'll create a variable which is called like user set and that'll be a boolean.
And then that's really easy to pick up. You can do like is user -- I'm doing this in text,
but it won't make sense. Is user set question mark colon. And then you can use user or host user
for the parts of that. Now, of course, you could do is null, not null, et cetera. But sometimes
it's better to do that by a more declarative way. There is also the has value output of some of the
dynamic variable nodes you can use there. A lot of the time, though, you can actually just get away
with something along the lines of like... Yeah, I'm literally typing that. World user question mark
question mark host user is a lot of times what I use. Although sometimes I'll do like in the middle
there, I'll put like nearest user head sometimes. Because then it's like if there's a user set on
the object with dynamic variables or the closest user or the host user, and then it gets there.
Right now someone had a question which I needed to look up in the code base. I will scroll up and
find that now that the code base has opened up. Spawn points per player. Excellent.
That ain't the spawn point component. Not the spawn point component. Spawn... Let's do simple...
Yeah, okay. So the common spawn area, which is the one that usually creates the glowy ring,
that will respect the enabled field and the slots active field. So you could use that and do a
values override on that for those. Although I don't know if that would work with synchronization,
because I don't know if the host spawns that. Try that. Let me know how that works out.
The non-spawn area one, so the spawn point rather than the the circuity one,
that doesn't pay attention to the enabled state, which is problematic. But maybe it does. Give me
a moment. Where's the weight? Like there's a weight property on the spawn point, right?
Where's that at? Simple spawn... Simple user spawn...
I'm thinking of something else. I'm gonna just quickly hop to a video I recorded.
There's another component. I gotta look for it.
Thank you. Okay, good. Whilst I'm looking this up, make sure you get other doobly-doos questions in.
Now I remember. Thank you, Lex, for the help. The circular one, that is just an edit to the
common spawn area component. With the spawn point generator, that's correct. Yep, thank you so much
for that. That's exactly what I was looking for. Yeah, so common spawn area is the the common
component between spawn point and spawn. The reason why it's confusing is because the the dev tip has
got the create new menu. You go create new object, you can go spawn point or spawn area. Spawn area
does the sort of glowy ring thing. Spawn point does a static point. So all of those will respond
to the enabled and the slot is active field. I do not know if they will allow for a values override,
but that's how I would at least start doing it. A note there as well is that you can use other
point generators in the common spawn area. So I know that you will usually see a circle,
but you could also do like a sphere. I don't know why you would, but you could. You could also do a
whatever point generators we have. Let me take a look. Find all references. A box, a circle,
a sphere, a square, and yeah. Oh, Beagle has a new question and they say, can you possibly do an
entire logic system without using logic nodes at all, complete with the inspector? Oh, you could.
I would not suggest doing that. You'd basically be hooking up components by using ribbons that
you'd manually created yourself. Jackal asks, is there a way to make a hemisphere using the
procedural measures in the game or would you need a blender or some other modeling program to make it
hemisphere? You'd need a blender to do it. If you want to do that quickly, and I know this is kind
of like a long winded solve, but you only have to do it once. Go find sloppy mcloppy's ring of the
neolander, inspect it and find the templates in there and you can pull out all the shapes that are
in the ring of the neolander and use them isolated. They have good UVs and stuff like that. So I
sometimes do that. I think I actually exported all the meshes that that uses into like one object and
saved that to my inventory a while back. Player Cody asks, there was a mental workshop video of
name tags I attempted to follow yesterday where everything was set up the way you want. I wanted
logged out for the day, came back the next day, I found everything was back to default. Is your
video more accurate? My video might be more accurate. I would have to watch that video to
see what the problem is. Common problems when it comes to name tags is not adding the requisite
components to the name tag so that it doesn't know that it exists and it won't be hooked up correctly.
There's also people don't save it correctly, so sometimes they save it outside of the avatar root,
it needs to be inside the avatar root to work. I've seen a couple of people who make a custom
name tag in the user root and then save it, which does not work. And then various other things like
that. If you have multiple name tags in your hierarchy as well, it might sort of interfere
with each other, so make sure you've got one. My video has the way I recommend doing it,
so do keep that in mind. I don't know if it's going to work. I watched the workshop one when
they recorded it, but I haven't watched it in a while. The thing that I do that kind of like
reduces the chances that you can make a problem is I drag the existing default name tag into the
avatar root right at the start, and then I edit it from there. Other people will do setting up
the name tag from scratch, but that means you have to add all of the components manually,
whereas if you just steal an existing one and drag it into the avatar root,
then you don't have that problem. Beagle says "Where the hell did you get all the meme material
and stuff inside of your inventory? I browsed through it the other day and holy-" I presume
you mean the meme folder inside my public folder? Okay, yeah. That one needs renaming. It's not like
memes that you would see on 4chan, 9gag, or iFunny, stuff like that. It's not like regular
memes. It's usually sort of chaotic distractableness that happens inside of Neos. Of particular note,
there's a coat hanger there that's got dynamic bones on it. That used to be effortless equippable,
but I think that went wrong, but you could just make it one. That happened because a few people
that I was hanging out with were using deer avatars, and they had, you know, antlers,
and I just thought it'd be funny if I could like hang a coat hanger on their antlers, so I got that
happening. All sorts of stuff like that. There's a turtle in there, which has no instructions
at all, so I'm amazed if anyone's figured it out, but there's a turtle you can spawn in there,
and it's got a straw in its nose, and if you pull that straw out really fast, it plays the Beyblade
opening, and that occurred because I was speaking to someone in the world, and they were talking
about their use of straws, and I said "those better be, you know, metal or paper straws,
right?" They said "no plastic." I said "you know they have to like pull those out of turtles?"
And I did like a quick pulling motion, and someone went "like a Beyblade!" and then I made that.
It's like, you know, like environmentalism via memes, that one is. There's also a cutlery box
in there where you can grab and pull out cutlery. That was caused by a similar thing where someone
was saying like "oh yeah I need more cutlery" and I said "what did you mean? What do you mean?"
They used plastic cutlery, and I took offense to that, so I made that to kind of show the
inanity of it. The one that I have a real big problem with is foil. So I know we're going over
time but whatever. If you have a baking tray that is metal, and you put foil on it before you put
whatever you want to cook in the oven, you're like not human, I don't understand. You're like "oh I
put foil over my metal baking tray so I don't have to clean my baking tray" and it's like "cool,
all right, so people have to mine in the ground for a limited resource which they then have to
like smelt and process an alloy because aluminum is difficult to process and then they have to
roll it incredibly thin onto reels just so you can avoid doing the dishes. What planet are you on?
What planet are you on? Just do your dishes. Now I'll accept if you use if you use foil to like,
for example, cover a chicken or cover a turkey when you're cooking it. That makes more sense.
It's purely if you're using it to avoid cleaning. They dig that stuff out of the ground and it's a
limited supply. We're not going to run out in your lifetime, I know that, but like just think about
it. It's like because I can't be bothered to clean a baking tray, I have reduced the level of
aluminum in the world by a little bit. All right, moving on to actual questions rather than my
strange environmentalism. It's like really weird. It's like, you know, my computer's on all the time,
but I won't use plastic. It's crazy. Anyway, Tiki says, "Is the way to limit the rotation of fingers
in the hair manager in my avatar impales itself its own claws right now?" There is not. Currently,
there is not. That is a common thing that we have. Cody has an update to their nameplate issues.
"They spawned a previous avatar, hopped into that one, saved the configuration,
world spawned and recently saved one, hopped into it and everything was fine. When I said
it changes next to it in years, everything was fine. When I'm watching years ago,
I found out the default was activated." Double check the components. That could also be
synchronization and it could be this amazing thing in the inventory where occasionally the order
of items in your inventory can just randomly change. And so you may think that you're in
the most recent copy of your avatar, but you're actually in a copy from like three years ago,
because that happened recently. I see lots of people talking about like foiling their
baking trays. I'm too lazy to clean it. So you would rather like, you know, accompany
mines in the ground to get small rocks, which they have to smelt and roll, just because you're lazy?
Like, what planet are you on? You know, like hundreds of years, we're going to be like out
traveling the stars, we're going to be like on Mars, other like solar systems and stuff like
that. And they're going to run out of aluminum and they'll look and they'll be like, it's that guy,
the person who didn't just do their dishes. You know, aliens are looking down on us and they're
like, "shall we make contact with this like seemingly civilized society?" They've got
problems, but should we make contact with them? Oh no, they put like foil on them.
Rather than just cleaning them. Izit says that aluminum is recyclable. Yeah, did you know that
lots of recycling is actually just a lie? And like, it just goes in landfill anyway. It's crazy.
Here, I have a video for you. Actually, you can just like YouTube it, like recycling is a lie.
And like, you'll see a lot. Yeah, it is plastic. Yeah. But the other thing with like metal
recycling, you have to remember is it's foil. It's, it's, it's, it's going to get mixed up
and it's going to not be recycled sometimes. It's the, it's, it's thin. You have to get all
the grease off of it. So someone ends up cleaning it. Like someone, either like a very hot light
reforging machine or whatever, but you know, it's not just like when, when someone says like,
"oh, it's recyclable", but you have to put more energy into recycle it. We'll get back to Nia's
questions rather than recycling. Anyway. This week, Prime talks about recycling. Actually,
one more final bit about recycling. Clean your containers before you recycle them. I have a great
memory of being at university once and you know, university housing, sort of like five other people
and I was doing the recycling for them and I was sorting it out and it was like half a bottle of,
of Coca-Cola is not recyclable. The bottle that it's in, sure that's recyclable, but you have to
empty the, the cola out of the bottle before you recycle it. If you have cola in the bottle when
you recycle it, they won't recycle it because it's dirty. You have to rinse it. The polystyrene,
like burger boxes that you get from like a cheaper burger places, not recyclable. They're equally not
recyclable when they have half a burger in them. Like a jar of mayonnaise made out of glass, very
recyclable, but not when it's like one ape full of mayonnaise that's rotted and is moldy. Like,
you know, you like rinse stuff. It got to the point where like, I just took like a big glass
and I was just emptying everything that people were trying to recycle into this glass. And I
got up to a pint of liquid and I said that liquid should have been in the drain for that to be
recyclable. Oh, you should also remove the labels from things like you should remove the labels
from glass jars, bottles, containers, jars, et cetera. You have to remove the labels as well.
Cause the label is paper and needs to be recycled separately. I'm really, I'm going back to
questions now. I promise, I promise. No more recycling. Beagle says, where can we find
your MMC thing that you showed me in the wild? You already jammed out to the fart reverb.
Yeah, that's better. That should be in the meme folder. I need to do a video on it,
but it should be in the meme folder. Moving downwards. Peach Clover says, do you know
what, if any, model import format preserves origins of the object? Let me, I think this
is an unlisted video where I got angry at someone because they wouldn't, they wouldn't listen when
I was talking about origins. Yes. I haven't found a single 3d model format that I can input or output
and keep the translations for. It's really bugging me. I think I made an issue about it.
Okay. Moving forwards. I'm double checking. I haven't missed any. Okay. Here we go.
Okay. We got the import format. No, I'm not aware of, I want to fix that one. That one
really annoys me. I did the finger one. There's no way that I know of with the fingers.
Cody says, I was poking around with experiment with different forms of lighting in Neo Studio,
the semi video series on lighting. Is that a good source of, so yeah, that's a probably a little bit
old. I haven't really done much on it. I also haven't done much on sort of optimizing lighting.
One of the things I will say about lighting is if you are doing an inside map, as in it is not
outside, delete the main directional light in your world and light it purely with actual light
sources. I see so many sort of like social worlds where they're like inside a building and they
still have the sun and it just, it doesn't make any sense. Like if you're making that, say like a bar
that's inside, there's no way to go outside. So there's no outside, there's no, you know,
back door or anything like that. There's no front door or anything like that. It should not have a
sun in it because the sun should not be lighting it. I mean, if there's windows, yeah, sure. But
like it shouldn't, because there's no way to sort of restrict the sun's influence. It means that the
sun will just like beam in on everything and ignore any sort of collision. And so it's like,
ah, yeah, we want to make like a, you know, like a CD bar where maybe like, you know,
you've got the tip to solve the murder mystery in your game world and you've got a sun in there.
Beagle says, how does one prevent light from bleeding into floors above and below?
You usually have to sort of surround the things with primitives. Like if it's,
if it's custom meshes, it will usually leak more light. But if it's primitives,
you can usually sort of block the light a bit better with primitives. That's what usually
what I see happen. We do need better lighting tools, most notably, of course, light baking,
but also some tweaks to things called light probes, stuff like that,
which is on the graphics side of things that, that, that needs to happen at some point.
Zalasar, I think that's how I pronounce that says, I've heard a good Linux experience is to make your
own multi-tool tip. Where would I start if I wanted to do this? I don't have a tutorial on that
because I don't like multi-tool tips. I don't want to go into another like four hour rant about
recycling and stuff like that. So I will just leave it there. Like I don't like multi-tools.
I don't suggest you make one. If you want to use a learning experience, try making a game where you
are a broccoli trying to outrun a green cat that chases you through the swamp. And you'll learn a
lot more than if you make a multi-tool. There may be tutorials out there, but I'm not aware of.
If anyone has any, please refer to link them. Like when you come into Neos and new people are like,
how do I learn Neos? It usually goes like, let's make a custom inspector. Let's make a custom
multi-tool. And it's like, no, let's make something that touches other people. You know what
I mean? Not literally, but touches other people with my creativity, let them show, show them your
creativity and learn by doing that. And that usually isn't a multi-tool or a customer inspector.
Like look at the MMC entries that we had this year that are in the sort of world social,
world other, world game category, where they're trying to tell you a story. They're trying to
tell you some art through their creation. Like the carwash, for example, that carwash map
makes very little sense, but is fun. And people that worked on that probably learned a few things
and there wasn't like, there was a lot of creativity in that world, but there wasn't a lot
of technical complexity. Like everything was sort of, there was a pin pad for a door. I've got a
tutorial on that one. There was like an interactive screen for the carwash. I don't have tutorials on
that one, but it's quite, it's quite simple. I don't want to demean it by saying, you know,
it's not worthy of the praise it's getting. It is. It's just like nothing in that world was very
complicated. It was very, very well put together, but the technical aspects weren't very complicated,
which isn't a bad thing. And that's what I mean, Beagle. I'm not saying the creativity was low,
the creativity was incredibly high, but the technical skills needed to make that world were
lower than say, making a multi-tool or making a custom inspector or making red print or making
any of the other tools that people use. It was like a very good way of doing things.
Beagle has one final question. We'll close off questions there cause we're at 1646. For some
reason, my Eagle mounted beast of different and decent inspector size. For some reason,
my Nardo's inspector is tiny and it resizes the dev two tip smaller. That's usually caused by the
tool anchor scale. So try that one, try the tool anchor scale. Let me just head on over to the dev
tip code as well. Yeah, we don't really have any scale logic in the create inspector thing.
Make sure it's the tool anchor, not the like nothing underneath cause that all gets generated.
I can have it like the next time, which I don't, I'm doing a bunch of stuff. And with that,
okay, we'll answer one more final question from eyes and that, that, that last question,
no more questions, even about recycling. Is there some convenient way to give things
colliders that are the same precise shape as the object model? You need to watch,
if you would like to, I don't want to like order around. You can take a look at
optimizing colliders. Here you go. And we'll go ahead and leave off there. In the meantime,
between now and next time, I want you to think about what you're throwing away
and how you can reduce, reuse, and recycle it. See you next time.