All right everyone welcome to prime time the office hours stroke am a or prime man whatever questions
You might have for me, please thrill free to drop the questions in the office hours chat, and I'll get to them as soon as I can
With there being no questions in place right now
just a quick reminder to everyone to continue reading our roadmap reading the Neos wiki for the contact in the news team page and
Playing yes. I am a fun quiet bunch today
I mean if you have any questions any questions at all drop them in the office hours chat. I'll be happy to answer them
That's why you're all here. You have no questions. That's totally fine, too
But we're just gonna sit here in silence, so I'm making awkward. Oh the most amazing amazing sentence someone has a question
I'm amazed please please delight me with your question. I can't wait to answer it
Okay, so we have a question from bad. This is a good question
So thank you for asking it that says is there any plan for account management as in changing usernames or emails and such?
Right now lots of that stuff goes through shifty
She's amazing at her job and helping people out, but I would love for that to be automated
That will go into a lot of what will happen with like the website, so
If you visit like the author on the ice calm you'll see the sort of new
A website framework, that's not what it'll look like that's just sort of like a technicality thing as a technical thing
There's a lot of new endpoints and authorization there
That will allow things like
Changing username email and stuff like that
Those would be most of the website features that you you know find on many other web providers
I'd also like to see if we can get those abilities in the actual game from of them being in the actual game sometimes this
Processes are a little bit complicated and so when I usually do them on a website because it's easier, but
We'll see what we can do. Honestly though being yes
I would I would love it if shifty's primary job throughout the day was not
Doing stuff which could easily be automatable by a screen
I'm happy that she does it for us, but it would be great if you know she didn't do same goes for patreon
I want like automated patreon linkage
That'll be interesting because we need would basically need you to do is link your account met like you know how right now
Yeah, like it'll link automatically of the emails match
If emails don't match you have to like speak to shifty etc. It'll be like instead login to
patreon and allow
Like login to Neos allow
Neos to access your patreon data, and it'll be able to see that you have a pledge to it
And I'll be able to link those together
I strangely have the sort of policy of always trying to make myself redundant when it comes to any sort of process that I don't
Think I should do you know when you think about like vacuuming you're like oh
can I automate vacuum cleaning and that's how things like Roombas came up and they haven't yet found a Roomba that doesn't eat my
Socks, so I don't like this okay. We have some new questions, but a little bit about the Roomba first of all
Yeah, I agree like half the cleaning power of a Roomba is just making you pick up stuff like I I used to use a Roomba
I wouldn't turn it on as much as I would like because I had to babysit it
It could never do like a full cleaning job and even when it could I didn't think it was doing a good job
So I purchased a regular vacuum cleaner, and I pushed the vacuum cleaner around my apartment. How he would do it normally and manually and
It collected like way more dust and then I thought it should have and so I just haven't used it
I don't think it's effective. It might be on like an exceptionally clean house
But like it's like three pairs of slippers like in my like living room, and I don't really know why and there's a sock over there
I don't know how long that's been there. You know you got a tidy up. It's crazy
I bought a second pair because I needed to launder my first pair
But then I realized my first pad couldn't be laundered. It's not like like they're fluffy insides, right?
But I wanted to clean the fluffy insides, and I had I clean the fluffy insides
And it's like maybe just throw it in the laundry no you can't do that
So I specifically bought a new pair of slippers
Could be thrown in the laundry obviously by itself you wouldn't put it in with a full load of laundry
Excuse me. You wouldn't throw it in with a full load of laundry, but like you
You just put them in separately
As for the actual questions, sorry getting back on topic here. Ruscio asks
I have a question about the WebSocket text message sender node
node not note if the WebSocket client component has a separate user than user responsible for the impulse that is received at the
WebSocket text message sender node does the event get networked back to the other user as a rejected outright
I have opened up the code base to take a look at that, and I'll also take a look at
the
Follow-up question there, which is
Can I localize the WebSocket client component or would that not be advisable?
I'm go ahead and open up the WebSocket client component first and just sort of take a look at the I pushed the wrong thing
Control no, I don't run Neos. Stop. Stop. Don't run. Oh, it's just building. That's fine
WebSocket client here is a component as the
Handling user property here. Handling user is null. Cool. Cool. Cool. Cool. Cool. Cool
Text message received dot invoke
Okay, so that would be the Web
Text WebSocket text message receiver here
client text message
received there is no network synchronization of the event so should only be from the user which the
The WebSocket is done by basically we only open up the connection on the
on the user that is in the
Handling user so that's good there
Now you could by the looks of things you could
You could values override or localize in whatever way you want to the the component
The only issue there is that you would have to localize as effectively as you can
I don't know how effectively to do this across the board all of the properties. So there's URI
access reason and connect retry interval
Those all sync as in the value of those sync. And so if those all aren't localized then you'll have a problem same with the is
connected
Those are all syncs. You'll basically have to like localize the entire thing
As it only connects to the handling user
It might be better to just like make you know, say there's four users make four copies of that component on a slot
So four slots and use and use that right?
There'll be no overhead from doing that because it's only connecting on the user that is in the handling user property
See what happens if the handling user is null
Connect to references
It's helping out here, thanks. Oh, cool.
Connecting user not equal to local user
Parallels not. Yeah, should be good. Just make a yeah make four if there's four people etc
So Gun Griffin then asks does the bhaptics port open automatically or does it require enable? It opens up automatically
Make sure that the bhaptics software, the bhaptics player
has like a green status and that you've tested it if it's your first time and then it should just run it a little
bit like the
VIVE face tracker. I know the face tracker like when we initialize it we actually like will
Cause the the software to run which I think is quite cool, but I found that would be haptics better to run the software first
Particularly because you know putting it on is an activity. So I put it on and then I make sure it's okay and then I
I will then start Neos. With the face tracker like it's easy to start Neos with the headset on your head like the
Vhaptics vest is a conscious decision. In fact all the Vhaptics stuff is it's like let's shoot up and get it
All right, I think we're up to date on questions. So if you have any other further questions keep them coming
It's pretty quiet one today, but I'll still upload the recording. I'll try and trim the silence though
It's also awesome to see when you trim the silence how much time is actually spent on the office hours
We're sitting here for 30 minutes. That's the time but maybe once we've trimmed the silence
It's actually 22 minutes and that means who I've saved listeners eight minutes by trimming the silence from my recording
Rafi I see you type in I'm expecting good things. Ah, we already answered that one
I'm not sure if you're here when we did. Thank you for Rafi
Rafi was asking if I had answered a previously asked question and I did no worries
We all need more sleep these days. So wait for another question. I had checked my emails
I know this is nothing to do with you, but I have zero emails. I have no
I'm ecstatic that that is the case. Oh, I just dropped
Yes
Anyway when you question from sorta super who says a question
with all the tools for geometry creation in here
So their plans to implement a material remover of some form or eraser would be wonderful when creating rough drafts of an FBX to export
More mesh editing tools are on our roadmap
I'm not quite sure what like sort of form they'll take something that comes up. A lot is
Terrain generation of the sort of brush kind, you know, and you can sort of like go
Hey this area higher this area lower and also sort of carve through the terrain a little bit
That'll be cool
The tooling there could also probably used for like an eraser when you're using the pen like, you know
When you use the the tube pen
Which is most pens that you use they're just they don't look like tubes because the the dots been trunk small
It would allow you to do an eraser there
You can kind of do that right now, but that's only if you sort of write in a very specific way
You'll be able to just erase portions of it
We have the mesh editing tools. You might be able to erase it like it was an actual, you know pencil on paper
Let's say you draw. I don't know like let's say
H you might be able to just like erase half the H because you put the eraser tool through half the H
Thank you properly linked the topic shoes for those if you want to like see what might be possible
go back through Frixus's Frixus's
YouTube channel and
You'll see that there is a
Video, I don't know what's called. I think it's water water clean is or something like that
It's an earlier version of Neos that was mostly sort of a tech demo for the leap motion that had terrain generation in it
And Griffin is asking for a could we get a separate by loose parts option?
Depends like how that would work. I'd have to look entirely like how the mesh is converted. There's a concept in in
Assimp yeah, okay. It was out of the way, which is what's called sub meshes also exists in the file formats
We use etc. It just sort of refers to like how a mesh is bucketed down
Separate by loose parts in blender does it by
Its internal format as other applications, and that's more sort of like you know if it can see that those vertices are separated
I'm just not sure like like if the data structure is there that we can use. It's certainly a good idea
So hop it over to the github
It's not already there and do double check the static mesh ready because there are a bunch of options there one might function
Close enough like split sub meshes. I thought that was an option which reminds me if you're building stuff in blender
Please rename your objects and make them make sense
I'm so tired of downloading new avatars or new models and open them in blender and like the model is just called like
Cylinder it's like great
So you made this fantastic avatar?
Which I just paid 20 bucks for and you couldn't be bothered to rename the cylinder to body which is anything other than just
Cylinder cube or box or whatever same with hard surface modeling as well
It's so much easier to navigate through let's say. I don't know it's a
architectural piece and
You know I let's say it's a you know conference room
That's an always an easy example like the wall object is called box 22 and the floor is called box 50
There's no rhyme or reason there. You know what it is because you're just clicking it just
It'll be really easy inside
Neos to figure out what if you want to delete or move the walls of the floor and it reminds me of them some shoes
So I don't want to harp too much on sort of you know
People who are not as familiar with the tools that they're using as possible, but I do occasionally find
Usually more sort of like anime starred models where they've got shoes, and they're wearing a particular type of shoes and the reason
They're wearing those shoes because that's the customization they wanted. That's the identity they wanted they wanted those cool shoes
That's fantastic you you've decided the pair of shoes that you want
but then you went ahead and you downloaded an architecturally correct or anatomically correct shoe model and
Brought that into your avatar, and then just glued it to the bone
At that point you have like an a million
polygon shoe
And you go down and I've done this a few times you go down and you realize each individual eyelet for the laceless
That's the the hole what the laces go through on the side of the lacing area of the shoe is
Is like 20 20 K tries itself because it was meant to be a sort of close-up
rendering model for maybe sort of promotional renders of the shoe or to show off the shoe as like a skill of
3d modelism 3d model realism it does feel like I'm griffin says polygon ballast that it does feel like that sometimes
it makes perfect sense like if you're doing sort of like a promotional model for a shoe or
You're testing rendering rather than gameplay design
You render that shoe as many triangles as you want like it's just it's gonna render and it's gonna look cool
And you're gonna get the effect that you want if you're putting that onto an avatar though need to use different
Models different materials it also happened once with I think it was like a wedding ring or something
but you know that was like a VR chat wedding and
Someone was like could you put like a wedding ring on my avatar for me?
And I'm like sure send me the unity package I can sort that out and open it up and then I open up the ring
They wanted on there and again. It was like in a million
Polygon ring I said you realize you're gonna see like 0% of this yeah, but it looks cool and some okay
Let me try and decimate it so I decimated it down and I sent it to them
And they're like it doesn't look as cool now
It's gonna be like a pixel or two on most people's screens, and if you're close up
It's still only gonna be like a tiny square. Yes. That is a perfect representation of the problem
Imagine that a wedding ring or the eyelet of a shoelace. I do have a lot of architectural models as well
Those are interesting because those are made in
architectural modeling applications, they're more designed to be
True to the word what you actually need to build at the building from that
Maybe it will output blueprints
You know that the the foreman for a project will actually look at and build something for
And so the the model format comes out not that optimized for Neos
But the reason why it's not optimized is because it's like extreme detail and this isn't even really in polygons
It's in sort of like all the sort of like gubbins
Just if you're in a building
That's an apartment block like I am walking your stairwell and just like look at everything
I look at the way that like the stairs above you look the stairs below you look
I just like the handrails how they're affixed right because it's an architectural model. They've modeled all of that
And it's just like ah well. It was cool once we were doing a sort of walkthrough of something
we based on one of those models and
The person that was looking at it was like be great if the curtains were open
And I just shot one curtain with a mesh visibility tip because I had a feeling and that feeling was correct
Which was every single curtain was its own object within Neos
and so I shot the curtains with the mesh visibility tip one curtain and
The curtains throughout the entire building just vanished, and it was beautiful. They're just like that was quick
This is really cool, and it like you know showed the power of them sort of using it as a tool for visualization
But I was also scared because if I shot the wrong thing half the building would disappear like if you shoot
generic white wall it might take out like all of the walls because they're all sort of linked together because they want to export the
Mesh into like blueprint layers where it's like you know put up drywall here concrete here stuff like that
I think I just explained the odd interactions
Yoho asked about the odd interactions with those architecturally thingies. Lux has a question which looks to be interesting
So go ahead and read it out for the recording
I have a rather more abstract involved question about data types and inheritance is there a plan to add detailed documentation about how data types
Actually inherit properties from one another on the wiki for a contrived example
I know I collider is probably interface for box collider mesh collider, etc
So with this knowledge I could presumably store just an I collide a data type and store of the derived types into it
It would help to get a more general sense of how all the different types fit together
The answer is yes, but only to an extent there is some
Occurrences, I'm gonna see you so I'm gonna sneeze or is it a sneeze it's gonna disappear. It's it's disappearing okay um
Damn it. I wanted to sneeze um there are some occurrences in that area where you guys are going too detailed
If you're using like sync sync ref field ref you're usually doing really advanced stuff, and I always worry about that
I'm like how can we make that easier for you to do?
Because you shouldn't have to understand the entire sort of object orientated hierarchy of Neos to build something inside Neos
Collider is a good example of a case where you probably should but additionally I would probably want to
Like abstract the whole I collider concept into just a collider data type that
Transparently told you what was going on, but also made easier for people that didn't understand what an interface was programmatically
What I mean by that is like if you pull away all the layers you're basically dealing with raw C-sharp types
But should you have to?
Regardless of that though there will be documentation on that in the future
And they'll also be tooling like I just said to make those sort of easier processes for you
I see some people are just like if I put this like incredibly weird
I know you sometimes have to put weird symbols in various components, but they're like incredibly weird symbols in a component
I can do all these crazy things, and I'm just like that's actually a feature request in disguise
There's no way you should have to do all of that craziness just to get that effect
So yoho if you have a question locks if your question, that's good
Otherwise I want to cut it there as we are nearing the half hour so please go for some paper
If you have a question if not whatever
You have the opportunity
You know I wanted to see the April 1st badges for me
I couldn't get into a session with the limited time I had on yes that day to see them as I am a developer I
Can actually just turn on April Fools mode?
Myself and then run the game, so I'll go ahead and do that and get a picture when I get
Oh, it's otherwise. I think that's it so I will speak to you guys next week look for this to be up on the wiki
Etc later, and I'll get back to you soon. Bye