All right. It is the top of the hour. Let me get this recording started. So welcome
to office hours. This is the top of the hour. We can go ahead and get started. I don't see
any questions right now. So lovely. That's awesome. Quick notice. I was just looking
at the calendar. There will be no office hours on the subsequent two Mondays -- Tuesdays.
So there will be no office hours on the 20th or the 27th. I'm out of the country again.
So next office hours will be in 2023 on the 3rd, which is always like the meme people
do in December. They're like, see you next year. Finger guns, jazz hands. And it's like,
please, like, go home. So, yeah. Everyone has a great holiday period.
But, yes, I will be in various parts of Europe. I've got a pack and stuff. I hate travel.
So we still have no questions. I'm going to go ahead and double check the prequestion
sheet that Nolan uses. Make sure that's empty. It is. It's empty. It's been empty since August.
Oh, we have some good questions. Great. Love it. Good questions. So, switch to English,
please. SHFR says do you have any plans to do a tutorial on the use of evil joints beyond
the simple door hinges? It would depend what I could do. I might do -- so in my public
order somewhere, there's I guess what I would call like a train lever. I don't know if that's
the real name for it. Let me just Google that. Yeah. Like this style thing. I've got two
of them. I've got one that can just free form move. And then I've got one with the sort
of break handle because I wanted that as well. Because that was cool to set up. Yeah. Like
this kind of lever. Of course, a lot smoother and less rusty looking than these pictures.
But you get what I mean. It's like a big lever. I want to make more like tactile physical
like interaction objects for Neos. I think a lot of times we rely on UIX a little too
much and it's just interesting to see. You know, we've got the Japanese community making
like full on planes work. It's like cool. It's also recently concluded, now it's December,
of course, Node-Vember, which is sort of an art thing in November where Glenda artists
just use nodes to make art. And one of them made a shader graph node thingamabob that
did again tactile controls. In this case, like a DJ deck. But they all looked beautiful.
It was like let's get more of these together in Neos. So moving forward to additional questions
there. Lex says I see this field in the world list manager for item template. Do you have
any idea how to use this? This is the component that displays the UI for the world browser.
Yes. Go ahead and take a look at how the world's
run facet works. That actually does overwrite that field. There was a lot of hacky stuff
I had to do there because Neos people can't summon modals. So that's why the modal in
the world is so gross and doesn't fit everything. But that does overwrite that. You're able
to use the item template to change what the world list manager will use when it generates
items. There's also I believe it's called world nexus. That's where I abuse UIX and
physical representation of the open sessions in the form of a circle liner with archways
which are portals which lead to each open session. I thought that was cool. It was sort
of like an art piece, I guess. I think it's like a grassy knoll floating in the sky and
then each archway is an active session. I ran that back when we didn't have that many
active sessions. Maybe in the VR chat boom that would have been crazy nonsense. But right
now it should be quite easy to look at. Moving forward to Zari's question. With you
having recently held a presentation for the Science Edu, I was wondering if there's been
jump offs for projects in the site due to the situation. I know things are usually quite
locked in. One wonders given the bad publicity by such a -- always. Like literally always.
Stuff is always happening in the science realm. Amos is the main science dude that I work
with. There is always stuff going on. So just yesterday we were doing some eye testing stuff.
And today we just booked a surgeon who is coming into today to recreate a surgical case
on actual patient scans. We're comparing it to the output from the non VR, non-Nerus process.
It's just always happening. Sometimes it's not applicable to be shared.
In this case it's real patient data. It's someone's actual face. I can't share screenshots.
But otherwise it's kind of open. Just looking through pictures. Yeah, that's nothing there.
Of course there's also an exposure therapy thingy that we did. I was going to make a
video on that. But then I can totally do that. But yeah, it's always happening. I'd love
to see more of it happen. In some aspects it's a little bit harder to make noise about
Neers due to the current kerfuffle. But in some aspects it's okay. I'd like to be louder
with what Neers can do and louder with what and how Neers can help the area. So I should
do that. But in some cases I'd like the kerfuffle to die down. I'll double check for additional
questions. Another question here from Easton. Hi, Easton. Is it recommended to use a transparent
mirror on the floor to give a nice reflection effect? In my use case the mirror is only
512 by 512 and it looks really nice. If you want to do reflections on floor, a realtime
reflection probe might be better. I'm not entirely sure which would be more heavy. I
guess it would depend if probes render in stereo. Mirrors do. I know you'd have to look.
It would be fine. Some places do that process to get reflections on the floor. They usually
have it on a toggle switch for graphical settings. So make sure that's in place. And just go
for it. There are much better ways to do it. But hey, just go for it. Zach says can I get
a clip of you saying something about cheese? You can indeed. Go to my public folder. Go
to art. Go to cheese. There's a bunch of creations in there where I say stuff about cheese. There's
even a folder where I misspelt cheese. It says he's. There's no C on the front of the
word cheese. He's wisdom. Where I talk about various cursed things about cheese. Oh, hey,
mirrors work better than reflection probes. Go for it. There's really no other way to
do it. If you've done reflection probes and they've formed worse than mirrors, then your
only option is mirror. Make sure it's turn off. You also figure out when you can turn
it off. Do cull that effect. If they're not in the room, maybe the room's still loaded
because you haven't done culling. Turn off the mirror. In a very old map by me called
tea garden, there is actually a slightly opacity, slightly transparent, I guess would be a better
non silly way of saying that, mirror inside the fountain. And that only turns on when
you're really, really close. And it's sort of been tailored there. Lots of people use
the fountain and tea garden as a bath. It's just like it's not what it's meant for. It's
not what it's meant for. Whatever. No one goes there these days. So it's fine. Cool.
That's all the questions we have. So I'm going to sit here and think about cheese. And I'm
going to sit here and sip this tea on mute, of course. Any streams or such planned for
the holidays on news? I'm sure Nexlin will get some stuff sorted. I don't know what their
plans are. I do know this week's stream will focus on creator geometry. So look out for
this month's or last month's creator jam content. Accidentally open linked is completely aside.
Keep typing questions, please. I'm going to ramble. I open linked in. And I'm going to
say there's a bunch of posts there being pushed to me through sort of like recommendations
rather than me following them. And some of them just make me feel ill. I think they're
making a joke here. But there's like a post from someone saying that they cooked dinner
in their hotel room using a kettle rather than charge the company for their dinner.
Even though they could totally charge their company for their dinner because they're away
on a business trip for that company. So charging dinner to that company is the right thing
to do. And they're like, it's the little things that get you promoted. Like, okay, cooking
chicken in a kettle in your hotel room is what gets you promoted? I'm no. Another thing
that really bothers me as well is like everyone saying, yo, I wake up at 4am and like, I don't
know, like, run a mile climb a mountain and do half my work before 9am. This is what you
should do to what they actually mean when they say that is find time in your day where
you don't have distractions. That's all it means. So the reason why they get up at 5am
is because their day is so distractible when other people are awake, so that the health
advice there shouldn't be wake up at the crack of dawn because that's not suitable for everyone.
Some people need more sleep. Some people don't like mornings like I don't. So it should say
schedule time in your day where you have time to focus. That's all it needs to say. It doesn't
need to say I wake up at 4am. I wake up at 3am says the next person who's got like, you
know, a line of supplements they want you to buy. It's just wake up with enough time
for you to do the crap that you need to do during the day. If that's 4pm, Alex, fantastic.
If that's 3am, fantastic. But most of these self help people are like, it's got to be
3am because that's a magic number and let's snort my brain supplements that you can buy
on my blog. It's like, okay, dude, chill. Zari has a filler question, which is absolutely
fine. We don't have any nearest questions. It's just me being angry at LinkedIn. So a
filler question gets me off the LinkedIn approach. So Zari says any thoughts about the U.S. announcing
today that they reached fusion ignition? Getting more energy out of an experiment than they
put in? I'm more excited about that after watching one video on YouTube, which really
isn't that long. And I'm amazed because like it's a really, really good video. It's not
that long. And they literally make fusion happen. So here you go. This is by a channel
called, it is her name, so Cleo Abram, but the series that she's running on there is
a huge if true. And they build a small fuser in Simone's garage. It's not a free energy.
Because it's a small one, it's actually expensive to run. It's like running like a vacuum cleaner
or a hair dryer on full. It takes a lot of energy. It's sucking all the energy out the
wall. But it is doing fusion. And so then the only thing, and I say the only thing,
like it's simple, is for them to do exactly what they do in that video, but get more energy
out than they put in at home. And then like energy is solved. Of course, that's very difficult
to do. And that's why only sort of institutions and governments are doing it. And if you look
at the fusion chambers that they're using, they're like huge and very confusing. But
I learned more about fusion in that 30 minute video than I've done in the past many years,
including education. It's also incredibly pretty. It's just naturally pretty, which
is interesting. Like new power source, naturally pretty. Let's scroll down and look at questions
now. So linker says do you offer CV or resume proofreading for technical Neos users?
That is a skill that I do have and can do. Depending on how many, I would have to actually
charge for that, though. So maybe just for Zlinker, I don't know. But if it's like 200
of you, then it's going to charge some money. I've got to make up my cheese time. Let's
move down and see if we've got any actual Neos questions. We have two Neos
questions. I am awesomely happy that we have two of those. So I've got a question how flexible
is Neos? I think you mean in terms of development, I'm not sure. I'll answer in
terms of development. But please do take the opportunity to clarify that if you would like
to. They're saying let's say you need to modify and think how easy is that to do. That hugely
depends on like what angle it is and how coupled those things are together. When I talk about
coupling, I want you to imagine, you know, those big sort of things that couple electrical
systems together or railway cars together or, you know, chains together. How coupled
things are together is how long it takes to edit. So as an example here, in isolation,
logic nodes are easy. Particularly logic nodes that just do mathematics or operations. So
the plus node, very simple. The minus node, again, the same one minor code. Any of the
sort of avatar related nodes, they start getting complicated because they're coupled to the
avatar system. So then they start getting more and more difficult. There are significant
areas that are very difficult to do. Those ones for me are ones where I have no idea
what's going on because they've got some fruit's magic going in them. Ones that are coupled
very tightly to other systems. For example, there being Twitch. We are aware that the
Twitch integration that Neos has is fragmenting because it's old and it's breaking. Updating
that is the equivalent of basically just rewriting it because we need to move to a new version
of their library. It's a new version of their API and it's just going to be a mess. That
is on my plate to do. That takes a while. But just a logic node, easy. Let's take a
look at the next question. Is there a way for a tool tip to access the label of the
UI element the user clicks on? Find out what text the user clicked on the specter. It depends.
I love that. It does actually depend on what type of text label you mean. There are some
that would allow you to do that. But most wouldn't. What you need there is effectively
component access. In most cases, tool tips, I say in most cases, tool tips can only really
see the slot or the collider that a tool tip is aimed at or clicked on. From that, you
can't get a reference to the label component on that. Be it a text renderer, a piece of
text in terms of UIX or any other variant of how we render text. There's about ten different
ways. You can't get a reference to that. What you need is dynamic component access, whatever
you want to call it. Where you can take a slot and say give me the components on that
slot and I want the first one that looks like text and from that component, I want the text
field. That's a feature we don't have. Hamish has linked a video on how close nuclear
fusion is. I presume Hamish knows more than I do. All I know is those two did it in their
garage and they did explain, hey, this is using more power than it's generating. Alex
says do anyone have an optimized Neos APK build? Ask Xlinka. That's another example of coupling. It's basically
just sort of like how safe is this change? Logics knows usually okay. Logics knows it
should touch other stuff. If a logic node has an impulse going into it, one of those
white ribbons. It's vastly more complicated than the ones that don't. Alex says will the
new YouTube DL be included in the new version of Neos? When we resume updates, lots of things
will happen. Probably that included. I think it says how in trouble if I just dump the
Google drive link here. Probably not. I mean, like, you shouldn't be doing it, but, like,
whatever. Well, I guess the PR friendly version of that would be I don't personally mind.
Other people might mind. So your mileage may vary. With that, I don't believe we've got
any additional questions. I'm just scrolling around, making sure I missed any. By the looks,
things were good. And then that's a third party link. So, hey, it could give you a virus.
It could not give you a virus. I don't know. I'm not validating or anything. Sorry. I had
to answer the door so I will catch up with questions now. It was one of those things
where it's like oh, God, drop the headphones and run. I will take a look at what we've
missed. Another fellow from Zari who says I guess any project you've seen recently that
you're excited about in addition to the aforementioned Japanese community which continues to be scary
creative. Not that I can think of on Neos. I haven't really been on Neos, like, socially
in a while. I've been kind of busy with other things, sorting other things out. I'm always
interested to see what people see and do and make. I'm really interested if it's not a
multi-tool or an avatar or like an inspector or anything like that. So make more games,
make more art, make more, like, experiences and I'll be happy to check them out. I am
starting to think about and get excited by MMC which is coming up in February which isn't
actually that far away. I know it sounds ridiculous that February isn't that far away but it is
not far away. And then we have a question here from Easton who says are there any plans
to improve the storage facet to act more like the cloud storage indicator? You'll have to
explain what the complication there is. They sent a photo and I'm looking at it. Yeah,
so the storage usage status one is probably just like the logged in user whereas cloud
storage space indicator is, you know, for the whatever you want to look up. Make a issue
if you'd like to see advancements in that. Yep, you'll have to make a issue to request
that. We will talk about it. And with that, I don't see any further questions and we are
at the half hour mark. So I'm going to go ahead and end things off here and I will speak
to you guys at the next office hours in the new year. Do feel free to ping me wherever
you'd like, ask questions and I'll get to you as soon as I can anywhere else. It's just
office hours that is stopping until third. Yes, the third. I thought it was the second
for a moment. You know how half the calendars that you have start the week on Sunday and
half of them started on Monday and sometimes you can set that with a setting for other
times you can't and it's really annoying. Yeah, that anyway, I will see you guys again
sometime soon. Stay safe out there. Remember, cheese is good and I'll speak to you later.