Hello, it is now time for office hours. It's the top of the hour, so welcome to office hours for prime
This is primetime if you have any questions, please drop them in the officers chat
That's two channels above the current one that you're in if there are no questions. We'll sit here in silence
Enjoy, have fun. So our first question here is from rampa rampa says
That they're asking if it'd be possible to build a modding reference on the nearest wiki, and if yes
What sort of it's up to you you can put whatever you want on the wiki
People seem to still be under the impression even with the policy that modding is somehow bad. Just do what you want
The important juncture to make though is to make sure that people understand that modding is a choice
And it is not a mandate and I don't believe that people should be
Forced or obligated to mod
And that might happen depending on how we present it and the features that are available in those mods
So just be careful about how the way things are worded
Yeah, that's it really to do what you want. Oh, we should also make sure that you know it's not supported you break something
Neos can't help you
Serum has an interesting follow-up question which is how to make sure that you're not committing a source leak by source leak I
Predict that you're referring to the the EU the wordage about stuff like that
I mean, but depending on what type of documentation or after I probably actually wouldn't suggest the wiki
I'm like technical documentation such as the one that you're describing so header type info stuff like that isn't suitable for a wiki
it would be more suitable for some sort of custom tooling if it's custom tooling that also means you can do what you want over on
the
Neos mod loaders kind of website etc so maybe look into that
Don't I
can't really like
Enforce or common or like say when it comes to the EU though like what isn't isn't available because that's based on the company
And I'm not part of a said company so
Keep an eye on that
My recommendation would be to keep it as like little as possible
Like you can explain modding without too much like Neos source code stuff
But yeah like technical information, which I would call reference type
Which is like you know like hey this variable is of type this this is of type
This isn't suitable for a wiki there are much better tools out there for that
Yeah
All right any other questions drop them in office hours text chat
Which is to about the channel that you're in to enter this office hours segment, and I'll get to them in the order that they appear
For those just joining if you have questions
Please drop them in the office hours text chat that is two channels above the one you clicked to get into this and I'll answer
them in the order that they appear we don't have any questions right now, so we'll sit in
unending
Torment of just silence so Lex has an interesting question regarding a question
I asked yesterday and the questions at help which is I was asking for the
Text that needed to be entered into the attached component menu for a sinker a float which I was what I needed yesterday
So the reason I need to sinker a float
Yesterday was the time
I'm trying to graph stuff and for those who haven't done graphing in nears you need to use a value graph recorder and
a
Rec line mesh or uix rec line mesh. I think it's the same component. Just different wording whatever
Due to layouting those things usually need to be located like distinctly apart from each other
And so I have a list of configuration objects which define like what the graph should look like
Which are separate from the graphing area and so I need some way to link those across
across slots now of course
Everyone will say like you know dynamic variables would be great for that, but like hey
I need a dynamic variable a reference to a sinker a float
So that I can write it into the value graph recorder. It was like
Fun, I think there's a way to do it now
I have the appropriate component hierarchy like text available, but like I gotta like
Figure out what I want to do there. I also need to do like a tiered
Like a delete eating so when you delete the graph entry it will be like all right
I deleted the graph entry cool. I can hop over to the graph area and also delete the the graph that's on the other side and
That that should be fun. I can do that with like some dynamic variables that are slots because that's easy
But I don't know if I I might even need to do like the sink ref sinker a I'll take a look at the next time
I've been
Moving onwards we have another question from book sure who says is there a way to override or add up to an avatars?
I can't a mission another animation like some other time. I have a different way of walking compared to what procedure walking has yes
I'm so glad you asked because so many people ask about this
Um all of the walking animations in years are procedural, and they are editable by you
You just need to know where to look
Inspect the root of your avatar and find I can ever remember if it's on vRak or vRak avatar or whatever
But just like those those components
They'll be list of things called gates gates control
How you walk and they are entirely procedural and you can define all sorts of stuff like how big a step is
so if you increase the step size you get to sort of a
A march which German soldiers did around world war two called goose stepping
It's kind of sort of like frowned upon to do that sort of thing because you know
It's reminiscent of those troops back then but other military people do do it as well
All right, here's a picture. Yeah, it looks like lots of military to it
I just remember it being like overly associated with Nazis, so I don't usually mention it anyway um
Hey
so if you edit the
if you edit the
Gate settings, and then you'll end up with all sorts of stuff. This is who is this China?
This is the Chinese military doing that kind of march you know where their foot is is reaching unnaturally far forward
So you can totally control that in the gate that would probably be in the feet range because that's the range which your feet move
I you want to go through and document
All of those properties actually you know they are but they are quite cool
I do know the speed ratio if you increase that that's the number of steps that occur
And so if you made that really high you'll basically end up looking like a jackhammer right your feet
Or just constantly be like clapping on the floor
So so take a look at those play around with them my best recommendation for you is to remove all of them
So except one and then change the milling velocity on that one to be
Just zero so it always applies and then play around with that one the reason why there are multiples depending on the velocity is because as
you increase in speed your
Your stance to change if you think of a horse a horse goes through several gates as they speed up
She holds gates like a really interesting like thing topic to read about but
That's for another day. I've ridden a horse once
It's a wikipedia article about goose stepping. It is stupid. It is incredibly inefficient. Do not goose step
I don't know why they do it. It's impressive. I guess and can be very synchronized
All right moving around to questions someone said I missed one, so I'm gonna head hump for that one. Oh yes
I miss specs question
specs asked
I'm working on some monitoring stuff ahead this and there's much public variables related to time for sessions like average update time last update time
Do you know if these are measured in nanoseconds or milliseconds or something like that?
I have no idea
Usually our unit is like seconds because we use a float and then fractionals of that second or then milliseconds
But I don't know I'd have to look jump it up and down to came out races questions
So dre says easiest place to get a good help start the logics besides just picking up the logic starting
Honestly pick up the logic step and start I don't on my channel have any sort of beginner or introductory videos to logic
But I know that other channels do basement note has a very good video about just getting started
Something which I will encourage you to do is to just do stuff and not worry about it a lot of stuff
I do with people is to encourage them to just laid out
Nodes and not really worry what they're doing a lot of people like are they I want to use logics to make you know
Half-life Alex to well that's a bit of a stretch
You don't know logics or they'll go like I want to make this really complicated gun and like well
That's a bit of a stretch
Why don't you try adding two numbers together and then go from there right make logics?
That doesn't really have a function outside of your learning, and you'll get a lot better there also forget
Well, you know about all programming
Logics just isn't programming people like is it like C sharp, or is it like Java and I might know
It's just logics like it's it's it's often better to just forget what you already know and just learn it from scratch
Rampers is would be possible to get to try and brace don't create some sort of guidelines
What what would enforce modding docs from an approved shareable Intel for about from the team side is an appendix to the modern policy
I'm still not sure what you're on about here like
You can't share of course decompiled code. That's against the Euler you can't
Share stuff that breaks the guidelines right or come after you about that, but anything else you should be fine
I look at all the source codes for all the mods, and I'm like that's fine. I
Don't know it's like I don't know like I wouldn't be able to write a guideline or a policy against that because I don't know
What what you need I don't understand if I'm the correctly or not
But like I think going back to gates for a second an unoccupied avatar will still match the gates when you move it
and so something I've experimented with doing is putting a
an avatar on the floor so that their feet are touching the floor on an axis panner and then varying the speed of axis pattern
Sometimes that will show the gates about you being in the avatar. Just kind of cool
I did have a world that was looking to make that into a tool
It's gonna be called like on a gate editor right and you would like sort of load your avatar into I guess a treadmill
And then you would set the speed of the treadmill and watch how the feet work
But I don't particularly know if that works or what state that will be in
A trace follows up their question learning logics with there's some people going to very nitty-gritty of it. Yeah, that's problematic
Don't let them do that. Um, I see a lot of people that like, you know, they'll inspect logics nodes
So they'll talk about performance or worrying about nodes or say hey don't use this or don't use that
Every single logics node that exist is designed to be used by you
So if anyone tells you not to use anything particularly whilst you're learning don't listen to them. Just you use it
I don't advise they also talk about dress talks about starting with gestures
I don't advise gestures like I don't advise learning learning logics via gestures. You'll just give yourself a headache
I want you to learn logics not how to build something. So layout nodes look at the things look at the
way that things work
Another very important thing is to get your vocabulary down
I know a lot of people who are quite proficient Neos users, but when I use vocabulary
they're like that's not what you call that and I'm like it it literally is you can like
Inspect to the thing and that's what it's called. So I don't know what you're saying. Like as an example, you should know what the words
node
interface card
relay
reference arrow drive
impulse
Ribbon, you know all these words mean an addition should also know what the word primary secondary in context means
Everyone's like there's so many controls in here. So don't know which button to push about this three primary secondary in context with you
That's it
Primary secondary context. That's it. We technically is grab as well. But like grab is such a visceral one that people get it. I
Don't know cuz like I haven't had any family close to my VR headsets in many years
But I remember, you know trying to teach my mother to play Grand Theft Auto
It's a funny story and you know
There's tons of buttons on like an Xbox controller or whatever and she just doesn't know which one is to go
And I'm like that one on the right hand side that feels like a trigger
That will make you go and she got it right because it's such a tactile experience. I believe the same there is it's true for
Grab, right? It's grab the controller and you grab stuff
Yeah, primary secondary context menu grab those are the only things you need to learn in terms of controls and once you know those you
Could also learn packing as well
so many people like worry about like red prints and blueprints and
orange prints and pink prints and whatever the hell else you want to call it pack and
Unpack stuff just practice it make some shitty ball chicks that does absolutely nothing
Like I don't know adds two numbers together
Pack it into a box save the box geometry bring the box out unpack it do that like 17 times
You'll never have questions about packing again
If someone floats over in the middle of you learning logics and they're like, oh you can do that better another way if you use components
Bap them on the face of a breadstick and tell them the prime told you that that's a bad thing to do
Cuz I know it's not happening a lot. Well, you could do that better
Oh one, please for those who are unaware. This is a bad thing to do
If you are not editing the logics or helping someone with the logics
Please do not insert your avatar into the logics. I've had people fall asleep inside my logics
They come into the session. They hang out with me. They're chatting to me
Parts of their avatar are intersecting my nodes and then they fall asleep and it's like, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Get out of my logics
All right, I gotta catch up questions rather than talking about either you stepping or learning logic some more. It's good luck
Yeah, Ruthie has a question cool
Or she says are there any automated methods for re-enabling those that have gone red in ham radio world?
We're finding that web socket and downstream nodes are going red often with service inundated something like a world save or avatar loading
I wonder if this way to reset without putting out the logics of finding
There's no automated way to do it. There are ways to prevent it from happening. So usually those nodes would go red because
There is an influx of data or the nodes being called too many times
So and I know it sounds stupid, but just don't do that
So like there are various ways to do that
But you need to kind of figure out a way that will enable those nodes not to become swarmed
something which you should remember when it comes to live data, which you mentioned via web sockets as well is that if the
if the logic system is is struggling to keep up
make sure that you know what the
Lifetime or the like the lifetime of a single message coming through is as an example here that that is probably relevant
When the heart rate system that uses web sockets it talks to a bluetooth heart rate monitor
Which speaks your computer opens up a web socket server sends web socket messages to
Neos and then you just like your heart rate in your name badge the size of like mount Vesuvius and I get really annoyed
but anyway, your heart rates like the size of a mountain on top of your head and
Every couple of seconds the web socket is going. Here's my heart rate. Here's my heart rate
Here's my heart rate if you are struggling
Or the no system is slowing down or whatever
I'm like it's okay to skip some messages because you've always got the next message coming through that gives you information about
What your heart rate is so you don't need to process every single message
You just need to process as many messages as you can so there is an opportunity to drop some of the messages
So do keep that in mind. We did that a lot during racing
Of course like so I used to do racing software, and it's very complicated
But so we had like a master controller, and it was running the race it knew who was first to a second etc
But it would regularly send out those updates to view displays around sort of the race circuit and the track to be like you know
this person's winning and those would get overloaded because sometimes this like
300 bikes on track and it's really complicated and so we would drop packets right because we always knew the next
Available status was coming out, so we would drop them and be like it's okay
It can be invalid for like a split second whilst the next update comes
Let's not stress out about like you know doing that we also see that
Cmdr. Does that you know they drop frames OBS does that when you're streaming it drops frames, right?
It's just like it's okay sometimes to just throw out some data if you don't need it moving onwards
Deception says what's going on you're all currently in the office house ama from prime to ask about near stuff
so ask some questions in the office hours channel that you're typing in and
I'll answer them Gina says any plans for new logics knows a logical improvement. Yes
but
Rampers says and this is a pop to their previous questions, so that let's let's let's get into it
Let's rub my hands together. I'm not sure exactly how to formulate this baby remember someone's saying something a lot along the sign along sort of
Cool tongue-tied there
Someone said something along the lines of I don't feel comfortable discussing this stuff you want to look for and
Mod in modding discord do it in DM
So don't get to problems or at least something like that
What I say is I feel there should be some guidelines saying as long as you don't say too much about this you're not
Okay, written by freaks himself disagree
I'll answer that in a moment that essentially all hits back to the modding policy X you late
Contradiction the thing that we discussed many times is how I feel about it ah
Fricks doesn't have to write everything whenever you see the word fructs. I want you to replace it with Nias the company
I know there's issues in announcements etc, but just replace it with Nias the company like seriously
It's like well fructs needs to do that
No, Nias the company needs to do that if fructs is actually the person that needs to do it fine
But let's remove the word fructs from the vocabulary
That's what we did when we wrote the modding policy the security policy all the rules all the guidelines etc
Those are written by Nias the company or Nias's moderation team or prime
Because it takes the emphasis off freaks needed to do everything right if I need to speak to fructs to get whatever I need written
I will and he read and reviewed both the morning policy and the security policy before it was released to anyone
That's totally fine. It doesn't need to be written by him
That's I gotta be in my bonnet about that because it's like from the old days
It was just like well fructs needs to do that. No anyone can do that
Anyone can do that
We can't do that till we resolve that eeler modding policy contradiction what I will say to you though is
Maybe keep the morning discussion to the modding discord, and if it's in the modding discord. It's your guys's discord
We have no purview to say don't do that there if we get reports or tickets about the EULA being contradicted over there
It's I don't know what will happen because it's like off-platform and sort of out of our purview and the modding policy says it's okay
To do but like I still don't understand the issue at play here
People shouldn't feel that modding is bad or that modding is against the rules. We have a policy that says it. It's okay
So just do it question mark. I don't understand. It's probably situational
Depending on an individual thing just because I see
Realms of a another topic here. I don't want to touch on it as well. I see like the oh
There might be problems if we do this if you are worried about problems occurring because you do X ask
Dropping a ticket. It's okay to drop in a ticket and be like I am going to blow up the moon
Will I be modded you know have mod restrictions against be on on Neos if I do that perfectly okay ticket go for it
Let us know what you're worried about. I can't stand people saying like oh, yeah guys
There's rumors and the rumors are bad the last time someone said that to me
We took it to DMS, and I'm like those aren't rumors and none of them are bad or security related at all
So just just keep that in mind
So recio now says what method would you recommend for dropping those sets of impulses off the web socket receiver local impulse timeout?
Yeah, probably local impulse timeout. You could also use some sort of queuing system
which of course you need collections for but
local impulse timeout once per frame
Local leaky impulse bucket I have to say that very carefully because some friends of mine have a
less than professional nickname for it
I
Would speak of
You could also look at like how often the data gets duplicated from your end on the server as well
So if your server is constantly sending the same data every like second
Maybe up it to every two seconds, and then you've you've you've halved your data load right you've half the bandwidth also consider polling as well
I've noticed tonight. I don't know anything about your scenario, so I don't know if this is the case, but I've noticed a lot of people
Confuse HTTP nodes and web sockets, and they're just like you have to use web sockets for everything, and I'm like no no
Like the world uses HTTP. We don't all use web sockets a good example here might be
Let's think about let's think about discord actually so when you load discord first thing in the morning
And I'm not sure exactly works like this
But hey this is how I would do it when you first load discord in the morning
It will do a HTTP request to discord and say give me the history of the office hours channel
And you'll get all that history down and then when you're connected and you're synced up
To that it'll then use web sockets or something similar to that to get new messages so they get them live
But it's constantly doing HTTP requests right it's like everyone's like no. I got a bit of sockets
I'm like well, just just just trust me here HTTP sometimes better
Moving forwards deception ask what's new is his favorite food. I don't know you'd have to ask news
Dre says some time ago
I was accidentally crashed out you to unload video play again deleted
I'm home with crash force news to say for changes and all the untidy mess at my home world in that point in time
There's a way to prevent the forced over saving in case one of the crash
Not currently um I do have some recommendations, which are don't use your home worlds
I know that sounds kind of strange, but like I don't use them
My home was a jump points. I've got like
World orbs to various projects. I'm doing all sorts of stuff like that
I do that to avoid the problem that currently exists
We do have some open get up issues about sort of what to do their settings. Maybe tweaks settings
Conflict stuff like that that might help
But until then I just I don't recommend using them like my home world is literally like how to get to somewhere else quicker or
The space which I like hang out in last I'm waiting to join another world
You can even like put something in your home world which is like a big button
That's like open my actual like hangout world right and then when you don't you're just like
Click the button opens the world does it all for you and that way you're not right really missing any of the stuff like that
You know I've got like two bookshelves left bookshelf is in progress right bookshelf is
finished but sort of reference
There has been like a
Roman amphitheater
style thing
About 20 units to the right of where my home world starts for about a year now
And I just keep forgetting to leave it that just leaves there
I was gonna make it into a world, but then I kept forgetting and now it's just kind of there. It's strange
I don't really know why I
forgotten to do it, but
Yeah, it's something like like like this
But it's just like sat there in my whole world somewhere and just sat there doing nothing
Moving forward so Risi has more information about the web socket stuff
The you're doing it to get the RF level okay cool any changes from the server are sent
But they're sending a maximum of 20 updates per second is kind of important to receive this many updates
We can get real-time information on what we are receiving to the other end of the radio connected in real life. Yeah, um
At that point. I probably just have to look at the node set up
There's probably something you're doing somewhere that can be improved to prevent red nodes. There's a particular area. That's reading out
Think about how you can restructure it such that the data coming in from the web sockets is isolated from the rest of the system
For example you might write that RF level to a dynamic variable and then pick it up elsewhere
And then you've like you've ended your impulse chain very quickly like you received the RF level you write it to a dynamic variable
You're done. You're done, and then nothing else happens in that particular impulse chain. That's another thing
I want people to do when they learn logics as well as pack early and
Impulse chains early like it's always better to have more than one impulse chain than have an impulse chain
That is like the size of the planet
It's like and then we do this and then we do that and then we do this and then we do that and then
We do this and then we do that okay
Maybe just like chuck in a dynamic impulse receiver in the middle there
So you don't have to like keep doing stuff on the same chain
Another good way to look at it is when people talk about sort of multi-threaded asynchronous programming things like that
They're very complicated
But just think about it this way if there is a break as in between impulse chains it gives time for the computer to like
Catch up right so you're doing hey. I'm doing this impulse chain
I'm gonna stop and immediately trigger using whatever method you want to trigger another impulse chain cool
But in the split second between one impulse chain
Finishing and another impulse chain starting it gives chance for the logics engine to be like ah cool
I can relax a little bit. I can chill out right so it's a more
Uncommon to see red nodes in that case properties providing some information about dot opening the cloud home
I like that I use it because it's like has lots of links in it
But I don't put video players or anything like that, and it's like a mirror and some world orbs
Moving forward to other questions just check you haven't missed any
Specs has a question here speaking of home was I'll try to set my local headless server as a session
I auto-join when I start up nears
I tried using the documented command line parameters
But didn't seem to have any luck to have a working example of what using auto-join parameters looks like I don't have an example
I would highly recommend using the custom session ID stuff for headless
Because that's really cool, and that should be a little bit easier to launch into but I don't have a specific example
Ozi has a question which is a good question is a nice way to write is there a nice write-up on how nears is data
Model works during how nears think things that the players know
I know the hate tree was working in one for like how logics works which is kind of interesting
But that I don't think they buy published it yet. They're still working on it
I
want to
Hate mentioning this again, but I do want to caution people
Some of that stuff should be invisible to you
Like if there's like a lot of times feel like you know how do I use like an I feel?
Bracket sync ref bracket sync bracket sync sync sync, and I'm just like what are you doing stop?
Like you shouldn't use that lower level part of the engine you should use something above that to do what you need to do
and
That can be a case there when you're looking too much into the data model and how it works
like if there is a problem, that's a better question, so I'm just making sure that that question doesn't hide a
Problem behind that question, and if it doesn't that's totally fine, but if it does make sure you're asking the question the course
The chain of thought to lead up to generally how the data model works because you shouldn't ideally need to know how it works
moving down to
Gina what logics projects you want to see people make more of I want you see people make more of not multi tools
Not avatar gesture systems if you're making anything other than those two things
Fantastic just go ahead and do it
games
experiences artwork
science
Data visualization
All sorts of stuff like that. I don't need to see another multi-tool
Don't build blueprints either. I see what a lot of people do is they're making tools to make stuff like I am making
a hammer to hammer some nails and making a screwdriver to screw in some screws
What I want to see is what are you building? Oh, I'm building a bird box great. I want to see more bird boxes
I don't want to see more hammers if that makes sense those tools are great, but I
I've lost count of the amount of people that join my session, and they're like hey prime
Can I show you the multi-tool? I'm working on and I just go
No
Hard to not be rude about it, but like I've seen enough. I don't need to see any more multi-tools. Thanks
Rosie follows up this is it's just curiosity because I know how half it works
Yeah, understood. Yeah, I'm just making sure sometimes
I've seen people that are like how does logics work or like how does locomotion work?
And then I ask them some more questions, and I find out there
They're trying to do something that's that's solved with a logic node or a component that they haven't realized exists
moving forwards to dresus question
other way anyways in
Logics to essentially take your rotation of a bone and tell another bone to imitate the rotation and use some multiply map to tell
It to use any part of the rotation. Yes. I don't know it though um
We have a full mathematical engine for quaternions
We also have some shortcut mathematics like look rotation inverse rotation from to rotation axis angle stuff like that
But it's all hardcore maths you need to understand the maths about it
a good example here being and I do this on a 2d plane just because
2d is what I know I was once many many many years ago making a 2d space shooter. You know and
The enemy ship was going to fire a missile at the player ship
And I'm like well
how do I make the missile rotate such that it faces the the player ship and then moves towards it and
I'm like oh, let's figure this out. Let's try and do it, and I did lots of research, and I figured out hey
It's just maths the a 10 to operator will do that for you it will
Take the I never remember how to use I have to look it up every time
I know like I just google a 10 to I'll figure it out
But you get the x and y of a thingy and you plug it in and it gives you an angle
And then you rotate the ship to the angle or the missile to angle and it's aimed directly at the player
And then you move it there. That's a good example where I'm just like cool. That's that's all my problem thumbs up
That's sold my problem
gun Griffin or Kip says a
Note to self make a bird box hammer. Yeah, remember the there's a
Diy sort of like wooden furniture world that was one of the MMC entries. That's beautiful right? That's a good example
Hey, there's lots of stuff. You can do there if you made like just
Like a two by four with nails that you could hammer in and then maybe a ray-set button that brings the nails back up
To their non hammered in height. I love that lots of people do I like that people like the tactile tools
you can make and
With that or actually over time by a lot so rampa and kip if you have a question
Please feel free to finish typing otherwise no more questions
Okay, we have too many work two more questions
So rampa says is it possible to create a copy button on a user-made creation?
Facet world copy is in clipboard copy it is
People do it kind of in a hacky way they use
the light control C control V multi-key thing
Where basically they fake it like it's one of our keyboards, but it isn't one of our keyboards
There is like a problem in that because it's sort of
difficult to do understand and explain
I'd like to see a way to do it that had like maybe you know a defined way of doing it
We could also put more security into that way for example
like we could have a saying allow logics to access my clipboard which would default to off because that sounds like a terrible move or
Maybe like it defaults to only allow like put stuff in your clipboard, but it can't read the clipboard
I don't know if we put a system in place that was more controlled there. We can add
protections around that but yeah right now virtual multi-key control C control V
It's difficult usually need to do control a control C control V
Take a look at any of the cloud spawners that exist. I believe there's one in red print
it's one in a bunch of the the JP stuff and
It's not like backpack thing the JP have I forget what it's called
I'm actually sort of have like a radio menu that can spawn stuff from a public folder. It's cool
moving onwards to the next question
In an effort to make a robust mesh to mesh touch detection system
Can you sample the color of a pixel on an intersect material to detect if a mesh is intersecting near it?
I don't know
That appears to be what I call the empirical question
Which is please go ahead and try it and let me know what your result is I think it should work
But like I'm not sure what you're trying to do, so I probably wouldn't like say do that depends
What you're trying to do like I'm then seeing Ozi respond with like hey use cameras
And like if you're just trying to collide why not like use colliders
How do people not use colliders? Yeah deformed mesh?
Collider probably might not match up sometimes
So to break it to you there like you're never going to get like a mesh collider with a deformed mesh working correctly
I would strongly recommend you go after the
procedural colliders which are placed within an avatar's hierarchy
And if it's a custom mesh with a rig add to those procedural meshes
So a good example is if you look at your hand your hand as a box collider on it
Which represents the sort of square that is your hand your arm has a cylinder on it because it's a cylinder
And that is what you should be colliding with you shouldn't be colliding with the actual mesh that is
fraught with difficulties if you want to use a camera with that or
The sample color node of it good luck. I think it'll work. I would just question the the sanity in doing that so
Last question at all from from dre says it's possible to have a custom spawn point for your an avatar or work around to
Make it seem like you spawned on your desired point
Yeah, you can do like if you do like on like go to flow events and then use on start
On start it gets triggered when the like the system that you're loading in like avatar object
Whatever like starts up like it's a defined event
And so you can trigger on star and then I would wait like I don't know a second or two and then teleport yourself
I would question again
Why you need to do that usually when you load into a map the spawn point that you're given is
Tailored to the the map creator good example here being if you're in I don't know a parkour map
You would want the player to spawn at the start of the parkour
Map and not at the end of the parkour map
Yeah, you could if you're just teleporting to someone just just teleport to them just jump to them you can even put like
this is a great example of
The xy problem, so we'll go over a little bit more to explain it so your problem dres was
Losing friends in a world and your solution was change spawn point. You should have asked about your problem
Which is getting back to friends in the world rather than your intended solution, which has changed spawn point
So now that we know that your actual problem is losing friends. There are better ways to do that which are
The jump menu in the session menu or a context menu or whatever you want inside your actual avatar
Which will give a list of players in the session and teleport you to them like you can make a custom context menu
Which does you know a ring of all the players in a session and then when you click on that button it can teleport you
To that's that's quite easy to do yeah
They will they want to jump to us. You know a point not on top of your friend
You'll probably want to take the position of your friend
Go out a radius from that and teleport to there and so you take the position of the friend you
Add a radius to that and then you teleport to that you again. You can do that with maths
I would probably take their
Their position and then add their left or right vector to it and a little bit
And that will make you spawn to the left or right of them
By a little bit you'd also do forward or back, and then you'll appear in front of them or behind them
Which is both scary hence why it's just left or right because then that's not scary
I need to do more videos on the the left right up down toward backwards nodes because they're amazing and no one uses them
We are totally out of time, so I'm gonna go ahead and kill things off here
Thank you for your questions today
If you have any follow-up questions feel free to direct message me at any time or attend another office hours section if you have any
questions about
Moderation related matters, please remember you can just open up a ticket if you're confused. You're unsure open up a ticket
We can get back to you there
Otherwise keep reading the wiki keep reading the announcer's channel, and I will see you next time. Bye. Bye