All right, so we'll get started it is primetime the office hours AMA segment where I answer your questions and
We'll get started do any questions that appear last questions are
Not here. I will just sit in unimaginable endless silence whilst I check tracking for a parcel that is going all the way to Tasmania.
Really? I got that check information off to the Lord bucket head says how has my day been so far?
I really also like personal questions, but since questions are kind of dry. I'll go for it. Oh, yeah good
I have a giant mug of tea, but I'm gonna go ahead and and chug and
On the rest of my day. I guess anyway um
after office hours at least
Moving forwards to unnamed cyborg cat who says is Neos ever going to be finished yet
I don't think Neos will ever ever be finished
unlike games which are
Like real games like Neos is is always going to be ever-growing
Once we get through all this stuff
Let's think of an example here
I take the the latest Legend of Zelda game right that has a defined start point and end point and yeah
There could be DLC of course that could be DLC
But there is a defined start and end point where that game will just not require any additional work whereas we have a metaverse
that's going to need additional work until the end of its existence as a reminder for those who have just joined or run away please drop
questions in the
Thread that we have up in the office hours text chat. I'll answer them in the order that they appear
If there are no questions, I will sit here in silence until
Questions appear just the nature of office hours
Whilst I wait for questions. I'm gonna go ahead and push another couple of buttons to make sure that a
parcel appears at
my house
Scheduled package, please arrive today. Excellent. Oh
We have a question from Risa. Thank you Risa says another cjism
We've been having more world performance issues namely the lockups
We feel when avatars load in what we've noticed is that saving allowing the world to reload often clears this up when the same number
Of users are present in the world as typically buyers a few hours
Before we need to save and reload again any thoughts on what we could be causing the performance to degrade over time until they restart
Um
Potentially unused assets have you like does the cg worlds have the cleanup unused assets checkbox enabled on their sessions?
That that might help that's really the only thing I can think of that would be like people loading in and loading out
They do. Okay. Yeah
interesting to sort of monitor that I guess
My public folder somewhere. There's like the world health thing
I wanted to make it like a huge thing in the end. I just had two accounts the
Direct children of the roots law and the direct children of the assets law and and seeing if that goes
Up and down throughout the session might be a sort of indicator if cleanup unused assets is working
And then I don't really have any other ideas unfortunately right now. We have two additional questions here from Marcus
Thank you for this first question. Why do you like news? I don't actually know
I know that like, you know a team member should have like a really good answer here. That's like
Businessy and like, you know, if it's the like energy of the company
but I don't I
Like it. I don't know why
Yeah
Sorry, I'll get a words on that one. Oh
Then the second question is what would be some things to say to someone to try to get them to check out
Neos with me
Firstly make sure you're not
Guess like bullying is the wrong word nagging nagging would be a good word
Make sure that nagging them like some people are just happy what they're what they're doing
You know, they're happy in there. There are applications and they're happy
Not having a you know, boiling screen strapped to their face. So do keep that in mind
Don't don't pester people if they've said no a few times anyway, um
without the way
The focus on what you can do but also what you can experience a lot of times
I see players focusing on what you can do and that's where a session might turn into sort of like Gary's mod style session
And to that point you can do Gary's mod style stuff on Gary's mod
You can also do Gary's mod style stuff on many many games. For example, if just playing around with guns go play h3vr
if it's just
Goofing off then Gary's mod, even VRChat covers that rate show them what is unique about Neos
Take them on a world tour show them the community and how helpful they are
Also, try not to make their first session as about avatars as like it needs to be
Because they want to feel comfortable in their avatar
But like maybe suggest
Using one of the already uploaded avatars so they can get a feel of the game before they spend like four hours uploading their avatar
The first time because it will take them a while. Um, that's worked quite well for some people
I think it was like a friend once who resolved
I don't know
They were the first person I saw that idea from they came in to sort of see what Neos is about
And I sort of asked them if I wanted, you know, they wanted help him point in their VRChat avatar
And they went you know what? No, just just give me an avatar
That's like close enough to the avatar and show me what this can do
I'll worry about my avatar later and I really appreciated that sort of perspective on how they wanted to play the
Play Neos because it means that they didn't
They didn't spend their first session like EDP and inspectors. They fit the first session
Learning what we had to offer in the event that they have their avatar created and updated and stuff like that
It gave them more reason than later to get their avatar in
Lex's question here, which is I've noticed more frequently in the past months
The S variant servers either get stuck or stop entirely with no indication of uses
Except for broken textures and shaders. What would be a good way to find these specific users to notify the team?
Um, we have pretty good notification on that one from the QC team
More is always welcome. Of course. I am actually starting to mean that a little bit with a days since asset server
whole
Image, which I'm gonna get set up somewhere
but
You can usually see it in
in the logs as a failure on a particular like
On a particular gather job usually for like new shader files or something like that if they can't be got
Then then that's usually the problem if you see an increase in things turning pink randomly. That's also an indicator for
That happening as well
Yeah, C's link has got it. I get kind of annoyed about that one. Obviously we're a little bit stuck because we can't you know
do much about that, but
I
want to like
There's like
There's a whole class of like computing and engineering that happens at like big companies called observability
So observability is a little bit different than development observability just means sort of like what is happening?
What is happening?
And so large companies large corporations
They invest a lot in observability just so that they can see stuff and this actually goes like sort of beyond or tangential to data
Science where it's like, okay what data insights can we get about our users? This is basically just like what is happening?
Show me what's happening. And so getting more observability on the asset process
Processing for the team will allow us to do stuff like that. Now. I have worked for many corporations
Where you know if stuff goes wrong someone gets a phone call. I don't think we need that
Um, but we do need somewhere that like alerts us to it. I
mean probably a
But you know, like we'll see what we can do. Um
I'm not quite sure why that keeps happening, but it's about once a month and it bothers me. It bothers me. Um
Let's move onwards
A follow-up is a plan to move asset variation generation and uploads back to the client at some point. Clients do do some of it
But that's certainly an option that we wanted to look at
We also want to look at sort of more peer-to-peer style things and people get sort of like worried or concerned when I say that
but it's basically just like
hmm a
Friend of yours which happens to live like the next town over has the assets for this particular session
Maybe they can give them to you rather than you going to a server that's on the other side of the country. Maybe
just say
So that would also help in that regard because what that would mean is like hey
Maybe the asset variant like server doesn't have that particular thing all up-to-date, but hey, maybe someone in the world does
Windows Defender took action on threats. What's good on Windows Defender? What did you find?
Oh, Windows Defender is telling me that my hosts file has a lot of entries in it that it finds suspicious
Yeah, I think so and does be blocking all the track as you have is is that's totally sus
Thanks for letting me know windows
It's like you put stuff on your host file of my yeah, that's what it's for
All right. I'm not seeing any more questions
Ozi asks, what is a funny near Smith you see going around recently?
I think I actually edited the myth page out of sort of like anger the other day. Let me go see what I what?
I added but look at the history
Yes, yes
Apparently Neos is an airline in Italy. Yeah, I don't remember making that issue
This one is referring to
So like there are a couple that keep that keep coming up recently one is that Neos isn't multi-threaded to that
I say go to your debug screen and just play Neos without open. You'll see background worker threads. You'll see background threads
You'll see all sorts. Lots of stuff is multi-threaded. Another one is the
If you're in a session Neos users can access your hard drive. The answer is no they can't
So great, thank you for spreading that rumor
We keep getting
Let's just say the you know, the crypto community keep coming in and they keep saying is this project dead
It's like ha well
like one of the team member is like here every single week for half an hour talking to you guys and then on
Wednesdays and on Fridays we have the streams and then like hey those moderators that we've got
They've been burning those capture bots all the time
If it was dead
this place would just be a wasteland would be covered in capture bots and family servers and
weird OnlyFans advertisements and fake Elon Musk's I
I have seen so many fake Elon Musk's like they're all over like YouTube shorts tik-tok YouTube reddit
It's basically just like them deep faking sometimes good sometimes bad
deep fakes of Elon going like buy this crypto currency
Crazy anyway, yeah, so if it was dead, I wouldn't be here talking about Elon Musk deep fakes
other ones that come with like the sort of like
Weirdness in some of our features being similar to features and other platforms
For example, people assume dynamic bones on Neos is the same as dynamic bones elsewhere. It is not
It's our own
Own implementation, which means that for Neos, it's it's better
Like I'm not gonna say it's like better than fizz bones or better than the original dynamic bones. That's not for me to qualify
It's better for Neos because we own it. We don't have to pay anyone for it
It is compatible with all our stuff and it will get any improvements that we make to Neos because of that
Additionally like nothing else on Neos
That you use as a feature needs to be paid for like you only pay for storage
And yeah, there's the end this client and stuff like that
But like you want to build like an you want to build the next Legend of Zelda and Neos there is nothing
But like there is nothing you need to pay for
Provided it stays under one gigabyte. Yeah, you know, I mean there are no features
moving forwards to
Exos what's the recommended amount of dedicated WAM I have the server we have
recommended system specs listed on the steam page for the steam for like the the head head full
I'll see opposite of headless heady the one with the head non headless
What is the opposite of headless
head
containing a head anyway for that we have that on the steam store page and
for
For headless there's lots of conversation in the headless client
I don't think we provided any official recommendations there simply because the headless client is still in air quotes
in
Testing you're sitting on an early access game in beta. So like, you know, everything's in testing. But yeah
Foxbox asks when is a good time to clear your cash other than windows thing if you're out of storage because Neos has 150 gigabyte
Yeah, that just happened today for me
unlike I
Mean some of you might be like this. I'm like you though
I've got like four versions of Neos that run on my computer. So they've all got varying degrees of
Cash stored on them, which is is cool. So I need to go through and do that. Um,
A schedule might make sense, which is what the V T
Oxalis says, um, I don't think a schedule makes sense
Maybe another does I kind of do it based on?
Sort of like who I'm interacting with as an example. I haven't been to create a jams in a couple of weeks
That's not because I don't want to go to create a jams. I just haven't had the chance
So I probably have a lot of creative jammy stuff in my cache that I can clean out. That's it like
Small example, but it might be like a you know, a bigger example that might be useful. I guess might be
Let's say VBL FC happens again, right? So you go to VBL FC that means that you've got the entirety of the VBL FC
convention center hotel
Rooms in your cache and then anyone that attends you've got in your cache and then after VBL FC
You go back to your private world to work on your custom inspector or multi-tool. You don't need
VBL FC in your cache anymore. So you might want to clear out at that point
Git asks or inspired using threads for office hours and do you find that helped out?
That would be
Eastern came up with the idea and I think it helps simply because when I'm
Updating notes or taking a look at what I did for the episode description over on sounder
Sometimes I am delayed on that simply through having a busy life and then I have to scroll up through Canadian Git's office hours
Or moderation's office hours or scroll around a little bit with it being in a thread. It just keeps everything contained
I also find that it prevents spam in some cases because it's like focused
I think it's working for like containerizing them
Probably not needed but it works
Like says how would you be able to tell what was right for cash? Would you just leave stuff based on time? Yeah stuff based on time
Good example might again be you know, or parallel might be the junk drawer in your house
You know, if you haven't sorted out your junk drawer in about five years, you have no idea what's in it
Okay, so I think that's a good example
You know, if you haven't sorted out your junk drawer in about five years, you have no idea what's in it. Okay, so out your junk drawer
so when I get this like
Jaw surgery project finally finished I'll be clearing out my cash because it will have basically
Way more models of teeth and bones and jaws and skulls in it than I need
And I want to spend as little time as possible thinking about my teeth is you know
For those who are not practicing good dental hygiene, I'm not judging here. I'm just saying like you should brush twice a day
Juries out on flossing from my point. I actually ended up reading scientific papers on flossing
You know flossing is kind of a little bit silly when you go to the dentist or the dentist is like wow
I could tell you've been flossing and I'm like, yep
Yeah, totally in the back of my head. I'm like I have a single time at all
No, but you mileage me very because I have literally the world's most expensive toothbrush. I have the most expensive Phillips toothbrush
Yeah
Remember when I bought it, but I do I don't know how we got to teeth. Oh, yeah the dental stuff
Yeah, I don't really want like think about my teeth teeth were expensive, etc. Etc
Preference like what teeth are expensive. Yeah, if you start having dental issues then
You'll find out how expensive teeth are the best way to delete your cash, which is a question from fox box
Which is you know, is there a best way to go about clearing your cash is to follow the guide?
I wrote that says how to clear your cash
Uh moving back up to Marco's question. He says do you have any favorite worlds or worlds?
I really like the time and gears. I've been to time and gears like randomly some because it's like it's it's cool. They're
It's cool. They're all in the wall is like usually my go-to well to just like sit when I'm like half paying attention
To existing I really do like sort of experience your art worlds. I'm less
it's not to say that these are good, but like I'm less bothered by
Like the chill out was that you see basically if your world has string lights and lots of cushions
Then your world is probably fantastic and very beautiful. But like it just has nothing for me. It's like, you know the 12th or 13th
string light and cushy cushion world that I've seen so
You know
That's why our hole in the wall gets like that. They're also like 72 grooved late, right?
It's it's it's still a hangout world, but it's not got string lights or cushions
So we both actually do have cushions, but like it's a it's a theming thing. I
Don't know like the words for architecture. The one I do know is brutalism, which I quite like
for my own weird taste, but
The all of the chat was in the archer and being brought over they all are the similar architecture
I don't know the name for that, but they all are that exact architecture. There's this really word
Well, I can't remember the name of actually I'm gonna go find the name. So those that play yeah, I can go find it
I know the weirdest like you have any favorite worlds away. Here's a VR channel. This is just an example right of
Where our tastes might differ very favorite worlds
Trying to find it
Favorite world. Yeah. No
Okay, the the thumb the fails are loading on the on the website and it says like world is currently available
Unavailable on like basically half of them. So I'll give up on that list. Oh, no. No, I found it. I found it
So there's a world here called FF CR which is like again by a hangout world over there but
It's really weird
And I feel like there's a story to it. So there's art to it as well. So like I like that
no one will hang out with me it so sometimes I'm just there by myself, but I
Guess that was sort of a play on I like walls which I'll hang out
But but but maybe consider being a bit different than than the usual one. I'll move on to questions before I continue to ramble
Yeah
Alexa I'm surprised anyone's in it. Yeah, I was like there's a story here. Like there's there's like a narrative
I'm gonna spoil too much but like explore and you'll see lots of stuff. That doesn't make sense
there's also lots of
Buttons and stuff that I can't really like figure out and
Sort of like weird
Anyway for example of brutalism by the way desert meeting space which now is a 2021 version
Thanks to soap who found out that there was actually a skyline geometry for that world. I just lost
So do check out desert meeting space 2021
I up the brightening the lighting so it's not just yellow now and looks better
Marco has a question here, which is do you have any tips?
So people just can't find motivation to brush their teeth or really do any hygiene stuff. Oh, okay
Daddy daddy prime is now giving people life tips
The strange one for brushing your teeth that I have is get out of the bathroom, right?
Of course, I like I leave my toothbrush in the bathroom, but I don't brush my teeth in the bathroom
ah, that's already a title that many people have given me and I don't want it but
Most people have issues with
Brushing their teeth because of the sort of loss of time of doing other stuff and I'm like cool
Well get yourself some wireless headphones
Go in the bathroom grab a toothbrush
Grab the toothpaste shove it on the brush start brushing come back to your computer and watch your funny cat memes on
On your TV or whatever. You don't need to be in the bathroom to brush your teeth
You just need to be in the bathroom to I guess spit out the toothpaste and rinse your mouth out
That's all you really need
Also for inexplicable reasons due to that my toothbrush often ends up on my computer desk, so that's it
That's a good reminder
Then there's habits as well
Like here's what I'm trying to break right now, which is kind of difficult which is when you're alone when your alarm goes off
What's the first thing you do? Do you grab your phone because that's like
Literally what most people do they wake up and before even leaving their bed, but they're checking their phone
The thing you should do when your alarm goes off particularly if it's an alarm and you need to get up is without even thinking
About it stand up
I don't care if you stand up like a zombie and then check your phone standing by the side of your bed
You just need to get out of the bed right get upright
That was advice given to me by some random life coach on YouTube. Usually I hate life coaches on YouTube
They're like I wake up every day at 3 a.m. And do like
Deadlifts of horses until 5 a.m. And then I eat 17 breakfasts before I deadlift some more horses and then at 9
I'm ready to start my day job. I'm just like that that isn't life coaching. That's just insanity. Thank you
Okay, so we do have a question here apologies I'm talking about deadlifting courses and missing the fact that there's still a question
Lex says what defines the order of items in the inventory there?
That broke recently actually and kind of scared me. I jumbled the order of a folder and I thought I'd lost something
But I'm not quite sure I think it's like the date I'd have to look I haven't opened the codebase today
I can open it. I don't know how much longer I'll be here. I'll go ahead and open it
There's a defined order. I can just like control T around and find it
All right. Codebase is loading. IntelliSense is just like
My RAM is just skyrocketing. I see other questions feel free to do feel free to keep them coming
I will be answering this question from Lex by just control T around for a little bit
So if you got any other questions, please drop them in there
Yeah, I don't actually have the source of architects. I don't think so. At least I remember what was in there
Am I one of the empty ones?
engine
control T
inventory
browser
Active avatar color is color dot magenta
Yay, and that's sort of like mixed down a little bit
Do you try initialize? Here it is. Start task root
open
Open begin generating update directory items. There we go. That'll do it
Yeah, this will probably take a little bit longer than I have time to like dig into it
Let me see if the private variable has more on it
Okay, it looks like whatever order the API returns it in
That's a sort of question I guess I can answer like so
it used to be the every single part of
Neos that
Fruix created was sort of automatically ended up in the same Visual Studio solution and
then part of that Visual Studio
Part of that Visual Studio solutions post build script will
Copy it to the the unity side of things such that they were all synced up
So what I predict happened was at one point
architects and Gen X and stuff like that were part of the
the Neos solution and were copied to the unity directory and the unity directory is
Just sort of built on top of like every time we need to rebuild unity project we rebuild unity project
And then that will update the DLLs that do update but the ones that don't update just kind of live there
It is something that I want to clean up
As well as any dead code that we have we have a bunch of stuff
That's just like completely commented out on the code base. I'm getting rid of
Strange stuff where I'm just like, oh, that's cool
Then like weird components that don't make any sense
Shout out to
Where is it up down?
I need to switch branches to find this
If Syro is here or a panda's here
He's like up down control, I can't remember the name of it it's in uncategorized
It is a very very weird component
That is just designed to make something go up and down
And it's beautiful and we have a lot of fun with it like that though. That's sort of like weird stuff. I'm trying to clean up
I think it's part of Classroom. That's probably why I don't see it anymore. We split classroom off to its own repository
Yeah
Architects was probably I don't know I would have to ask freaks
But like if I could guess based on just their naming scheme, it would probably be sort of like architectural tools
A good example of that might actually be stuff that is in my public folder under tools architecture tools
So I have a staircase generator in there. I have an archway generator
I had sort of grand visions for additional generators, but then the
Japanese community made the builder tip and that's much superior so I stopped working on that builder tip much more superior
like mathematically it should be possible if you're using primitives to
say
Give me a four by four room
With a door here and here and here and here
And then it should be able to like mathematically figure out using a metric type of logic, but you should be able to figure out
Wait logic. This is so dlc that is
Yeah, we'll clean that stuff up as soon as we can um, let's take a look
Make sure i'm not missing any questions, and then we'll leave off. Okay, so that's done. That's done. That's done. That's done. That's done
Scroll down to oh marcus. Is it spelt colour or color depends where you are. Um, there's this interesting channel
Which I can't find right now because it will probably take too long
I will find it and then i'll drop it in the office hours text chair. Um, which goes over sort of the
Origins of words and um, an interesting one. I watched it's actually a youtube short channel
So, you know, you watch like 20 and you're just like where is my life gone?
Uh was about the difference between the pronunciation of herb and and how you americans say it which is herb
um
In some parts of america, of course
Well, you just don't pronounce the h for some reason and you really over stress the b and all sorts of weird stuff like that
But that was all explained and I found that kind of interesting
Um, a lot of the sort of differences in spelling and also pronunciation
Come from the distances that existed between america and the uk when it was like, you know
First in existence and developing and and you know using language. It's like cool
Remember it used to be like I don't know like a two-week boat ride to get between there and we didn't have the internet
So that's cool
I always think about that like, you know, I fly back and forth from america quite often
And it's like I don't know what to do with my life. I don't know what to do with my life
And it's like, you know, that doesn't you know, seven hours eight hours
Isn't that long compared to a two-week boat ride is what it used to be?
And this is a two-week boat ride without any electronics remember like I don't know what they did
like
What would you do for two weeks on a boat?
It's not like a particularly nice boat as well because it's like it's just like a transport boat. It's not a cruise
Same thing goes with uh, the titanic, um, when you watch the titanic
Pay more attention to the the lower class decks
Because those are basically sort of university dorms or in some cases
They look like prison cells where people were just there for however long the titanic was meant to you know
Um journey, which is a long time
Anyway, if we're talking about the titanic, I believe that we have gone off track enough to cancel, uh, cancel end office hours. However, um
Um, speaking as I mentioned the titanic if anyone would like to um play a video game, which is amazing
You should play titanic adventure out of time
um
it is just like
One of the like best pieces of of 90s video gaming I have ever seen
Please play it don't question it if you don't know anything about it and you're you know, you've never played it
don't question anything just
Just please just go play it
Uh, marco says that there's a question actually. Thank you. Lex for pointing out. What happens if you delete empty dlls, uh
Uh, if they're not referenced anywhere, it should be fine. But ideally don't do that. Don't give me as a reason to hate you
and with that we'll leave off play titanic adventure out of time and uh
I will uh, see you guys next week ping me, uh questions help
If you've got other questions and uh notes and stuff will be up when we get to them. All right
I will see you guys later. I gotta push like five buttons because they change the way that you end stages
So here we go. Bye. Bye