Alright, it is 4pm, welcome to Office Hours with Prime.
I'm here to answer your Neos questions, and you can drop those in the Office Hours text chat.
Make sure you're talking in the Office Hours text chat and not the text channel that's for this
weird thing that we should use, but I think Discord doesn't make it obvious enough that
this exists, so many people don't see it, but many people still don't see the thread,
so it just gets really really complicated. Anyway, get your questions in the usual place,
I'll answer them in the order that they appear. Whilst there are no questions,
we're going to be sitting here in unimaginable silence, just hoping for some juicy question that
we can probably do some strange anecdote on. Whilst we wait for a question, did you know that
right now in RuneScape, yes that's RuneScape, there is an event where you can get a cape,
and once you have the cape it gives you a 30-day buff which will transmit anything that you mine,
woodcut, or fish to your bank for free, which means lots of people are training mining and
woodcutting very very quickly right now, including me, who has been mining in the same spot for a
very long time. It is completely unrelated to NeoSina, but I just thought I'd let you know.
I have to fill the dead air sometimes because someone's grandmother told me there should be
less dead air. Left 4 Dead was a good game, but I think it was like the end of 2022,
I instantiated a policy in my brain which is I will never play Left 4 Dead again.
Basically what happens is I install it, and then someone says a few months later "Let's play Left
4 Dead" and then I reinstall it, we play once and then never again, so I've just decided no,
I will never play it again and that way it can be removed from my computer. Same thing happens with
Grand Theft Auto V actually. The moment I uninstall Grand Theft Auto V sometimes it's just needed
again, and I don't really understand why that keeps happening but there we go. Oh yeah, the
dead air was also removed from the crawling because we have an effect in Audacity called
Truncate Silence. It's useful for making you only listen to the questions or me manically laughing
at you. We still have no questions, so this is going to be a quick office hours unless questions
start appearing very soon, but yes, unimaginable silence. DIA says that they need something like
Truncate Silence for their sleep talk recordings. If you get the app Sleep as an Android it will do
it for you. If you're not on Android device I can't help you, but there's probably a similar
app for an iOS device. I've had Sleep as an Android for many many years. It keeps track of
how much sleep you need and how much sleep you're getting in the form of a sleep deficit graph. The
deficit graph is un-resetable, so it's just been listing my deficit for months and years, and it's
just like, you know, you've missed 609,000 hours of sleep or whatever it is. It's wrong because it's
got duplicate data or something from when I change phones, but I can't reset it, so it's just like
your deficit is really bad. It's like, okay, cool. All right, so we got a cheese question,
which I don't answer, so skipping that one, sorry about that. Lex says are you aware of,
are you aware, and if you are, do you have any comments on the issues that a large amount of
people are having with Learning Essence in the US? I am aware of them, I am taking a look at them,
but I don't have any further comments on their matter. Erin asks, other than the US,
what games have you worked on that you enjoyed your time while doing so, if any? I haven't
really worked on any other games. Oh yeah, I haven't really worked on any other games.
A couple of projects here and there, a few bits and pieces, never really like, you know. I am
partially responsible for a particular piece of literature, which I will dig up.
If anyone is seeing people's names in Discord cut off with triple dashes, it is a security feature
that is instilled into Discord via the username update debacle. You have streamer mode enabled,
and that is why people's names are cut off like that. There is no documentation on that,
I just figured it out because some random person tweeted it and then some other random person
retweeted it. It has been bothering me too, but there you go. Yes, I am partially responsible for
the fact that there was a video involving pigs on the Xbox YouTube channel. I will
paste that tweet when I find it, because I think I have it close to hand. I do. Yes, it's really
only for people that have got the username update as far as I'm aware. It's something because like,
now that, like, I don't know, it's a feature of streamer mode. I appreciate it because streamer
mode is cool, but like, you know, I could speak forever about streaming security and making sure
you don't leak your bank details while still streaming. But you know, that's not a Neos
question. Any additional Neos questions? Seeing as we just had the pig video from Mixer. I don't know
if there's any other Mixer stuff on the Xbox channel. There probably is. Let me see if I'm
responsible for any more of it. I'm not responsible for that or that or that. I'm responsible for that
one. Who had that one? Oh, they're tips and tricks videos. Got it. Okay. Yeah, cool. I'm not responsible
for tips and tricks, but yeah. Anyway, as a reminder, if there are no questions, we're going
to sit here in silence. Take a moment to, you know, stare out of the window. If you haven't been
looking at the computer monitor for too long, you should look at something at least 20 feet away
for 20 seconds every 20 minutes or something like that. 20, 20, 20. Yeah. I'm sure you're breathing
right as well. So many people don't know how to breathe. Well, I don't mean stupidly, but you know,
there are different mechanisms for breathing. You can breathe at the top of your, at the top of your
chest or like right the way down into the bottom. And you need to do that right the way down into
the bottom. Oh my God, we have a question. Do you happen to know why animated meshes seem to jump
when you swap the animation? I would presume that's because we don't have any smoothing
between those animations. So let's say animation one has a character's right hand raised and an
animation two has the character's left hand raised or right hand lowered. Like there's no way to sort
of smoothly interpolate between those. Oh, comma frames at the end. Honestly, it's probably still
interpolating. Our animation system just needs like reworking it. It really annoys me. I have
actually FPX animations just in general too. I've got a world where, it's a science world, people
need to give a speech in front of some pretend judges or business folks. And they were just sort
of staring at the person that's in that world. And it was, you know, like, oh, could we get them to
like, you know, do something? And so we did. And the way that we did that is I had to go to
Mixima and I took three animations, had to stitch them together inside a blender, which took forever
because they didn't know how to do it, apply the animation to five people, get it into the game.
And then because one of the animations was writing, I had to like write logics to position a pen that
appeared in their hands whilst the animation played that they were writing, and they disappeared
when they stopped writing. All to make them look more interesting. electronic has another question.
They say, does the headless play animations or can it not? Should be able to. Animations are just
like streams of data, right? It won't render them because it doesn't render them. But it's,
it's still do the updates. I don't know if they run locally, they might run locally.
As much as I hate the fact that in VRChat you have to do everything with animation trees,
we need all that feature from Unity, like animation trees, animation state machines,
all sorts of stuff like that. VRChat users should not have to do that. I was looking at making
the face tracker work over in VRChat, and it was just like, what the f-- it's just so complicated.
All I want to do is make some blend shapes change. Why am I making 50 animations and linking them
together with spaghetti? But there you go. I got like 30 seconds into the process of making it work
on my avatar over there, and I just said, nah, I'd rather just grab a cheese grater or shredder,
push it right against my face, but that'd be a lot easier. There are like community tools to make
that stuff easier, but a couple of them are archived, and I followed like three archive links
until I got very confused and just decided, meh, not today. We're just over halfway through this,
so if you have any more additional Neos questions, please do let me know. Please drop them into the
uh text thread, I'm not seeing any here, just uh, whilst that's not there, just remember to breathe,
stare at something into the distance, and there you go. Uh, Erin asks, actually that is a question,
but it's not a Neos question, but seeing as there's dead air, we'll fill it, um,
they say, uh, does losing focus and staring at nothing count as zonar tot when? Yes, that does,
that may be a sign of some, um, mental trouble, so do keep an eye out. Sometimes I enjoy just
staring at a wall, I'm not really staring at the wall, I guess I'm just like, you know, not using
my eyes for the moment. Oh yeah, because there are any useful, uh, components you found in Neos
recently, and I found texture size driver personally, it saved me a lot of trouble. Um,
there haven't been, um, there hasn't been a case of that like in a long time, like sometimes you
just find a component and you're just like, that's, you know, exactly what I needed it for.
There are some times where you, like, you find a component and you're like, okay, I understand what
that does, I just don't understand why it does it, but then you like see it later and you're just
like, all right, that's cool. But yeah, neither of those have happened in a while. Um, like I'm sure
there are ones out there, it just depends, like at some point you've used all the components that
you're going to use, there's like edge cases. Uh, Aaron asks, are there any questions you would ask
right now in office hours if someone else was in your place? Um, I am getting like interesting
questions where someone's building something that isn't obviously an oldie tool or an inspector,
that's what I like. Um, moving forwards to, uh, Churnace's question. Um, see here's an example,
light cookies, lighting, excellent. Lighting is a fantastic topic and more people should do it. By
the way, it is not natural if you have an indoor only map that you have a sun, please turn off your
sun and light it with lights. Um, and there should be dark corners of your indoor space, there should
be bright corners of your indoor space. Like think about like a bar, right? The bar should have lights
above it, so you can walk up to it and have a drink, but maybe like a booth in the corner of
the bar should have a darker light to it. You can't do that if you've got a sun inside your box,
turn off the sun if you're doing an indoor only map. Um, so electronic is asking, uh,
something issues of light cookie not being loaded when I needed it, is there a good way to ensure
it's loaded? Try the asset loader, I think it's called, it's in the assets folder. It will ensure
an asset is loaded before you need it. Uh, you need to sort of put things in that component if
you are using them from outside asset components. So things like the asset multiplexer or
stuff like that will try and keep the asset loaded. But if you have an asset as a raw reference,
it might de-load, so try the asset loader. Saray asks, um, would it make sense to have a
gesture system in the assistantials that are relatively easy to instill, given that when you
without, uh, Logix expressions tend to be intimidated because it looks, yes. Uh, there are
multiple gesture systems inside an assistantials and that is actually one of the problems that we
have. Um, I am working with the team on that one when I can, um, but we need to sort of standardize
a little bit more rigidly what we put in that folder to make sure that it is, it's very good.
Um, every single MMC, for example, we get a new gesture system and I am, I'm not bothered by the
fact that we do, um, in terms of the user making it, I'm bothered by the fact that Neos itself
hasn't solved that. Like I don't, I don't understand why there are so many. I mean,
I do, but like, I don't understand why we haven't made that not in a necessity, right.
You always be able to use your own systems, of course, but why don't we just have our own?
And if we're like, oh yeah, but we, you know, we don't really like gesture based systems. I don't
like gesture based systems. We can still make one. It's easy. Um, so we should do that. We should
definitely do that instead of making our own. Like if we made our own Logix based one, there would
just be another Logix based one, right? I made one of the first ones, which was the gesture wheel
based one. Um, it got sort of outdated within like a week. So that's fine. But like, even when I made
that, I felt bad because I felt like I was contributing to the problem, which is there are
too many gesture systems and none of them are easy to use. If we made one that was like Neo standard,
it would probably be like a very simple component. Um, I'd like to, you know, maybe build like a
wizardy UI for it. Uh, and that way, um, we would of course be adding another standard,
the list of standards people are referencing, uh, an XKCD comic, but it would allow us to
help in that because most people wouldn't even have to get the Logix tip out.
Like one of the big problems I see when people come into Neos is they're almost like goaded,
either accidentally or sometimes on purpose, please don't do this by the way, um, into
getting a Logix tip or a developer tip out, right? Cause they need to set up their avatar
or someone starts talking to them at multi-tools or inspectors and stuff like that. It's like,
just, just let them experience Neos as a new user, uh, don't force technical stuff into them.
But to do that, we need a better avatar setup that isn't as technical as its current avatar setup.
So moving onwards to electronicist question says, uh, is there a good tutorial for NMJ?
Uh, there's like the Wiki page, like got some information on it. There's also some research
that Lex did. Um, we could never really find, like we kept coming across bugs, so we kind of just
stopped. So no, there's no tutorial I'm aware of, but the Wiki does have some information that,
okay, the Wiki didn't help. And sorry about that, but you know, we try.
Maybe, yeah, and you're stifles talking about the, the various bugs that exist in, um, NMJ. Yeah,
there's, there's bugs, there's problems. We've got a question in two parts, which looks like I'm
answering the long, I'm out of order, but I'm not. Um, uh, Jack will ask when you do tutorials
again, which consider one that does a review of less obvious data types. And then in a follow-up
message, they say like iWorld element or SyncRef backtick one, uh, you shouldn't be using iWorld
element. If you are using it, you're probably doing something incorrectly. If you're using
SyncRef, you are at the point in using Neos where you should not require a tutorial on it.
Um, both of those things are very, very advanced. And if you're using them, uh, you really need to
know how like C# works. Like always, always, always start with a problem, right? So if you're using
iWorld element, you're probably implementing the solution to a problem incorrectly, or your problem
is really advanced and there's no other way to do it, but mess around with that stuff. But I don't
advise messing around with that stuff. And therefore I won't be tutorialing it because
it is, it's structured so vague compared to like the problem. Trying to think of a good analogy
and the only one that came into my head, and it probably is not a good analogy, but the only one
that came into my head is it's like someone asking how to tie their shoelace by going to a, uh, rope
manufacturer. It's like, alright, let's go watch a rope being made. Like, let's start with the problem.
Like what, what, what do you want to do with those, those things? Uh, Jackyl, again, we're jumping
around. Cody, I'll get to you in just a second. Um, Jackyl updates with, so don't mess with reference
target, the logics note. No, you can use that. You can use everything. It's just like, you need to know
why you're using it. Like I use that note a lot, but I need a problem that requires it's use to
explain it. I can't, like, I can tell you what it does and that's exactly what it does, but let's
start with the problem, not the data type. Um, if you really, really want to see why that's the, the
stance I take, go take a look at the C# reference, which is the language of course that Neos has
written in. There are like data types in there that I have like no idea why anyone would go
anywhere near them. It's just like, cool. Um, I actually had an interesting issue the other day,
uh, with, it was something like, you know, a trip, like anyone who knows, um, uh, C# knows that you
can put attributes above stuff, right? So you put like square races and then some other stuff, and
it's sort of like tags a piece of code and says, do this extra piece of functionality. There are
tributes in C# that have no documentation, but it sounds really cool. And you just don't know how to
like, just like, Microsoft, come on, tell me what they do. And it's just like, nope, not going to
tell you what they do. Uh, let me take a look. Um, I'm going to jump back to questions. Play code.
It says what are the best method for requesting tutorial recording a 3d moment that has a component
I'm not familiar with. Um, you should list that 3d model and component in your question. That'd
be great stuff. Um, Maya has a patreon question, please direct message shifty about those. Um,
I don't handle them here. Um, uh, Play code. He says they saw your wire cube object and saw
the component that drives the mesh of the wires. Ah, that's the wire stuff. I don't know how that
works. Um, I have no idea. Like, um, that creates a piece of wire between two points, but it does it
in a way to kind of try to, and it does it really badly, but tries to avoid twisting and tries to
make it look like a patch cable might on, like an analog synthesizer or a breadboard electrical
circuit. I'm trying to suggest using a making a tutorial for ref hacking. You can absolutely
do that. I won't personally be doing that because I don't think that we should. Um, I don't think
you should be doing it. You can do it and there's nothing wrong with doing it. No one's going to yell
at you for doing it, but just know that you're, you know, you're doing stuff I'm telling you not
to. That one's a bit like, um, trying to think of another analogy here that might work. You peek
behind the curtain on your ref hack, basically. So you're peeking behind the curtain and you know,
you get certain capabilities with that, but like the curtain's always changing.
Last question, because we're running low on time here, um, from Storm who says, uh,
any idea what was causing the issues of worlds and items not sinking over the weekend? I don't know.
I have a team are aware of it. Um, people that can are looking into it. I don't know. With that,
I think we've got all the questions. If you have any additional questions, please drop them into
the questions and up channel where someone will help you out or direct message me. I will see you
again next week. Um, the six, the 6th of June is now up on the Wiki. I know Lex, I have a bunch of
SRT files. I'll get those shortly. I'll get this recording done and up as soon as I can. I am
moving right now. What's it does anyone know when like tape doesn't work? I have a roll of duct tape
and like I taped up a box and then I go to it this morning and the box is undone. And I'm just like,
is this just bad tape? What the hell? It could be humidity killed it. I don't know. I've got some
new tape arriving, but that means I need to like remove the old tape and apply the new tape. It's
just really annoying. Specs says duct tape isn't good for packing boxes. I do have like box, like
specific box tape coming in the mail. I'm getting movers, but like there's, I have a box. I have a
bookshelf. Uh, books in a box shelf. Uh, yeah. Anyway, I will leave off there. Bye-bye.