All right, now it's four.
Welcome to Office Hours.
This is the half-hour segment where I answer
questions from chat and
everyone else that questions up here.
We have one question waiting,
so I'll go ahead and just jump straight into that.
We are recording, yep, so you'll hear on the recording.
I can ask, is there a way to merge changes between two worlds?
For example, I have version one and I publish it,
but I want to work on version 1.1 over a few weeks,
so I save a copy of that world to work on.
Once done, is it possible to merge
those changes back to the published world?
Yes and no. There's no way to merge it at the world level,
so there's no UI for that,
there's no feature for that that can happen.
But if you do a good practice,
which is where everything in a world is
parented to a slot other than root,
then you can go ahead and
just transfer that slot between the worlds,
and that will allow you to merge those changes in.
Version management on worlds is something that we need to do
a lot more work on as a team at
NEEUS to make it a lot easier to figure out.
I am plagued by
people doing that in a way that doesn't really make sense to me.
So when I make a world, I have one world,
and if I publish it and I break it, I'll just fix it.
So I don't maintain multiple versions of worlds.
Additionally, I practice something which I really
wish many, many, many more people would practice,
which is you don't need to save
the world if you're just saving bits of it.
So example here being,
you're in a tavern world and you've edited the drink system.
Just save the drink system and then replace that in the world.
You don't need to save another copy of the world,
and then that makes it easier.
You just go into the published world once you're
aware that your new drink system
works and you replace the drinks.
Stop treating the world
as a big circle and save parts of it.
I always have little bits of the world which I can then load in,
position, update, and it makes it a lot
easier because you can just save stuff to the inventory.
I've got one world on the go right now for
some science where we're doing eye testing.
So we're testing your vision and stuff like that.
Really, really cool. Many players have eye-tracked headsets,
but I do let me know.
I'm keeping a list for future times.
Anyway, the point being is
that there are components of that world.
There is the system which records
the data from your eye-tracked headset.
There is the way to do those eye movements.
So it's basically like it makes a dot move and
you've got to follow them in case it's a separate system.
There's a system which can block one eye or
the other eye such that we're only testing the left or right eye.
That's, again, separate. All those parts are separate.
If I update them, I just replace them in
the world and they work because they're all separate.
Shifty has updated me saying that
the world overwrite function is not working.
I forgot that that button existed,
but probably because it's broken,
it left my brain.
So do take a look at that particular issue which may
help with overwriting worlds and versions and stuff like that.
It is 3044 for the reference.
Yeah, it's a thing.
There's an enter button.
It's like a square with an arrow in it and it can overwrite worlds.
I forgot it existed because I've never used it because it was broken.
It's weird. If you own a house,
I guarantee, well, also if you rent,
but basically, and maybe even if you just have a room in the house.
Anyway, the point being,
there is something that you need to do that you haven't
done for so long you've just forgotten that it exists.
If you own a house, it's usually something like cleaning the gutters.
But that's an example of that problem that you can relate to.
Just forgetting about something because it's been broken for so long.
No, it's not that button.
Maybe it is that button. I'll just stop talking about that feature because evidently,
I don't know how it works,
but I thought that's the one that did it.
Anyway, there is a way to do it.
Check that GitHub issue for information.
That's issue 3044.
Moving onwards to additional questions.
Duff asks, what is Prime's preference of drink while playing Neo?
So what advice would you like to share to those who are drinking age while drinking in VR?
If you have a face tracker, get a straw.
I have taken to drinking tea with a straw,
which is very strange, but there we go.
When I first got the face tracker and
strapped it to the front of my headset via various means,
I was constantly just punching it in the face,
and that was just problematic.
I've learned now I need to reach around it,
and a straw does help with that.
Generically, a straw does help when you are drinking anything in VR.
I don't tend to drink alcohol these days.
It's not out of any preference or need or medical stuff like that.
It's just it's expensive and I am unable to get drunk.
I can bathe in alcohol and still be not drunk.
So there's no point.
Does it taste better in some cases?
Yes. In the majority cases, no.
So there's no real point.
I managed to quit soda as well.
Soda is incredibly addictive and if you are a regular soda drinker,
you're probably just addicted to it.
I was on regular soda, of course,
growing up because that's kids and we don't really care about our health.
But then when growing up, I'm like,
hey, that's unhealthy, I should switch to diet.
So I was on diet soda for many years,
and then I realized how addictive it was when I stopped drinking it for a while,
just randomly, and then went back to it and it was gross.
I hadn't drunk soda in forever and I drank it again.
I'm like, this is gross.
I was just addicted to the random components of the soda.
So yeah, it's usually just water and tea these days.
Although I do, I have joined the cold coffee.
Everyone's like, it's cold brew.
I'm like, no, I just stir cold water into instant coffee,
and that's cold brew as far as I'm concerned as well.
That is purely for caffeine.
I will like stir cold water into coffee, instant coffee, and then just chug it.
And that's how I start my day these days.
I will not join the Starbucks frappe whip caramel banana sprinkles,
pumpy squirty sauce crew.
That's just crazy.
There's a meme image I can never find where it's like a two panel comic
and it's someone holding like a really big fancy frappe style drink.
And the speech bubble says, I'm just not me without my coffee in the morning.
And then the next panel of this comic is like a breakdown of what's in the drink.
And it's like less than 1% coffee.
The rest of it is just like pure sugar.
And so the meaning being, they're looking for the sugar.
They're not looking for the caffeine, but I can't find that comic.
So if anyone wants to sort of Google through that, fantastic.
Thank you.
We don't have any other questions.
Hence why I'm talking about coffee and things like that.
So actually I can comment on Epic Eastern who says,
Prime, you are the funny source code man.
You're supposed to know everything.
I don't know anything, everything.
There are like thousands of files and like,
I'm not sure like Fruits knows all of them.
Of course he can like remember them.
It's like, you know, when you hear like a familiar tune and you're like,
Oh yeah, I have listened to that before,
but I don't remember how the tune went.
That's because it's not being used.
The memory is kind of like fainter.
So I'm quite certain there are parts of Neos,
which are like at the back of Fruits's head.
And he won't remember as well.
So it's normal to not know.
Like I found out the other day, you know, the Neos launcher,
like the old one, not the new one, like the old, old one,
the one that actually, you know, do various stuff.
I'll just get a picture of it for reference.
No, that took a picture of just the Neos logo
at the top of it.
The purple logo on that is a good distinction.
So you have like four of them right now.
Yeah, the purple logo one.
The purple logo one.
Lots of people are using, you see what it says?
Use custom bootstrap class right at the bottom there.
Use custom bootstrap class isn't meant for what
people are using it for.
Like what people are doing is they're checking that
and then they put in command line arguments.
And this works, but it's a bug that it works.
It's not meant to work.
It's like, it's a bug.
So the custom bootstrap text box is actually meant
to provide a custom bootstrap class,
which no one to my knowledge has done.
I think Neos classroom does it.
And like one other business thing we did back in the day
did it, but that's actually a way for you to,
in addition to plugins,
it's a way for you to customize how Neos launches.
So if you do that,
and there's no documentation on how to do it.
So if you're interested, let me know.
I'll write some documentation,
but like no one has used this feature
as far as I'm aware.
It will allow you to change the startup routine.
So the startup routine will be like,
yo, I'm going to do this stuff.
So it checks and logs you in.
It fetches your avatar, does a bunch of stuff like that.
With that custom bootstrap class option,
you can basically say, no, don't do that.
Instead, open this very specific world,
load this specific avatar into this world
and do not connect on the Neos cloud.
That's what you could do with that bootstrap class.
It is a bug.
It's a bug.
Great.
I know you guys are using it.
It will continue to work because by the time we fix it,
we'll have something as an alternate there that will work
or maybe we'll just place another checkbox with it
or whatever, but it is quite literally a bug.
So yeah, that was just some random anecdote.
Ruscio, it's fine that you put the questions in here.
I know it's different for this week.
Ruscio dropped a question in the regular chat.
We're putting questions in threads,
just trying to keep things organized.
I will accept the question outside of the thread,
but just keep the next subsequent questions
in the thread. Thank you.
Let's move forward on questions
rather than talking about coffee,
although Dier recommends French press for cold brew.
I used to have a French press machine.
It worked on 240 volts, so I couldn't bring it here.
Scary guy for asking a question.
It goes in the thread.
Thank you for the memes here. Cool.
Okay, let me just double-check that we're not missing
in questions before I go to the ones that are at the bottom.
Okay, so we'll go for Duff's first.
Duff came before Ruscio, so Duff, Ruscio,
and then whoever types the question next. Excellent.
So Duff says, what would you say at what point
would NeosModerator take initiative disciplinary action
without the use pre-resc of a moderation ticket to be inputted?
I will defer to the response which Git gave
at the previous moderation office hours,
which I'm going to quote from memory,
so please do check the notes for the official commentary
from the moderation team,
but that the moderation team can issue temporary restrictions
which are designed to just de-escalate the situation.
So that might be just like a temporary public ban
so people can't join public sessions,
which they then are required to follow up with a ticket
such that there is a record of it
where a discussion and proper ticket process
will happen about maybe extending that to a longer period.
So a good example there might be hate talking
about moderation things because of stuff like this,
but I'll just think of an example.
So let's say harassment, right? Let's say sexual harassment.
So that happens. I would, as a moderator,
I would issue a temporary ban,
and then I would open up a ticket
where we could discuss what happened next.
It's important to remember that moderators are not beat cops.
They're not designed to go around and police sessions.
They're also not designed to get in their squad cars
and, you know, blip up and down the road
that's next to my house at like 4 a.m.
with their, like, sirens on,
but not the sirens that are regular.
You know the, like, intense sirens they do sometimes,
the more high-pitched ones?
Usually when someone's in their way,
they're just, like, going up and down the road
outside my apartment all the night doing that.
I don't know why.
Anyway, moderators are not designed to do that.
Yeah, we're going to try it.
I think it'll be better for, like,
scrolling through the office hours.
I'm sorry. We're talking about the threads for questions
because, to me, even when I scroll back,
it's kind of difficult to see when one starts and one ends.
There's usually a lot of messages which are around the area,
you know, from the people hosting office hours,
but sometimes they're harder to miss,
so maybe threads will be better.
I don't know. We're just trying it.
It's a request. I think it's a good idea, so we'll try it.
Moving on to Risio's question, which is next,
which is, in the Creator Jam 4 last,
we're looking for a way to produce custom curves
and start checking out the Bezier curve component points
in the curve tip.
They seem to work by themselves,
but there's also felt incomplete
as there's no way to clear the gizmos
beside manually detailing, manually, manually deleting them.
Are there any further enhancements planned
for these components that you know of?
No.
The curve tip is actually a really old one.
You can tell that just by inspecting it.
You can also tell it by reading the code.
Like, it's ancient.
So there isn't anything planned to address that yet.
I think we had...
Like, when I mentioned the curve tip previously to Frix,
he said that that's old and it might be removed
but replaced with functionality to do that
in such a way where you could remake it
as a Neos builder rather than a Neos developer.
There are a bunch of sort of curvy chubby meshes
that we have, and at some point,
I want to sort of reconcile them
and put them together such that there are less.
The same with straight line meshes as well.
There's segment mesh, slot segment mesh, line mesh.
There's just so many, and they're basically
just like, draw a line.
Even the curve ones are, draw a line.
So it's like, maybe we could standardize them
into something that made it a little bit easier to know,
especially that slot segment mesh versus segment mesh.
I can never remember which one's best.
One has more options than the other,
and you should use the one that has more options,
because you're like, I don't know, maybe.
As far as like editing and stuff to do with curves,
check out the Vigileboes folder.
They don't really play Neos that much right now,
but all of the like types of curves that you would need
have editors inside that folder.
You're looking for blue thick lines
with like green dots on them
when you're looking for the thumbnail
in the public folder.
I get those out every time I want to use a chubby mesh,
so I can just remind myself of which chubby meshes do which.
If you'd like better functionality in the area as well,
make sure that there is a GitHub open for it.
Scary, yes, I could totally lock down Office Hours.
I'm just not currently doing it.
Yeah, the curve tip is really interesting.
It will make a complete mess of your world though,
because each of those points,
the like ones attached to the line
that leads to the main point,
those are called control points, by the way,
is on my route, and it's just like there.
If you delete the curve, you can't,
basically you'll spend like five minutes
cleaning up that curve that you made, Easton.
It's not fun.
Same thing with the label tip, actually.
I've never really understood why the label tip
doesn't create something more sensible.
The label tip will make two slots in your world route
called label point and label content.
I wish it would like be a bit more intelligent about that
and make one slot called label and parent the point
and the content to that,
and I might actually update the label tip
to do that when I can.
There are a lot of tools that need to either be removed
or updated such that they work.
You can tell a lot of this, by the way,
by going to start new world or create new world
and choosing the scratch-based template.
The scratch-based template is a holdover
from the days where there was no inventory system in Neos.
When there was no inventory system in Neos,
if you didn't have the developer tool,
you had to go to the scratch-based world to get it.
And if you wanted to save something,
you had to go to your cloud or local home
and drop it there to save it.
That didn't used to be a cloud home, by the way.
So you had to save it to your local home as well.
And so I remember, I hear things
from people that are around at that time
where they were just like, yep,
we would just grab everything and return it to our homes
and save it there because we didn't know if we needed it
and it was very difficult to get.
So do be thankful that we have inventory systems now.
Moving forward to the next question.
Lex says, would you know if there's any reason
when saving objects that they are locally compressed as LZ4
but when uploaded, they are compressed with 7-zip?
There are multiple compression algorithms that we have
and have support for.
Neos will pick one in a way that I don't understand
when you upload stuff.
I don't particularly understand why, how, or what.
I also thought 7-zip's compression was similar to LZ4.
We would like a few modifications.
I don't really remember, though.
Peach, yes, you can answer any questions that you want,
whatever you would like.
Rusio has found a curve tip custom
that makes things a little bit cleaner.
There is a Neos2p link for that.
Try that one out.
Yeah, I want, Ramp has talking about the LZ4
and things.
I'm not gonna comment on further stuff to do
with compression.
I'll have to open up the code and do that.
If there are no questions, I can sort of idly poke at it,
but I wouldn't actually know where to go.
For those who are familiar with programming,
and for those who are not, I'll try and explain it.
There's like layers to code,
and asset uploading is like the deepest part of the code.
It would be the equivalent of me like opening that drawer,
that one drawer that you haven't sorted out in a while,
and like emptying the entire thing onto my bed,
and then like going through it to try to figure out
where the hell that piece of code is.
It's like a descent into madness.
It's really great when you come out of one of those, though,
because you'll remember how to get there.
Visual Studio has this cool feature called Bookmarks,
which I heavily use
because it just makes navigating things faster,
particularly when I get questions about common stuff.
So I have a bookmark that takes me straight
to the entry point for all of the Neospot commands,
so I can get there quickly.
I've got another entry point,
which takes me to rig classification stuff,
so I can find really quickly any sort of rig-based issues,
sort of like that.
Now, that isn't to say that the code base is bad.
That's just something that happens
with a code base this big,
is like sometimes you're like, yeah, that's really deep.
I've got to like spend a lot of time
finding like the end of that.
Like, for example,
I was looking at opening worlds the other day,
and there are about like 15 different ways
for the code base to open a world,
and they all do like various things differently.
And so it was just like, okay, cool.
I don't know which one I need to use.
Let's take a look down at additional questions.
Alex says, what's something you didn't expect
the Neos community to make, but have?
Honestly, I'm still dumbfounded every time I see
that someone has made another multi-tool
and another custom inspector.
If you are considering making another custom tool,
a multi-tool or a custom inspector,
please, please make something else.
Make a Neos world where you are a cat
trying to save the world from extremist broccoli
who are trying to take over the world using chlorophyll.
There you go.
Just like make a game, make an experience.
That was a completely random idea.
Make things, make things.
There is one thing, Lex did say positive things.
The positive things, I guess, are all the micro tools.
You know, there's a process that we want to do,
and then there's a tool made that makes it easier.
I did expect some of them,
but like it's getting kind of crazy how much those are.
If you mean, you know, additionally positive there,
like the, I always go back to abandonware.
Like abandonware, like if abandonware, the AMC entry,
if that was on Steam for under 10 bucks,
it would be really, really popular.
Like it was not going to make like thousands of dollars
or anything like that,
but like it would be very popular on Steam.
And if it was on Steam, people like the market players
and the other horror game players of the world
will have played it and put it on their channel as well.
Like that's how good that one felt.
Next question here.
Scary Guy says, what's the airspeed velocity
of an unladen swallow?
Do you mean an African or European swallow?
I think that's the quote, anyway.
Zach says, is there a way to clear a string
when a video ends?
Absolutely.
So depending on what you're doing with a video,
all of the playback nodes works.
You could do playback position.
Normalized position might be better for that one.
Normalized position outputs the normalized point
of the video.
So zero is the start of the video,
one is the end of the video.
So you could do when the normalized position equals one,
fire on true, clear the string.
There may even be a node for when the video ends.
I don't quite remember.
I'm not in Neos right now,
so I'm not looking at those nodes.
But yeah, basically figure out if the video has stopped
and then clear the string with the right node.
Easy, easy, easy.
We have a question here from Kazu says,
recently I often see logs that are running out of space
when asked by beginners,
but everyone says they can afford display capacity.
Is there a gap between capacity display
and the capacity is actually determined
as a synchronization failure?
Yes, those things are like delayed a little bit
from each other,
particularly because if there's an active sync happening,
then we're able to see how much is coming in
and maybe stop it because we know that it won't fit
and stuff like that.
And then sometimes the space display that's on the dash
is like cached or delayed
based on the cloud processing the incoming assets.
So those things can get out of alignment sometimes,
which might be what you're seeing.
Lex actually made a good comment there,
which is he thought that we were talking about local space,
not cloud space.
So Kazu, maybe if you could clarify
or just direct message me later, we'll take a look at it.
Particularly if you've got the log file
that was causing the problem,
I can just double check which one of those are.
Moving forwards, Peach has a question.
What is the possibility difficulty
of integrating programs, plugins, things into Neos?
Particularly I was about to ask this general
regarding to playing flash games in virtual arcades.
Okay, so flash is dead.
I know that that's sad.
There are ways to play flash games that exist.
There's like a, I can't remember the name of it.
What that thing, I can't remember the name of,
does though, is it downloads a very old version of Firefox
and then just goes, here you go, flash works.
That's what it does.
It's quite cool,
because it lets you sort of relive the nineties,
but flash games inside Neos wouldn't be a thing
that would probably support.
Now, you're welcome to do that with plugins or mods.
It'll probably have to be a plugin for flash,
but that would be quite an undertaking.
Yes, Linker, you wanna make Neos Plus run flash files?
Go for it.
That'll be out next Tuesday, right?
We are looking into web assembly later.
There's a GitHub issue for it,
which would allow you to run things
in that range a little bit,
but probably not flash itself.
Integrating stuff is basically a mix of,
are you okay waiting?
In which case, hey, Neos will do it.
And if it's compatible with Neos's ethos,
development strategy, et cetera, great,
but you'll have to wait.
Then there is plugins,
which is you can do whatever you want in a plugin.
You can do whatever you want.
You could probably get like a Windows emulator
into Neos with a plugin.
That'd be very difficult to do,
but you can probably do it.
So you can probably do flash if you would like to,
but it would have to be a...
Let's take a look down at the next question.
Zach says, why does it take so long to sync a large file?
Well, I don't know what sort of magnitude
we're talking at here.
If you're talking about like a gigabyte,
then it's a gigabyte.
That's why it takes a long time.
Additionally, larger files are large.
Sorry, I completely lost my train of thought.
Large files are large.
That's why it takes so long.
Give you some more details and I'll see what it is.
Like if you said it was taking like three hours
to sync 500 megabytes, that's a problem.
We could look at that.
If it's like, it takes a long time to sync one gigabyte,
it's like, eh, it does.
Mr. Square Pig.
No, Square Peg, sorry, to use there.
Will the Pico4 work with Neos?
I have one on order.
As with all gadgets and headsets,
the only way that those can work is with a Neos update.
And if we, as in the Neos team, have a development unit
or sufficiently documented developer documentation
from the manufacturer, I get the question
about other headsets, like every single week.
It's like, will you support this unannounced headset
that some person found in a hotel room and leaked online?
Not until it's public, no.
And then when it is public, we'll figure out if we can.
But yeah, it needs work to be done.
There are, again, the modding community
have made certain weirder headsets done.
So if you don't want to wait for us,
that might be an opportunity.
Moving down to Arisios for live streaming video into Neos.
I have experimented using HLS RTMP and other protocols
desperately trying to get video and audio to sync on a live
stream, but all it takes is one avatar to load.
And someone says the audio and video are out of sync.
Do you have any suggestions on what
we've done to try and keep the audio and video synced?
I can't remember how we did it in a world,
but there's a property on the video player
now called playback error sync, something like that.
That one is local, I believe.
And what we did was we hooked up that.
And some sort of comparison, I really can't remember.
I'm pulling stuff out of the bowels of my memory here.
We hooked that up locally to a fire on true,
which would then pause the video temporarily,
wait a couple of updates, and then play it again.
And that seemed to re-sync things automatically.
Of course, it was incredibly frustrating
because if anyone was out of sync,
it would pause it.
But we only had it happen two or three times during a video
that we were watching, so it was OK.
Another time it happened every five seconds,
and we just turned it off.
That might be something to look at.
Kazu says, local storage, not cloud one.
Let me scroll back up to your question, Kazu.
He's obviously nervous about running our spaces.
Ah, yeah.
So do make sure that they are looking
at the drive which stores that particular type of data.
So if, which question did I really want to ask?
Scrolling around.
Local storage.
Oh, not local storage.
Oh, OK.
Thank you.
All right, cool.
I'll just skip that question.
We'll move on.
Thank you.
Zach says it stays at 0.0% for 15 plus minutes.
That is a stuck sync, which means
you need to post a log file and questions and help one.
I'll take a look at it for you.
It could be any number of things until I see that log file.
Another one friendly thing you can do when you encounter
a problem, by the way, is to provide enough information.
People say, something went wrong.
And I'm like, what went wrong?
What were you trying to do?
Just think about how much more information
could you give us such that we don't
have to ask you any more questions.
We can just fix your issue.
So start with log file.
Start with a complete description
of what you are doing.
Start with any information that you have.
That's why the bug report form on the GitHub
is so long, so we can get all the information.
Let's scroll up and down, look for more questions.
Ozi says, what is Neosis development ethos?
I think I generally know what it is, but not exactly.
We don't have it exactly written down.
And to be fair, it is basically Frix's ethos as well.
It's like, I guess I can give examples.
Sometimes there's things like a feeling,
and you can't really describe them.
And this is one of those cases.
There are examples which kind of help you explain it.
One of the most prominent examples
is one would be as backwards compatible as possible.
So any time we change something, we're
like, will this break anything in backwards compatibility?
And if that's the case, then we'll figure it out.
I always use this example of backwards compatibility
because people see it all the time and ask me about it.
If you are using the find child by name node,
I think it also does it with the child by tag node.
And you look at your logic.
Sometimes there'll be this slot that has been created
and just appeared there that says injected
for backwards compatibility.
That one is to add an input's value to the old default value
because we swapped the default value for one of the inputs.
So when we detect that your find child by name node
was created before we applied this update,
we invert that particular option back to the old one
just in case it would break by being the new option.
That is a really bad way of explaining that.
Anyway, that's an example there.
And then another one would be future proofing,
which is kind of like backwards compatibility.
You'll see things like collections and stuff
like that in mods and plugins around.
They are great and fantastic that they're able to do that.
But are they backwards compatible?
Are they completely integrated with the Nius engine?
Not sure.
Haven't looked at the code yet.
So I'm not making a judgment here.
I'm saying, are they?
That's what we would do when we were
doing those particular features.
We would make sure that we thought out
end-to-end everything such that we never
have to really redo that feature like it's done,
like it's part of Nius.
You'll see other examples.
Basically, if you look at any issue
that we've closed for like, no, sorry,
and that is sort of the ethos.
And I know it's annoying sometimes,
but it's just like that's another example where
it comes up.
Duff says, might have already talked about it before,
but why is it the majority of the community
usually stays in non-public baseballs more often than not?
I talk about this in my previous office hours,
so refer to the notes on that one.
I will do the speech again.
I probably had a better speech last time,
so check that one out.
Easton says, that was an oddly specific example
of someone finding a VR headset in a hotel room.
That's exactly how the Quest Pro was leaked.
And for about three office hours after that, people are like,
will you support the Quest Pro?
It's like, not until we know it actually exists.
I'm like, yeah, we know a leak is confirming
that the headset exists, but a cardboard box in a hotel room
is different than a developer platform, and library,
and documentation, and API, and us having
headset in our hands to test.
Cassie says, do you have any prospects for the years
to resume development?
It's been 11 months since the problem happened,
but I'd like to know if there's any progress.
I really don't have anything to say on that one.
There was some information a couple of office hours ago,
but the summary is, please just check announcements.
I know it's horrible.
There's nothing really I can say,
except we are working as hard as we can on that.
Stifle says, current clock error is the property, I think.
Yeah, that's the one.
So yeah, if you check current clock, clop, clop, clop,
clop, clop, clop, clop, clop, clop, clipperty-clop.
I'm making horse noises.
Anyway, if you check that, I think it's local,
and then you can fire on true when
it's above a certain threshold, pause the video,
and load the video again, or pause it
and wait a couple of seconds, then load it again.
I believe what we did to counter the it kept pausing thing is,
we put a little red light at the corner of the screen that
turned on when someone was experiencing
desync using current clock error.
And then we knew that when that light had been on for a minute,
we knew it was pretty severe desync,
and then we would manually pause and stop it.
Rampa says, log sanitizer utility
when for moderation you need full log,
but posting in the open public, in my opinion,
ain't the best thing, since they're all the item IDs,
user IDs, et cetera.
So do keep in mind, and I understand
that if you as an individual have
a different interpretation of that, that's absolutely fine.
Do just keep in mind that Neos doesn't consider some data
private that might be considered private.
Now these, of course, vary on individual preferences.
Some of these ones I actually disagree with myself,
because we don't consider usernames, user IDs,
or machine IDs private data.
Those ones I do agree with, because the machine ID is
randomly generated by us, and it really doesn't mean much.
The username is your username.
It's on your name badge.
And the user ID is usually just your username
with a U dash on the front of it.
So none of those are private.
So we also don't consider IP addresses private.
I know that other people do.
I kind of do.
But it's kind of not a problem these days, IP addresses.
Yeah, I can find out which city you live in,
but I do understand that people want
to strip those from logs, though,
so do figure that one out.
I don't know if we would do log sanitizing on our part.
We might when we have sort of inbuilt reporting.
I want inbuilt reporting for moderation purposes
and for bugs and feature purposes,
like send us feedback.
At that point, we'd be able to sanitize it,
because we would be the ones getting it.
And then maybe we could sanitize it automatically
when we post it to the actual public repository.
But the point is, the log file would
go from your machine, from Neos, to us
without Discord or GitHub in the middle.
And then that would be less of an issue for sanitization.
But yeah, someone could make a utility that does that.
That would be quite helpful, actually.
I know there are a few mods that do it, but like,
you know when you need to just do a random thing to a string
and you go to randomthingtodoofastring.com
and you do it there.
If I need like a Unicode character, like a font,
an icon, I need to like decode and code a string,
there's like websites for all of that stuff.
Someone could make a web-based thing.
And it would run entirely in the browser.
It could just do JavaScript, right,
that could sanitize a log file.
A bit like NREX's material combiner website tool thing,
Easton mentions that when you're reporting a bug,
please disable your mods, cannot agree with that more.
I've seen so many log files where it's just like,
I have no idea what's going on because there's
like 50 mods in here and I don't even know what half of them do.
On a note from that, if you remember,
mods are allowed by our modern plugin policy.
But I do have a recommendation there,
which is don't install all of the mods.
I'm seeing a frequent number of users
who just download every single mod from the Neos modding
group and install them without really understanding
what they do.
And then when something goes wrong,
it's just impossible for them to know what the problem is.
Easton provides a picture of the clock error.
Yep, current clock error right there.
I'd have to double check Ramper with the item ID front.
You said that if you know the item ID, you can spawn it.
Don't think that's true because of various things.
I think if you know the URL to the 7z by sun, you can do it.
But if you know the ID, you can't then look up where it is.
I believe that's all the questions that we have.
Oh, hold on.
We have Peach, who's asking, does Neos have plans
for a Unity translator to make it easier for VRC users
to import their creations?
Yes and no.
So we do have a Unity SDK.
It is sort of broken, sort of not broken.
The problem that we have with a Unity translator
is when we use that phrasing, people think it's ultimate.
It is the ultimate Unity translator.
You throw any old Unity package at it, and it will translate it.
We can't do that because a single Unity package,
while it might contain stuff that we can use,
for example, the model we could use, the textures we could use,
and accessories on that avatar we can use,
we can't copy over any behavior.
So we can't copy over the animation doodads.
You know how VRC is.
I don't remember the phrase.
Controllers, that's the one.
We can't copy over that.
We can't currently copy over Dynamic Bones or Fizzbones.
Now, we could update the Unity SDK to do that.
But regardless of what we add to that,
there's always going to be something incredibly weird,
which is done, that we can't translate.
And so then people will get the impression
that the Unity translator is just like, does everything.
Yeah, this custom C Sharp script,
we've transferred it to Logix for you.
It can't do that.
So I think Unity, better naming, a better expectation setting
is needed there.
But yes, we do want to make that process easier.
In some regards, though, and this
is more of a personal note, I really
do wish more people, when they see that we don't have that,
would just try anyway.
I have some people who just outright
will leave Neos when they see that we don't have a Unity
translator.
And it bothers me because I'm like,
at a certain point in your life, you
learned how to make a VR avatar.
And that was challenging.
And now when you're faced with a similar challenge,
learning how to make an avatar in Neos, you're like, no.
I don't think I will.
And I don't know.
I just have a personal grievance against people
who refuse to learn.
Sometimes it's like, hey, you learned to tie your shoes
and walk as a child.
You can learn stuff if you just apply to yourself.
Anyone who says, I have a smooth brain.
I can't learn Logix.
I'm like, please apply yourself.
Please ask the community.
Please try learning, we'll help you out.
Your brain is amazing and is not too thin.
You have the ability to.
So I believe that question is done.
Kazu mentions that some booth items include 7z buttons.
They do.
Do remember that that is on the things to avoid list
because it can and will break in the future.
Easton, you don't have to tie your shoes.
I'm going to DM you some videos later.
Yeah, I use slip-on shoes these days.
Although when I went on a vacation recently,
it was actually at my parents' house in Spain.
And I only had one pair of shoes with me, and it broke.
And so I bought two new pairs of shoes
that actually do have laces because they
didn't have any of the slip-on shoes they used over there.
But yeah, I've had one pair of shoes for four years,
and they finally broke.
I'm very frugal.
Kazu says that they want to change it to a better
method when that's provided.
Absolutely fine, I understand.
Every time I see something that might break,
I let you know that it might break just so that it
stays inside your head.
And you keep in mind that when it breaks,
that we told you that it was going to break.
I believe that's all the questions we have.
If there are any follow-up questions,
please do direct message me, and I'll go ahead and close off
the office hours here.
Just let me know if you have any other questions.
Direct message me, ping me on Discord.
Send me a carrier pigeon, hopefully with some treats.
I'll take caribou or cheese.
That's fine.
And I'll see you next year.
Next year?
Next week!
Not next year.
Promise.
Next week.