Okay, welcome to office hours. It is time
So if you have questions, please feel free to drop them into the office hours channel
I'll get them answered in the order that they appear. Otherwise, we're gonna sit in
unimaginable unending
Silence mmm. Okay. We have a first question of the day, which is from specs
Which says I've asked a bit before but it's been a while. So why not? I'm running ahead the server again
I'm trying to get near
Logs into an elk elastic stack
unfortunately the timestamps and the s logs only have the time and not the date of an experience with such things any advice on how
I might do this. Um
Do they not have the date? I was not aware. Let me
Just open up a log file just for my personal reference here. Yeah, they only have a
Only have the time interesting. Um, you could probably base it on the
Like the name of the file when you ingest things we do have the date in the name of the file there
So maybe you can pass that out logging is actually something which I really really really want to improve
Like we don't really use like a standard logging library right now, and I would love to get one situated
I'd also get to one get one situated where you can kind of provide like a little bit of config to it
So for example when a user has a problem with Neos and we know it's in an area. Let's say physics I can say
Run Neos with this like command line flag and it will enable extra logging about physics because right now what happens is if we
Needed say extra logging about our problem
We would commit changes to Neos in everyone's sphere that would update the locking to include that information
And then when it was fixed we would then on the next update remove that information and that would allow us to
Stop doing that that would also allow us to not remove those log lines from the code
I'm weird and and maybe a little bit sort of
Obsessed with it, but if a log line exists in code it should exist forever because there's sometimes a lot of work that goes into
Creating logs or creating specific log messages, and we shouldn't need to delete that we should just disable it if we don't need it anymore
There's lots of libraries for doing that we're just not really using any of them
So we need to that one improve a lot of the stuff there
Next question from
Actually, I'm gonna jump to specs is because it's a follow-up
Who asks when the date rolls over does Neos create a new log file and you date will it continues the same file?
I have no idea. I have no idea
We'd have to have basically like a 24-hour session running and then see what happens at the date boundaries. I don't know
So gun Griffin asks what restrictions can oppose filter apply
Can it be manually clipped I use a raycast to tell it to limit the motion in that direction
So a post filter has like a number of components that you can use
I actually have the code base open which is a rare occurrence right now, but
It does mean I can I can look them up all real quick for you, so I just find references to post filter
okay, so
You can do what's called a smoother
post filter that one will sort of make your
Controls smoothed Gable has an example of that inside Neos essentials gadgets
Skibbles toy shop and then there's a weight in there and it feels like a heavy weight
And that's because it's smooth lerped in you grabbing it. That's also good for like levers or heavy wheels or something
There's a part in Fundamentally 8. This is a sideline, but hey we have time. There's not many questions
there's a side part in Fundamentally 8 where you're you're descending through a building and there's this
big wheel to open up part of this like basement level of a building and
You need to spam like the x button on your controller to do it and the speedrunners of that game have sort of
Narrowed down the mathematics of spamming that big wheel to a tee so they can get through as fast as possible
If you can't do it on the first try
Another member of your party in this rPG will then join you and then you have to spam it less because then there's two bodies
On that wheel spinning it
So that's a sideline. It's cool
I know what they call it in the speedrunner community is like first try valve or whatever it is and it's very difficult
It's like I don't know. I'm not gonna get this right
It's like 120 button pushes over a period of like a minute or I don't know whatever the the limit is
But that's what it's meant to you know meant to signify
Hefty lifting would be a good use of that post filter
Moving on post filters. There's a rotation
a rotation constraint that prevents you from Rotating whilst you're holding it so things like again levers
And wheels would be really good for that one. I haven't actually used that one a lot mostly because you know
It uses similar things to a joint and joint scary
Joint scary, there's pose offset that will basically offset you and a position in a rotation when you grab it
I'm not really sure why you would use that but hey, it's there
The one that is probably more applicable to guns actual question though is the box constraint
So what the box constraint will do is when you grab something you only be able to move it in that box and because there's
A box it's got three dimensions if you only want left and right make the box really
Really short, but really wide or really deep just you know remove that height
And then you don't need to be able to move it up and down stuff like that
Manually clipped use a raycast to tell it to limit motion you would do that using the box constraint. That's
All there is really to them if you want any more sort of other pose restrictions that you've got please do drop them a feature
Request on the github and we'll get it sorted
Whenever we can or if it's a good idea
Remember when you're like asking for things like that ask for what you would like to happen rather than your intended approach
So for example here and you're doing good in the way that you've asked it
I'm just pointing out because there's an opportunity to
Gun asked use a raycast to tell it to limit motion in that direction
We don't need a raycast to do that
You could use a raycast to do it and then calculate the the distance based on that
But what we need is an ability to limit the range of motion the amount of motion, right?
So that doesn't technically need a raycast that could be static. It could be dynamic
So make sure you kind of separate those two so that we don't get lost in the sort of like
Why would you need a raycast and said it's like oh you could use a raycast to have this effect
Moving on to our next question we have from unnamed cyborg cat has anyone tried creating a physics gun yes
I believe quite a few people have just off the top of my head. I would probably go off. I wrote
Sorry, we're really like scariest mod, so maybe they would know if someone has one or maybe they made them on themselves
I'm not sure, but sorry would be my target to go ask that particular question
Specs asks lately myself and friends have experienced issues joining sessions. Yes
We're aware of that one I think we're looking into it today
It's probably just the relay server like pooping again, so we'll take a look at it should be fixed today
If not, I will I'll bash bash fruits around a little bit too. It's fixed gently of course just like that. Hey fix it um
Really almost too fuzzy. It's a way to swap into another avatar. That's in the world via logics. Yes
There is the equip avatar
Node is inside the avatars folder
So cool like just take a look at it. You can find inside my public folder
I think it's in like public proper prime tools. There is the avatar equip
Tooltip that basically you can just point at an avatar and equip it it sounds weird
But there was a bug for like one update where you couldn't equip avatars that are in the world and so I made that tool
quickly
It's also got I don't think actually release that version
No, turkey turkey edited it. There's one way you can
Select an avatar with secondary and then duplicate and equip it over into
Like the other ones there
That will just change the avatar not teleporting equip avatar will just change your avatar
It shouldn't teleport you the context menu does teleport you as far as I'm right
Name cybercat asks about Hypno space outlaw. I have no idea what that is and so no I have not checked that out
electronic asks so I have a user parent or one of my avatars and users can walk around on a box collider with it when
I move manually they tend to stay in place, but when I move my stick even slowly they tend to fall off
I've been advised to use a box collider for the parent that is fairly large to basically catch them is the better way to do
This um no, that's what you'll have to do
Look into how the character parent who works this comes a lot a lot in elevators basically if you stop colliding with that
Call a collider it will be parent you and so what's happening
There is probably like an update order or something like that is happening to decollide them from the collider
So that's cool. I didn't think it actually got taken down taken down. We didn't delete it
I don't think we delete anything for that's a reference of Turks tool being taken down. I think it has
So you just keep an eye on that collider make sure they're not
De-colliding with it you might be able to hook up some light logics to try and figure that out a little bit more
Because you can detect when they de-collide from it
You know like children count change or something like that and maybe sort of narrow down
What's going on there moving course to Fuzzy's question is there a recommended theoretical discovered maximum number of children you compare it before things get upset
Not that I'm aware of you'd probably end up in issues
quite rapidly, but like not quickly at all you should never have to worry about it
This does come up a lot as well people worry sometimes too much like I understand the worry
But if there is like a performance problem or like a limitation or something like that
Then we should take care of it with you like we should take care of that for you
So you don't have to worry about it. No, we see that's
Children a parent can have children a parent. Oh, yeah, that's a different thing. Yeah number of slot children
There is a limit
I thought you were talking about trees like descending down children parent children children children children like a branching tree
That's probably got no limit, but number of slot children. There is a limit. I forget what that is again
You shouldn't worry about it. It's probably close to one of those other
boundaries yeah, yeah
You shouldn't like it shouldn't like it shouldn't you shouldn't have shouldn't have anything there there are then of course as he brings up the
JSON limits as well sometimes there are limits on on JSON when saving it good example here being that folder
So I prevented it from being created, but I haven't obviously what's going on
I haven't fixed up so that it will then be okay in the actual UI
There's people that were creating folders that had incredibly long names
They were using colors or ASCII art to make their public folders
that was breaking stuff because the folder length was too long and
Some of the validation just just couldn't handle the link for that. It was related to the JSON and synchronization
So I put like a sort of stopgap on that in the create directory menu
So you can't make them really long
But I haven't then gone back and done the rest of the operations there to clean up from behind next on was to
Has who says on unis player not sure if the right place to ask is there some kind of general plan to simplify
I knew as his UI. Yep. There is that's the UI overhaul roadmap. Also. Take a look at the myths page on our wiki
and this page is sometimes quite sort of
Bludgeoning in the way that it's worded. It's not intended like that
It's just intended to be as quick and as blunt as possible just to get in the message out there
So we want to improve the UI we know it's bad. We are going to improve it like it's not intentionally this way
It's not on purpose that it's terrible. It's just not finished
We will finish it at some point in the future
TBD fuzzy is there a nice way to discover and not off an object exists XYZ other than looping through everything from root down
Checking yeah collider. So again, I guess happens a lot and I keep hearing about it. So I'll keep saying it
colliders
People worry about colliders being Aggie or colliders being problematic if you do them correctly, they're totally fine
So what you would do there is probably take a small and I say small because you're trying to look for a singular point a small
sphere active Collider
teleport it to that position and
Detective any collisions occur and then turn it off if you do that all within like a couple of update cycles. You're fine
There's no like it's fine
That would enable you to sort of see what's going on there now
You could technically do sort of weird bounding box stuff
But you would have to look through all the children there if you want like a dynamic access without looping through the children and descending
Colliders the way to go
And speaking of that, maybe I can tutorialize it at some point head on over to the creator jam
Not this week's but last week's creator jam that was about bread and carbohydrates
There is a small wheat farm there where I I use active colliders. I I use them. They're good
They work well
And you can kind of see how I advise doing that over there
You can grow wheat and then harvest it and grind it into flour because that's part of the cup jam if to so
It was a good job
Etronus points out that the object that you're trying to discover must have a collider that is correct if an object doesn't have a collider
It's kind of a bug sort of like if it's like an art world or it's your own world cool
But if it's someone else's world don't spawn stuff that doesn't have colliders that happens a lot with sort of like
I don't know half finished
projects or something like I'll go into a world after it's been open for a couple of hours and it just be like
There is a sphere the size of the Sun in the background
Why is no one removed it and they're like we can't find it. It has no collider, and I'm just like
Really?
Active colliders active cut yet
You just I know that we have the pseudo physics via the collider at the character colliders that are active, etc
Just just don't do it. Just don't do it
Electronus points out additional clarifications about collider types double check my table
you'll see there, but there's something there an avatar would do that because avatars have the the
Colliders on them that do have collision
If you wanted to go for the non collision ones then maybe maybe raycast to help there like kind of it like picturing like this
weird sort of
Robot that flies around the map that just goes like okay couldn't get a collision with my active Collider
Pupupu of a bunch of raycast couldn't get a collision with my actual raycast cool. Guess there must not be anything here
But yeah, I don't don't descend madly through the through the hierarchy of just drive yourself mad. Oh
I'm sorry. I did miss that question. Thank you for re-asking it. I try not to
Crafting asks is it possible to make any contact means that aren't arcs. Yes, if you don't use our context menu system
I said lots of people do it. They put like UI or tooling that exists on their avatar
That is not arc related
I guess a good example here is prominent that comes to mind is there is jacks like
Wrist gauntlet thing that has a lot of sort of menus and stuff on it on arcs
There's lots of people that do sort of customized avatars that go extreme
And they've got all sorts of like yeah, just imagine like Iron Man menus in your head
There's lots of those that exist those aren't arcs, but if you only use our context menu systems, then nope they gotta be ox
And Griffin asks can you reference an item by relative hierarchy path Robin specifics lock ref no?
What you're asking therefore is like almost CSS style searching
in HTML you can kind of search for like
Look for any cube which is under a sphere like you can totally do that in web programming web development
It's totally easy to do, but you cannot do that there
You might be able to do in the future and the reason I say that is whenever
Fruits puts out something that has a text box like dynamic variables parent data links
Tag slot names all sorts of stuff like that. He'll sometimes reserve characters so for example inside dynamic variable system
There are reserved characters that you can't use for your dynamic variables the reason why those are reserved is so hey
Maybe we can do more more complicated string matching later
I'll follow this up the question with is it just search by name. Yeah, there's fine child by name which
Confined a child by the name. There's no
Fancy searching you can do there this fine child by tag
There's no fancy searching you can do there to descend also reminder tags are singular
Some people get confused about the has tag
Node there the reason has tag exists is because it is a shortcut rather than doing get tagged equally cool
It's like has tag instead
It's it's like one or two less nodes fuzzy ask is there a way to get sound from one place to appear to be coming
from another place yes um
You know got a video on that one
Let me let me see if I can find the video for you, and we'll take a look
Yeah, yeah remote audio
Essentially though what you do is you?
you do
Anywhere, there's an audio output component is where?
The audio actually comes out of audio output is the is the component that plays the audio so let's say you have a music clip
They exist in the world and you play it there
There's usually an audio output on it
You know the green the green sort of circle thing you could go into that audio clip and you can remove the audio output and wire
Up an audio output elsewhere. That's what a lot of the sort of video players DJ systems
Surround sound systems do they like take your audio data, and they wire it to different audio sources
That's how you get sort of audio around there also check out my public folder. I think it's under gadgets
I've got a tin can telephone here remember you know tie two tin cans together a piece of string and then spoke into them
I've got that working that uses remote audio to do that
That's a bit complicated like if you unpack it. You'll probably go. Oh, that's because I made it like many years ago, but
What it essentially does is it redirects your audio output when you're holding a can to the opposite can as an audio output?
Moving on to OZ question may have asked this before but is finding a child by tag more efficient than funny by name given the most
Objects don't even have text search through
Find child by tag let's take a look how this works
instance finds child
cool, and then
t find child by name
t find child by name does find child does find child index of
Technically, they're about the same. They're probably about the same the reason I say that is because find child by tag
has to do
Predicate based searching where it's a sort of process each slot and go through the list
But find child by name has to do a lot of string stuff, so they're like about the same
Find child by name doesn't have to do any sort of predicate matching you can just do a for each so
Honestly, you shouldn't have to worry. This is again what I talk about where I'm like if you're worried about performance
Let us worry about that. We don't do it right now as much as we should
But we did do it with one note that doesn't be released yet
but will be other is just count occurrences fruits, and I had a
Disagreement and this time is a polite disagreement these happen all the time of programming
They're amazing and you should learn to understand that those happen that they're cool about the performance of a counter currencies node
And which methodology were doing so we wrote tests to see how fast it was we found a faster methodology for doing that
And so in that regard we found the fastest way to do count occurrences
And so you as a user should never have to worry about how fast counter currencies is because we've done that testing for you
That's the design of Neos right you shouldn't have to worry about performance if you do it means we should do more work
We should do more work
fuzzy asks about
Okay, so the way that it's done with the Tim. Sorry. I'll state the question
It's not a question, so I kind of just like paraphrase into a question so fuzzy is asking what I previously said about
Audio was only applicable to avatars and not like an in-world microphone, so it's a little bit difficult with like a
a user's voice because the only way to obtain a user's voice right now
Dynamically is to use an avatar equipping event so the tin can telephone what it technically does when you grab it is
you
Temporarily get equipped into another avatar. I have stuff inside the avatar that then like shoulder taps the
Tin can and says here's the audio stream use it and then you get a quick back to your original avatar
So I know you're asking about a clip avatar above that tin can does both of them
Um and then what that does is it lets you gain access to it. That's the only way that you can do it with
Within avatars voice with a user's voice right now. Is that kind of weird equipping route SLS talks about ref hacking
I don't advise ref hacking because it can break at any
Moment so don't advise it it could break tomorrow. It could break yesterday
I don't know could even technically break during a session it just depends like
It's a bit crazy there if you're doing non avatar audio though. There's there's lots that you can do. There's the avatar frame slot
That's why there's like a square and you can put the sound effect in it
There's a bunch of components for doing that and a bunch of
Like stuff there like random audio clip player stuff like that you can redirect that to any audio output throughout the world
There's a bunch of like optimizations that can be done with audio outputs. I do want to talk about on a video at some point
Something which I see for a lot of for example is when people use those frame slots
They forget to remove the audio output on the actual green circle thing
But they redirect the audio from the green circle thing to another output like a speaker
and what that means is you actually doubled your audio output components, which means you've
reduced the available audio outputs that can play concurrently in your world by two instead of one and
You could reduce that back and have an extra audio output component something happens. There are a lot in particle systems
for example, you can have
The same particle system in use by two different emitters
So let's say you're walking through a hall of fire and you've got fire coming out of the wall into you know
Like a sort of Indiana Jones temple star thing. What I'll see is basically each fire on every side of the wall is its own
Particle system and part on a particle emitter. And so there's competing systems that are all firing fire
They're all in the same particle same effect
Instead what you can do is have one particle system and an emitter first side of the wall
And what that lets you do is change everything about the particles from one location and is slightly more efficient slightly
It also means that you can sort of
Globally control the number of particles for that particular fire walk in its entirety and know exactly how many particles exist
For the entire walkway rather than for each flame at the same time
And if you want the flames to be different color, you only have to write it one place. So that's a good tip there. Oh
It's it's great when when people have to continually ask better and better questions to get exactly what they need
I love it
So fuzzy has updated the question again and saying that they would like to pull audio from the world itself including avatar or ambient noise
You're talking more about sort of
Recording what's going on in the world from a from an audio point of view?
That we don't really have anything for and the reason is that like audio coming like out to your ears only goes through one
Thing there. I think there's technically like something in the unity side of things which is the component that does that
It's like the the point in space where you hear the audio coming from. There's only like one of those right now
And that exists in your head
There's a bunch of stuff that like only exists inside the unity side of things and it's completely invisible to you
It might be an audio listener component. I could open up the unity project
It's usually quite scary when I do that. It tries to recompile shaders sometimes which takes two days
I'll find it at some point. But yeah, like it's uh, there's lots of like unity related stuff
That we hope to open up to you at some point. They then be able to mess around with for example
I'm quite interested in we want to do sort of voice calling or in some cases video calling between people in the
In in Neos and to do that we would need like a better system for audio listeners as they're called
So ears in the world, there's lots of ways to make like, you know mouths and speakers and stuff like that
There's only one ear that exists inside your avatar. It's right in the middle head
jumping around
electronicis what's the limit on audio outputs? I never forget. I never forget. I always forget
I always forget that it is something along the lines of 32 to 64
I would always give yourself a little bit of headroom and aim for maybe 28
just because you've got to remember the people in the world are technically an audio source as are
Context menus or bells on their neck, by the way
If you have a bell on your neck that rings when you move around, please adjust it
So it's not on the global audio channel and consider making it not make noise at all. Thank you
Like you're taking up an audio output from the rest of the session to be annoying. Sorry
That's just the way it is
electronicis, but they're the most important more show me your importance through being a good person and through the work that you do inside me
So I don't even mean the stuff that you create
I mean being a community member and then you'll get all my attention, especially if you write talks
Fuzzy ask is there a way to swap left and right audio channels and someone know
You might be able to do that in the user inspector. But again, I wouldn't really advise it
If you do with the developer to create new editor user inspector
There's a bunch of stuff in there and like if you play over the wrong thing
You will crash your game or you will disconnect yourself from the rest of the like just be careful with that stuff
But you might be you might be able to do it in there. Don't negatively scale ahead
Audio has nothing to do with
Like what your head looks like there is something in like how small you get that can affect the audio
That's because the audio engine sort of on a sort of how big things are and tries to sort of mess around audio on that
You'll notice that on an audio output. There's like in the scale max scale
I haven't played with that person because I don't really understand it
But maybe you're making like a borrower's game and you need like bigger things to sound bigger
I don't know. It's there play around with it. Fuzzy says it'll be interesting challenge. Sorry Fuzzy Fox. There's two to two Fuzzy's
says
Fuzzy challenge to play with reversed audio. Um, when you say reversed you mean swapped L and right L R
Sorry
Or do you mean like reversed as in speaking backwards? Oh, they mean to know them. Oh, yeah
Yeah, be interesting. I don't know
Take a look at I'm gonna forget the name of it and probably spend like 20 minutes trying to find it if anyone knows it
In the in the channel, please please please drop it by there is a audio only RPG game on Steam
It won a bunch of awards you play it you play it with your eyes closed
I mean there is text on the screen if you want to but like you don't see your character
You don't see the enemies, but you can like battle people have like full-on boss fights. You don't see anything. It's amazing
moving on to
Additional questions actually just a little anecdote before we get on to the next question here because I see business lawyer in there
There was one time when business lawyers microphone was emitting
Absolutely eldritch cosmic horror noises. I don't remember why I think it's something to do Windows 10
But they joined Aegis wolf and I on
The moon landing world
She's already quite sort of dark and dreary and dim and spooky and they just like because it's also spherical gravity
They kind of like crested over a hill of this spherical gravity world and they were just like speaking just absolute
Horror at us and it was terrifying at a recording of in-game
I will try and get it outside a game so I can post it here
But it was it was terrifying on the audio recording. I have it includes the hitch that would happen before
We had a good garbage collector, which was the long you played Neos the worst the hitch got
And you knew it was happening because all the audio sources would hitch you'd hear like
And they would like get through the hitch and his cosmic horror recording includes some of that
It was terrible especially with the glowing bird eyes of the beak
Just sort of like bouncing up and down of this like oh, it was terrible. Yeah, it was really old like first couple of months
I was scared like I was scared and then once I was scared
It was business lawyer periodically coming back into the world and trying to see if it was fixed or not
moving to
Last questions, I guess because we're running over in time
Girl Griffin asked us an intimate audio source keep a channel busy. Yes, depending on how you use it
There are people here that will disagree
periodically with what I say, but
Use play one shot more lots of people like don't use play one shot these days
I see lots of sort of parented audio outputs or parented green circles, etc
The reason I say use play one shot more is because it creates and then deletes the audio output
It creates then deletes the audio output and people say well it makes a slot
I'm like yeah, but we can optimize that for you like if that's got a problem
We'll optimize it for you like maybe we'll do a play one shot update where it doesn't create a slot
And it'll be more performant if you go out of your way to make systems that we don't understand
We can't optimize them for you later. So I always advise wherever you can play one shot
It's it's just a lot better
It creates the audio output and then removes it if you need to have the audio output around good example here would be repetitive
Noise that needs to occur background music or like ambience stuff like that crickets wind howling stuff like that go for it
But the moment you don't need that sound turn off the audio outputs enabled flag the enabled flag and needs to be off if you're not
Outputting audio through the audio output turn off the enabled property of the audio output that will mean it won't count to your limit
But it can still exist and be there
Footsteps you should question why you need footsteps if it's a game world or you've got atmosphere sure if your avatar individually has footsteps
My headaches do not like that spec says
if
They suggest play one shot
But maybe limit if it's spammable like no more than 380 plays in a time
We did keep audio source counselor
Yeah
Do keep an eye on that one if you spam it then you will create more than you would have found if you had used
a static audio output
Something which I usually do and do advise doing a lot more
Particular things like play one shot and also raycast and stuff like that is make sure that you're filtering the user that the impulse occurs
Into just one user like sometimes, you know, it's just a one user like if it's on a button push or something like that
but if you're not sure there's throw in a equal equal if node and don't fire the impulse because uh
That leads to problems sometimes, you know
You'll you'll have an impulse that you didn't expect to be able to be caused by multiple users
Being caused by multiple users and then at point you'll have n sounds rather than one sound because n is the net of people in
the world
Fuzzy Fox asks is the audio limited because the audio system we're using yes
It's a unity limitation those limitations do exist in a lot of audio engines
It just depends on the ones that we are using
I don't know what it would be or how prevalent it would be but I would I would estimate the the unreal has it
I'd estimate that cry engine has it I would estimate that they all have it. It's just the way that audio works in some regards
I'd like it to not be there but like but probably need a new audio engine for that. I don't know whatever
It's good that it needs to be there though. If you think of like traditional game programming
The audio engineers you'll see that on the credits of our audio engineer. What does that mean? That means both sort of mixing?
Creating the sound stuff like that. That's more audio production though
But that also means like how the audio feels in the game and how it's activated in the game
it's very very complicated and they would keep an eye on how many audio sources they had even if there wasn't a limit because
Audio is resources dresse ask about sound filters. We do have some but they only apply to
Globalized audio right now and they're also sort of like a box, right?
So there are a cube around you that does that effect?
I would like to be able to sort of more limit that to particular sounds etc. It's good for voices
But again, it's only on broadcast audio. So annoying that is an audio engine limitation
Yeah, if you wanna know more about audio
Um speak to ng and if you want to know more about randomized audio stuff speak to fur who does audio for roller coasters
That's a really interesting conversation
Ask them about the Hagrid ride ask them about the Hagrid ride with that. I think we're done
We're running way over on time here
So I will go ahead and leave off here
if you have other questions, feel free to DM me any time and I will get back to you as soon as I can and
And this will be up on sound later today. You'll have a good day. Bye. Bye